<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.pasda.psu.edu/pasda/uci_metadata/dtd/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission</origin>
        <pubdate>2010</pubdate>
        <title>DVRPC 2010 Digital Orthoimagery - TIFF Tiles</title>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Mt. Laurel, NJ</pubplace>
          <publish>BAE Systems</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://www.dvrpc.org/</onlink>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2010</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>
-76.137</westbc>
        <eastbc>
-74.772</eastbc>
        <northbc>
40.677</northbc>
        <southbc>
39.772</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>orthoimagery</themekey>
        <themekey>orthophotography</themekey>
        <themekey>aerial photography</themekey>
        <themekey>orthophotograph</themekey>
        <themekey>aerial photograph</themekey>
        <themekey>orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>aerial photo</themekey>
        <themekey>digital orthoimagery</themekey>
        <themekey>digital orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>digital aerial photo</themekey>
        <themekey>rectified photograph</themekey>
        <themekey>rectified image</themekey>
        <themekey>imagery</themekey>
        <themekey>ortho</themekey>
        <themekey>aerial</themekey>
        <themekey>DTM/DEM</themekey>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>DVRPC Region</placekey>
        <placekey>Bucks County </placekey>
        <placekey>Chester County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Philadelphia County</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Bucks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Chester County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Philadelphia County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Must contact DVRPC.</accconst>
    <useconst>The Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission (DVRPC) excludes any and all implied warranties of merchantability and fitness.  No guarantees are expressed or implied as to the use or application of the digital information supplied.  DVRPC assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form.  DVRPC will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the material supplied, or arising out of any inaccuracy or defect in the digital information supplied.  Recipients of DVRPC digital files are not entitled to any file revisions, updates, corrections, or new releases.  Recipients of DVRPC digital files are expressly prohibited from copying or releasing these files to any other individuals or agencies, under any circumstances.  Recipients of DVRPC digital files are expressly prohibited from displaying for view or making these files available for download from the Internet or World Wide Web, under any circumstances.  Recipients of DVRPC digital files will credit DVRPC as the source of the data when producing maps, publications, reports, or other documents that utilize DVRPC files.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Glenn McNichol</cntper>
          <cntorg>Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Senior GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>190 N. Independence Mall West</address>
          <address>8th Floor</address>
          <city>Philadelphia</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>19106</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>215-592-1800</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>215-592-9125</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gmcnichol@dvrpc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>BAE Systems</datacred>
    <descript>
      <abstract>DVRPC2010</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The accuracy of the ground control is confirmed by the evaluation of the results of the analytical bundle adjustment.  The residuals of the final adjustment ensured compliance with NSSDA standards.  The Pre Adjustment Gross Error Detection Statistical Test (Data Snooping, with a confidence level of 99.9%) has been applied to all observations included in the aerial triangulations. To detect small gross errors, during Adjustment Robust Estimators were used with the same confidence level and a power of the test of 1-beta=0.2. Systematic errors were eliminated through self calibration and through Additional Parameters. Their numerical stability, statistical significance, internal and external reliability were checked using Student-t test with the same confidence level and Variance/Co-variance analysis. Finally, the arrived variance factor was submitted to a Chi-square test against the pre-adjustment variance factor using a confidence level 99.9%.  Evaluation of the DEM includes checking the terrain data for spikes and wells, omissions, and other anomalies that do not meet the project accuracy requirements.  The horizontal and vertical accuracy has been tested by comparing the coordinates of well-defined points in the dataset with coordinates of the same points from an independent source of higher accuracy.  The program ORTHOQC is able to match the original image pixels of pass/tie points, ground control points, and check points with the final ortho, extract the corresponding horizontal coordinates from the digital ortho and compare them with the original measured points in the field or adjusted from the aerotriangulation.  Values of statistics such as RMSE, Max and Min Discrepancies, standard deviation, etc. are then derived and analyzed statistically.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>All files are inspected by the Production Manager to ensure that they conform to the specified file naming conventions, all files load in their correct geographic position when loaded using the ASCII file header, all files conform to the project specifications for pixel resolution, file standard, dimensions, and compression, and all files do not contain blemishes such as visible seam lines, tone differences, data dropout or artifacts; scan swathing, or warped bridges and overpasses.</logic>
    <complete>All imagery is visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no gaps or image misplacement exists in the image area.  Imagery is mosaicked to ensure complete coverage for map sheets.  The imagery has been checked to ensure that the boundary and the content has been covered in its entirety.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal accuracy standard follows the NSSDA-1998 standard.  The maximum permissible RMSE for 95% of the horizontal check points for the mapping product is 5 feet or better.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The DEM data meets the required vertical accuracy necessary to ensure that the horizontal accuracies of the orthophotos are met.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>BAE Systems</origin>
            <pubdate>20000401</pubdate>
            <title>GPS Photo Control Survey</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20000401</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GPS Ground Control</srccitea>
        <srccontr>To be utilized in the analytical aerotriangulation process.  All horizontal and vertical control was prepared under the supervision of licensed Professional Land Surveyors.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Earth Data International</origin>
            <pubdate>20050410</pubdate>
            <title>Digital Color Aerial Photography</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>2400</srcscale>
        <typesrc>disc</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20050404</begdate>
              <enddate>20050410</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Aerial Photography</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Color Aerial photography to be used in the creation of digital orthophotos.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>39.933333</stdparll>
            <stdparll>40.966667</stdparll>
            <longcm>-77.750000</longcm>
            <latprjo>39.333333</latprjo>
            <feast>1968500.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>1.000000</absres>
            <ordres>1.000000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>A digital number from 0 to 4095 will be assigned to each pixel.  For the color imagery this number refers to a color look-up table which will contain the red, green, and blue (RGB) values, each from 0 to 255, for that digital number.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Where applicable, all data conforms to the Proposal for 2005 Aerial Photography Project presented to the Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission August 5, 2004.</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission</cntorg>
          <cntper>Glenn McNichol</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Senior GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>190 N. Independence Mall West</address>
          <address>8th Floor</address>
          <city>Philadelphia</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>19106</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>215-592-1800</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>215-592-9125</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gmcnichol@dvrpc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>Recipients of DVRPC digital files are expressly prohibited from copying or releasing these files to any other individuals or agencies, under any circumstances.  Recipients of DVRPC digital files are expressly prohibited from displaying for view or making these files available for  download from the Internet or World Wide Web, under any circumstances.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2010</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.

</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <Esri>
    <ModDate>20080205</ModDate>
    <ModTime>12552500</ModTime>
    <CreaDate>20110906</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>12454900</CreaTime>
    <ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat>
    <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
    <DataProperties>
      <itemProps>
        <itemLocation>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\URSUS\dataC\DVRPC_TIFF_2010\DVRPCMrSidMosaic2010</linkage>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
        </itemLocation>
      </itemProps>
      <copyHistory>
        <copy source="C:\dataC\DVRPC_TIFF_2010\DVRPCMrSidMosaic2010" dest="\\URSUS\dataC\DVRPC_TIFF_2010\DVRPCMrSidMosaic2010" date="20110906" time="12454900">
        </copy>
      </copyHistory>
    </DataProperties>
  </Esri>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20080205</mdDateSt>
</metadata>