<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.pasda.psu.edu/pasda/uci_metadata/dtd/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>The Conservation Fund</origin>
        <pubdate>November 2004</pubdate>
        <title>Protected Lands Inventory: Nonprofit and Private Lands - November 2004</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>November 2004</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>
-80.725788</westbc>
        <eastbc>
-74.808918</eastbc>
        <northbc>
42.194241</northbc>
        <southbc>
39.554029</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>managed lands</themekey>
        <themekey>conserved lands</themekey>
        <themekey>protected lands</themekey>
        <themekey>Biota</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None.</accconst>
    <useconst>For educational/demonstration purposes only. The Originator, Publisher and Distributor exclude any and all implied warranties and make no warranty or representation with respect to the data files or accompanying documentation, including quality, performance, merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. These data files and documentation are provided 'as is' and the User assumes the entire risk as to their quality and performance. These data are not to be redistributed for commercial profit. Reproduction or redistribution of this digital data set without permission of the Originator/Publisher is expressly forbidden. The Originator and Publisher should be clearly cited in any product derived from this data. Any modifications to this data must be described in any digital or hardcopy product derived from this data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>The Conservation Fund - PA Office</cntorg>
          <cntper>Todd McNew</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>105 North Front Street</address>
          <city>Harrisburg</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>17101</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native>
    <descript>
      <abstract>PA_PLI_NPF_Private</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Every attempt was made to accurately attribute features in each dataset.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>As a result of the multiple sources of data used, there are spatial overlaps between features in the some of the layers.  Where there was a conflict, a note was included in the ACC_NOTES attribute field in each dataset.  Be careful when summarizing areas and acreage and when depicting muliple protected lands layers at the same time.</logic>
    <complete>While the Protected Lands Inventory enconpasses the majority of protected lands within the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, there are still significant gaps in the dataset.  Only some land trusts and local government provided information on their parks and other protected properties.  Some Federal and State acquisitions since 1998 are not reflected.  The Nature Conservancy was able to provide data only fee simple acquisitions but not easements.  Some environmentally sensitive lands were not included.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Spatial accuracy varies depending upon the source of the data, although every attempt was made to comply with National Map Accuracy Standards.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>PA GAP Analysis Program</origin>
            <pubdate>1998</pubdate>
            <title>1998 PA GAP Analysis Program Managed Lands layer</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Data from the 1998 PA GAP Analysis Program was categorized by protection type and separate into multiple categories.  The data was then reprojected and reattributed to the PLI standard attribute table.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The Conservation Fund obtained digital data from land trusts and local governments, which was then reprojected and reattributed to the PLI standard attribiute data.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Hard copy data from land trusts was digitized by the Pennsylvania Environmental Council and sent to The Conservation Fund. The Fund then reprojected and reattributed the data.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Data from the three sources were merged into one file for each category: Federal, State, NPF-Private, County-Local, CountyAgEasements.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Spatial conflicts between features were resolved by a GIS analyst at The Conservation Fund.  Every attempt was made to include the most accurate spatial features.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
        <srcused>P:\GIS\Penn_Download\PLI_FINAL_Albers\PLI_Metadata_Template.xml</srcused>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
        <srcused>
        </srcused>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
        <srcused>
        </srcused>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>969</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>40.000000</stdparll>
            <stdparll>43.000000</stdparll>
            <longcm>-74.000000</longcm>
            <latprjo>38.000000</latprjo>
            <feast>400000.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.001024</absres>
            <ordres>0.001024</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>
PA_PLI_NPF-Private</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Federal Lands</enttypd>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PLI_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique ID for each feature using the PLI numbering scheme.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FEATURE_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique ID usually linked to a PIN or ID# from a land trust or local govenment to facilitate accessing source data.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GIS_ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Calculated acres using a function in ArcMap</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CATEGORY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Broad classification scheme. Used DIVISION field from GAP data and CONSERVATI from PEC data.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>UNIT_NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature Name. Used UNIT field from GAP layer</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of protected land. Used LCODE attribute from GAP data.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MECHANISM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fee simple or easement.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ACCURACY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Source of data.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ACC_NOTES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Spatial overlap.</attrdef>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania DCNR</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <transize>0.750</transize>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>downloadabledata</resdesc>
    <distliab>Not for commercial use or resale. The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20061016</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>The Conservation Fund - NC Office</cntorg>
          <cntper>William L. Allen III</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Director</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>10001 Main Street, Suite C</address>
          <city>Chapel Hill</city>
          <state>NC</state>
          <postal>27516</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>919-967-2223</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <Esri>
    <ModDate>20080612</ModDate>
    <ModTime>10461100</ModTime>
  </Esri>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20080612</mdDateSt>
</metadata>