<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Federal Emergency Management Agency</origin>
        <title>FEMA Historic Flood Maps</title>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
          <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>hydrology</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
        <themekey>transportation</themekey>
        <themekey>elevation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>FEMA NFIP Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>FIRM</themekey>
        <themekey>FEMA Flood Hazard Zone</themekey>
        <themekey>FIRM Database</themekey>
        <themekey>Special Flood Hazard Area</themekey>
        <themekey>Flood Insurance Rate Map</themekey>
        <themekey>CBRS</themekey>
        <themekey>Coastal Barrier Resources System</themekey>
        <themekey>Riverine Flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>Coastal Flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>NFIP</themekey>
        <themekey>Base Flood Elevation</themekey>
        <themekey>SFHA</themekey>
        <themekey>Floodway</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The hardcopy FIRM and FIRM Database and the accompanying FIS are the official designation of SFHAs and Base Flood Elevations (BFEs) for the NFIP. For the purposes of the NFIP, changes to the flood risk information published by FEMA may only be performed by FEMA and through the mechanisms established in the NFIP regulations (44 CFR Parts 59-78). These digital data are produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRMs and generally match the hardcopy map exactly. Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Federal Emergency Management Agency</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>500 C Street, S.W.</address>
          <city>Washington</city>
          <state>District of Columbia</state>
          <postal>20472</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>mscservices@riskmapcds.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <descript>
      <abstract>FEMA_PA_Historic_Flood_Maps</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab> The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>ESRI Shapefile</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>DVD</offmedia>
            <recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>Contact Distributor</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2015</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://hazards.fema.gov</onlink>
      <onlink>http://www.epsg.org</onlink>
      <metprof>FEMA NFIP Metadata Content and Format Standard</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <Esri>
    <CreaDate>20150819</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>09181000</CreaTime>
    <ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle>
    <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
    <DataProperties>
      <itemProps>
        <itemLocation>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\ALCES\D$\DATA\FEMA_update\NFHL_42_20131111_metadata</linkage>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
        </itemLocation>
      </itemProps>
      <copyHistory>
        <copy source="D:\DATA\FEMA_update\FEMA_NFHL_42_PA_20131111\NFHL_42_20131111_metadata" dest="\\ALCES\D$\DATA\FEMA_update\NFHL_42_20131111_metadata" date="20150819" time="09181000" />
      </copyHistory>
    </DataProperties>
    <ModDate>20150819</ModDate>
    <ModTime>9354300</ModTime>
    <scaleRange>
      <minScale>50000</minScale>
      <maxScale>5000</maxScale>
    </scaleRange>
    <ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat>
    <ArcGISProfile>FGDC</ArcGISProfile>
  </Esri>
  <dataIdInfo>
    <idPurp>The FIRM is the basis for floodplain management, mitigation, and insurance activities for the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP). Insurance applications include enforcement of the mandatory purchase requirement of the Flood Disaster Protection Act, which "... requires the purchase of flood insurance by property owners who are being assisted by Federal programs or by Federally supervised, regulated or insured agencies or institutions in the acquisition or improvement of land facilities located or to be located in identified areas having special flood hazards, " Section 2 (b) (4) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. In addition to the identification of Special Flood Hazard Areas (SFHAs), the risk zones shown on the FIRMs are the basis for the establishment of premium rates for flood coverage offered through the NFIP. The FIRM Database presents the flood risk information depicted on the FIRM in a digital format suitable for use in electronic mapping applications. The FIRM Database  serves to archive the information collected during the Flood Risk Project.</idPurp>
    <idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;FEMA Historic Products Once a FIRM or FIS has been superseded by a new version, it will be categorized as a Historic Product. After they move to this status, these products are no longer official and binding under the NFIP (National Flood Insurance Program). However, Historic Products may serve as valuable reference information and provide a record of an area's changing flood risks over time. They are made available on the Map Service Center for these purposes. Letters of Map Change (LOMC) that were issued to amend Historic Products when they were still effective are also listed here. A LOMC is a formal document that communicates an official modification to an effective Flood Insurance Rate Map (FIRM). LOMCs are issued in place of a physical alteration and re-publication of the map. Regulatory Mapping Products Flood Insurance Rate Map (FIRM) - The official map of a community on which FEMA has delineated both the special hazard areas and the risk premium zones applicable to the community. Full FIRM panels are quite large (36' x 25.875'), so most users will prefer to print out a smaller selected portion called a FIRMette. This can be accomplished by selecting "View" once you have located your FIRM or by using the FIRMette - Desktop application. Flood Insurance Study (FIS) - A compilation and presentation of flood risk data for specific watercourses, lakes and coastal flood hazard areas within a community. The FIS report provides a detailed written account of a flood hazard mapping study and its findings. Letters of Map Change (LOMC) - Documents, including different types of Letters of Map Revision (LOMR) and Letters of Map Amendment (LOMA), that are issued by FEMA to revise or amend the flood hazard information shown on the FIRM without requiring the FIRM to be physically revised and republished. In addition, FEMA issues a formal determination letter, called a LOMC Revalidation or LOMC-VALID letter - when one or more previously issued LOMCs are found to still be valid during a new flood mapping study of an area. Revalidation letters are included in the LOMC product results on this site.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs>
    <idCitation>
      <resTitle>FEMA Historic Flood Map</resTitle>
    </idCitation>
    <searchKeys>
      <keyword>hydrology</keyword>
      <keyword>environment</keyword>
      <keyword>inlandWaters</keyword>
      <keyword>structure</keyword>
      <keyword>transportation</keyword>
      <keyword>elevation</keyword>
      <keyword>FIRM</keyword>
      <keyword>FEMA Flood Hazard Zone</keyword>
      <keyword>FIRM Database</keyword>
      <keyword>Special Flood Hazard Area</keyword>
      <keyword>Flood Insurance Rate Map</keyword>
      <keyword>CBRS</keyword>
      <keyword>Coastal Barrier Resources System</keyword>
      <keyword>Riverine Flooding</keyword>
      <keyword>Coastal Flooding</keyword>
      <keyword>NFIP</keyword>
      <keyword>Base Flood Elevation</keyword>
      <keyword>SFHA</keyword>
      <keyword>Floodway</keyword>
    </searchKeys>
    <resConst>
      <Consts>
        <useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The hardcopy FIRM and FIRM Database and the accompanying FIS are the official designation of SFHAs and Base Flood Elevations (BFEs) for the NFIP. For the purposes of the NFIP, changes to the flood risk information published by FEMA may only be performed by FEMA and through the mechanisms established in the NFIP regulations (44 CFR Parts 59-78). These digital data are produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRMs and generally match the hardcopy map exactly. Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit>
      </Consts>
    </resConst>
  </dataIdInfo>
  <mdHrLv>
    <ScopeCd value="005" />
  </mdHrLv>
</metadata>