<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>(creation): US Fish and Wildlife Service</origin>
        <origin>(compilation): Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</origin>
        <pubdate>20030128</pubdate>
        <title>
WETLANDS_NWI_POINT_IN: National Wetland Inventory Points
in Indiana (US Fish and Wildlife Service, 1:3M,
Point Shapefile)
</title>
        <edition>National Wetland Inventory</edition>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Evansville, IN</pubplace>
          <publish>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This dataset is a compilation of
the National Wetland Inventory created by the US Fish
and Wildlife Service &lt;http://www.nwi.fws.gov/&gt;  Dataset is one layer in the Indiana
Statewide GIS Database funded by Indiana Department of Transportation.  This metadata
applies to one shapefile for Indiana.
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
WETLANDS_NWI_POINT_IN is a point shapefile that contains features
of wetlands, lakes, ponds and other water resources in Indiana counties. Point
features are used to represent areas which may be small to be represented
by a polygon. These layers are compiled from the National Wetland Inventory.
This layer is intended for use with its companion layers of Wetland
polygons and Wetland lines.
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"NWI digital data files are records of wetlands location and
classification as defined by the U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife
Service. This dataset is one of a series available in 7.5
minute by 7.5 minute blocks containing ground planimetric
coordinates of wetlands point, line, and area features and
wetlands attributes. Wetland Attributes follow the Cowardin
Classification System (1979). The digital data as well as
the hardcopy maps that were used as the source for the
digital data are produced and distributed by the U.S. Fish
&amp; Wildlife Service's National Wetlands Inventory project."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
BROAD, GENERAL information for planning, development, and research
in Indiana.
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"The data provide consultants, planners, and resource
managers with information on wetland location and type. The
data were collected to meet U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service's
mandate to map the wetland and deepwater habitats of the
United States. The purpose of this survey was not to map
all wetlands and deepwater habitats of the United States,
but rather to use aerial photointerpretation techniques to
produce thematic maps that show, in most cases, the larger
ones and types that can be identified by such techniques.
The objective was to provide better geospatial information
on wetlands than found on the U.S. Geological Survey
topographic maps. It was not the intent of the NWI
to produce maps that show exact wetland boundaries
comparable to boundaries derived from ground surveys.
Boundaries are therefore generalized in most cases.
Consequently, the quality of the wetland data is variable
mainly due to source photography, ease or difficulty of
interpreting specific wetland types, andsurvey
methods (e.g., level of field effort and state-of-the-art
of wetland delineation) (see section on "Completenesss_Report"
for more information."
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Data is derived from the National Wetland Inventory
(USFWS). More information about the NWI can be found at &lt;http://www.nwi.fws.gov/&gt;.
Wetlands_NWI_codeset.html contains the definitions to describe the NWI wetland
type codes. Specific metadata for wetland creation for individual 24K quadrangles
may be obtained from the NWI website.
Dataset consists of 1 shapefile for Indiana.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1971</begdate>
          <enddate>1992</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>source photography date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.0157</westbc>
        <eastbc>-86.8562</eastbc>
        <northbc>38.5276</northbc>
        <southbc>37.3724</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
          <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcView version 3.2 shapefile format.</native>
    <themekey>
Theme Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus
Place Place_Keyword_Thesaurus
</themekey>
    <useconst>Hydrology--Wetlands_Inventory_Points</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"Attribute accuracy is tested by manual comparison of the source with
hard copy printouts and/or symbolized display of the digital wetlands
data on an interactive computer graphic system.In addition, WAMS
software (USFWS-NWI)."
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"No duplicate features exist nor duplicate points in
a data string. Point data are represented by two sets of
coordinate pairs, each with the same coordinate values.
All data crossing the neatline are clipped to the
neatline and data within a specified tolerance of the
neatline are snapped to the neatline. Tests for logical
consistency are performed by WAMS verification software (USFWS-NWI)."
</logic>
    <complete>
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"All photointerpretable wetlands are mapped given
considerations of map and photo scale and state-of-the-art
wetland delineation techniques. The target mapping unit is
an estimate of the minimum-sized wetland that should be
consistently mapped. It is not the smallest wetland that
appears on the map, but instead it is the size class of the
smallest group of wetlands that NWI attempts to map
consistently. Users must realize however that some wetland
types are conspicuous and readily identified (e.g., ponds)
and smaller wetlands of these types may be mapped. Other
types (drier-end wetlands and forested wetlands, especially
evergreen types) are more difficult to photointerpret and
larger ones may be missed. In forested regions, the target
mapping unit varies with the scale of the aerial
photographs given acceptable quality (e.g., captured during
spring, leaf-off condition for deciduous trees), as follows
for the Northeast, Southeast, and Northwest: 1:80,000 = 3-5
acres; 1:58,000 = 1-3 acres, and 1:40,000 = 1 acre. This
means that where 1:58,000 photography was used, the NWI
maps should show most wetlands larger than 1-3 acres. In
the treeless prairies (e.g., Upper Midwest), 1/4-acre
wetlands are typically mapped due to the openness of the
terrain and occurrence of wetlands in distinct depressions.
In forested regions, small open water and emergent wetlands
may also be mapped where conspicuous. For Alaska, the
target mapping unit is 2-5 acres, while for the Southwest,
1-3 acres is the target. Map users must pay close attention
to the photo scale used to prepare the
maps. Also, users should be aware that black and white
imagery tends to yield more conservative interpretations
than color infrared imagery, except when the latter was
acquired during a dry year, complicating wetland detection.
In most areas, farmed wetlands are not mapped, with
exceptions including prairie pothole-type wetlands,
cranberry bogs, and diked former tidelands in the
Sacramento valley. Mucklands and other farmed wetlands are
usually not shown on the maps. As mentioned in the
"Use_Constraints" section, no attempt was made to separate
regulated wetlands from other wetlands, as these decisions
must be based on criteria established by Federal and state
regulatory agencies. Maps produced by photointerpretation
techniques will never be as accurate as a detailed
on-the-ground delineation, so the boundaries on the NWI
maps should be considered generalized, especially in areas
of low topographic relief (e.g., coastal plains and
glaciolacustrine plains). Partly drained wetlands may also
be conservatively mapped, since they may be difficult to
photointerpret and in many cases, require site-specific
assessment for validation. For more information on the
limitations of NWI maps, consult "NWI Maps: What They Tell
Us" (National Wetlands Newsletter Vol 19/2, March-April
1997, pp. 7- 12; a copy can be obtained from the U.S. Fish
and Wildlife Service, ES-NWI, 300 Westgate Center Drive,
Hadley, MA 01035)."
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
National Wetland Inventory metadata, USFWS, states -

"Horizontal positional accuracy for the digital data is
tested by visual comparison of the source with hard copy plots."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>vertical position was not an attribute in the data</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), U.S. Department of
Agriculture (USDA), National Aeronautics and Space
Administration (NASA), special project
</origin>
            <pubdate>19710101 - 19920101, Variable by Quad</pubdate>
            <title>
National Aerial Photography Program (NAPP), National High
Altitude Photography (NHAP), Agricultural and Stabilization
Conservation Service (ASCS), NASA or special project photography.
</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>20000 - 132000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>
black and white, color infrared, or natural color aerial
photograph film transparency
</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1971</begdate>
              <enddate>1992</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>aerial photograph date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NWI1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>wetlands spatial and attribute information</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</origin>
            <pubdate>19710101 - 19920101, Variable by Quad</pubdate>
            <title>7.5 minute Quadrangles</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Reston,VA</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>20000, 24000, 25000, 30000, and 62500 by quad</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1902</begdate>
              <enddate>1992</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NWI2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>base cartographic data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service, National Wetlands
Inventory
</origin>
            <pubdate>19710101 - 19920101, Variable by Quad</pubdate>
            <title>Wetlands by Quad</title>
            <geoform>digital map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>St.Petersburg, Florida</pubplace>
              <publish>
U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service, National Wetlands
Inventory
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>20000, 24000, 25000, 30000, and 62500 by quad</srcscale>
        <typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1979</begdate>
              <enddate>1994</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NWI3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>wetlands location and classification</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
NWI maps are compiled through manual photointerpretation
(using cartgraphic Engineering 4X Mirror Stereoscopes) of
NHAP or NAPP aerial photography supplemented by Soil
Surveys and field checking of wetland photo signatures.
Delineated wetland boundaries are manually transferred from
interpreted photos to USGS 7.5 minute topographic
quadrangle maps and then manually labelled. Quality control
steps occur throughout the photointerpretation, map
compilation, and map reproduction processes.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NWI1 and NWI2</srcused>
        <procdate>1979-1994</procdate>
        <srcprod>NWI3</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Name Unknown</cntper>
              <cntorg>
U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service,
National Wetlands Inventory
</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Chief Cartographer</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>9720 Executive Center Drive</address>
              <city>St. Petersburg</city>
              <state>Florida</state>
              <postal>33702</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Digital wetlands data are either manually digitized or
scanned from stable-base copies of the 1:24,000 scale
wetlands overlays registered to the standard U.S. Geological
Survey (USGS) 7.5 minute quadrangles into topologically
correct data files using Wetlands Analytical Mapping System
(WAMS) software.  Files contain ground planimetric
coordinates and wetland attributes. The quadrangles were
referenced to the North American Datum of 1927 (NAD27)
horizontal datum.  The scanning process captured the digital
data at a scanning resolution of at least 0.001 inches; the
resulting raster data were vectorized and then attributed on
an interactive editing station.  Manual digitizing used a
digitizing table to capture the digital data at a resolution
of at least 0.005 inches; attribution was performed as the
data were digitized.  The determination of scanning versus
manual digitizing production method was based on feature
density, source map quality, feature symbology, and
availability of production systems.  The data were checked
for position by comparing plots of the digital data to the
source material.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NWI3</srcused>
        <procdate>1981 - present; varies by quad</procdate>
        <srcprod>NWI-Digital</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Name Unknown</cntper>
              <cntorg>
U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service,
National Wetlands Inventory
</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Chief Cartographer</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>9720 Executive Center Drive</address>
              <city>St. Petersburg</city>
              <state>Florida</state>
              <postal>33702</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A set of the NWI wetland quadrangles in Indiana was purchased
from Geocommunity to save the time of downloading them from the
website. Files were unzipped and ESRI ArcInfo
coverages were converted to ESRI ArcView 3.2 shapefiles resulting
in a shapefile of polygons, lines, and points for each
county.  Wetland quads for each feature type were merged for
each county, then cut to the county boundaries.  Some computer
generated fields used in processing were deleted from the tables.
The dataset was then reprojected to North American Datum of 1983 (NAD83)
using ESRI ArcView and the ESRI ArcView extension Projector
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NWI-Digital</srcused>
        <procdate>20010100 to 20021200</procdate>
        <srcprod>WETLANDS_NWI_POINT_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Daniel Townsend and Cinda Bonds</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller &amp; Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Transportation Engineer I, Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47715</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-479-6200</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <hours>8-5 CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates, utilizing ESRI ArcView version 3.2
and the ESRI ArcView extension Geoprocessing, merged 92 shapefiles
representing all Indiana counties into one (1) shapefile for Indiana.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>WETLANDS_NWI_POINT_'COUNTY'</srcused>
        <procdate>20030127</procdate>
        <srcprod>WETLAND_NWI_POINT_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47715</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-479-6200</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <cntemail>
nschroeder@blainc.com
Contact_Website:  www.blainc.com
</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit. v 2.6.1) and
MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20030128</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47715-4006</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1-Many, variable by county</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate Pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>WETLANDS_NWI_POINT_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Attribute</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Wetland Attribute as assigned by the Cowardin System</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WETLANDS_NWI_CODEST.HTML</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>classification of the wetland</codesetn>
            <codesets>
Cowardin, L.M., V. Carter, F. Golet, and E. LaRoe. 1979.
Classification of wetlands and deepwater habitats of the
United States. U.S. Fish Wildlife Service. 103 pp.
</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Division</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website:  www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
No claims to accuracy are made on this data. It is intended
to be used only for general planning purposes. Detailed
planning or analysis will require more accurate data.
LIMITATION OF LIABILITY
The product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user.
Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates
is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20021213</metd>
    <metrd>20040407</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
          <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cbonds@blainc.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the BLA/IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  BLA/IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the BLA/IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>