<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>(creation): US Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>(compilation): Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</origin>
        <pubdate>20021100</pubdate>
        <title>
WATERSHEDS_HUC08_CATALOG_UNITS_USGS_IN: Cataloging Units, 8-digit,
Hydrologic Units, in Indiana, (Derived from US Geological Survey,
1:24,000 Polygon Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Evansville, IN</pubplace>
          <publish>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This dataset is derived from
the Digital Dataset of 14-digit hydrologic units in Indiana
created by the US Geological Survey and Natural Resources
Conservation Service; &lt;http://in.water.usgs.gov/&gt;
Dataset is one layer in the Indiana Statewide GIS Database
funded by Indiana Department of Transportation.
</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
      <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
WATERSHEDS_HUC08_CATALOG_UNITS_USGS_IN is a polygon shapefile showing the
boundaries of cataloging units in Indiana.
Cataloging units are noted by a 8-digit hydrologic unit. Actual
hydrologic units often extend beyond the state and county
boundaries.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
Provide a large-scale digital database of 8-digit HU (cataloging unit, HUC) boundaries
for BROAD, GENERAL information for planning, development, and research
in Indiana.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
HUC08_CATALOG_UNITS_USGS_IN was created by dissolving
the Digital Dataset of 14-digit hydrologic units in Indiana
created by the US Geological Survey and Natural Resources
Conservation Service; &lt;http://in.water.usgs.gov/&gt;
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19460101</begdate>
          <enddate>19910101</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date of source lineage</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1607</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.6882</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7753</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7554</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Hydrologic Unit</themekey>
        <themekey>Hydrologic Unit Boundary</themekey>
        <themekey>Hydrologic Unit Code</themekey>
        <themekey>HUC</themekey>
        <themekey>HU</themekey>
        <themekey>HUA</themekey>
        <themekey>8-digit hydrologic unit</themekey>
        <themekey>cataloging unit</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>DeKalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
          <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcView version 3.2 shapefile format</native>
    <useconst>Hydrology--Watersheds_HUC08</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
Hydrologic unit codes were added by the USGS and
NRCS personnel. Attributes were rechecked using 1:24000
checkplots. Attribute processes are fully described in the source information metadata.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
No overlaps or slivers encountered. Some multi-part
polygons may exist because clipping to the state boundary can
sometimes created separate pieces of the same cataloging unit.
</logic>
    <complete>
USGS metadata reports

"This shapefile shows only the areas within the state of
Indiana. Actual hydrologic units often
extend beyond the state and county boundaries. All area
attributes reflect only the portion of the hydrologic unit
that lies within Indiana."
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
USGS metadata reports -

"All digitized lines fall within 0.025 inches of the source
linework. The source linework had an average thickness of
approximately 0.025 inches. The combined variation of about
0.05 inches at 1:24,000 scale constitutes a potential deviation
of about 100 feet on the ground. The user is reminded that the
source drainage-basin divides were interpreted from the
topography represented on each 1:24,000 scale map."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
Vertical accuracy was not a factor in the digital production
of the data set.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>
hand-drawn drainage divides for streams with drainage
areas greater than 5 square miles
</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1946</begdate>
              <enddate>1991</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>
Publication date of USGS 7.5' topo maps used to create a
hand-drawn source linework of drainage-basin boundaries
</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>drainage</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
These hand-drawn drainage-basin divides provided the basis for
the 14-digit HU's in this ESRI ArcInfo coverage.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
Krysten M. Debroka and David A. Cohen, US Geological
Survey, Robert E. Dunn and Bruce J. Nielson, Natural
Resources Conservation Service
</origin>
            <pubdate>19990801</pubdate>
            <title>Digital dataset of 14-digit hydrologic units in Indiana</title>
            <edition>Version 1.0.0, July 1999</edition>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
Contact - District Chief, Indiana District, USGS-WRD,
5957 Lakeside Blvd, Indianapolis, Indiana 46278,
317-290-3333, dc_in@usgs.gov
</othercit>
            <onlink>http://in.water.usgs.gov/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>hardcopy</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19460101</begdate>
              <enddate>19910101</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>
Publication date of USGS 7.5' topo maps used to create a
hand-drawn source linework of drainage-basin boundaries
</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>IN14_HUC</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Digital file of Indiana subwatersheds (14 digit HUC)</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A TIC coverage was generated for the State of Indiana and immediate vicinity
with a coordinate TIC at every 7.5 minutes of latitude and longitude. These
TICS corresponded to the corner vertices of the 7.5-minute topographic maps
that included any area in Indiana. The drainage divides on most of the maps
(693 of 710) were digitized by hand on an ALTEK model AC-40 digitizing tablet.
The drainage divides on the remaining 17 maps were scanned on a Scangraphics
model CF1000 scanner.
Following are the procedures used to hand digitize the drainage divides on 693 maps:
Each map was taped to the digitizing tablet. The ARCEDIT module of ESRI ArcInfo was used
to determine the Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) of the 4 map corners as compared to the
4 corresponding TICs in the TIC coverage. All RMSE values for hand-digitized maps were
0.016 (the equivalent of 32 feet on the ground) or less. The RMSE values, along with other
quality-assurance data, are recorded in the arc attribute table, in_hu14.aat. The drainage
divides on the map were digitized in stream mode with a vertex every 0.020 inches
(the equivalent of 40 feet on the ground).
The following ARCEDIT tolerances were set-
INTERSECTARCS ALL NODESNAP CLOSEST,32 ARCSNAP ON,32 SNAPPING CLOSEST,64 GRAIN 21.15783271851
WEEDTOLERANCE 16
The drainage divides on the following 17 topographic maps were scanned-
Bluffton, Gilman, Quincy, Cloverdale, Hazelrigg, Roll, Deerfield, Montpelier, Saline
City, Domestic, Newport, Shannondale, Frankton, Omega, Wallace, Gaston and Petroleum
Following are the procedures used to scan the drainage divides on these 17 maps-
Each map was scanned at 200 dots per inch (true optics out). The Scangraphics Editor
was used to remove extraneous lines from the resulting raster-image file. The ESRI ArcInfo
module ARCSCAN was used to vectorize the raster-image file. All RMSE values for scanned
maps were 0.013 (the equivalent of 26 feet on the ground) or less.
The following Arc Environment Properties were used in ARCSCAN during vectorization-
Copy parallel- default Move parallel- default Rotate angle- default Align distance-
default Vertex distance- 0.556 Node snap tol- Off Arc snap tol- Off Intersect arcs-
Off Unsplit Item- Off
The following Tracing Environment Settings were used in ARCSCAN during vectorization-
Straighten Properties- Generalization- Tolerance- 0.01 Line Straightening Distance-
10.000 Range- 30.000 Angle- 15 Corner- 30 Line Properties- Width- 16.000 Value- 1
Gap- 15.000 Dash- 20.000 Hole- 0.05 Fan angle- 45 2nd angle- 90 Variance- 200
The following general procedures were performed subsequent to digitizing or scanning
in 6-10 maps-
After approximately 6-10 maps were digitized, the coverage was stripped of line overshoots
and undershoots using the CLEAN command with DANGLE=50 and FUZZY_TOLERANCE=1. The newly
digitized lines were then examined along the edges of the map where they should meet
previously digitized lines from an adjoining map. Occasionally the ends of lines on
adjoining maps did not join correctly. The lines on the original maps were examined, and
in most cases, the drainage divides on the original paper maps did not precisely align
across map edges. These lines were corrected on the original maps and the appropriate
portion of the line was re-digitized.
All digitized lines were examined for node dangles, double lines, and sliver polygons.
These errors were corrected and a checkplot of each digitized map was plotted at
1:24,000 scale with a line thickness of 0.025 inches. Checkplots were placed over the
original maps on a light table, and any portion of the digitized linework that did not
overlie the original line was re-digitized. For quality control, 36% of the digitized maps
(256 maps) were later re-plotted and all lines were checked by either a USGS staff
member (other than the individual who originally digitized the map) or an NRCS staff
member. Dates for this quality-assurance activity are recorded in the arc attribute table
in_hu14.aat.
Digitizing efficiency began to decrease after approximately 35-40 maps were digitized
into the coverage. Undue amounts of time were being spent waiting for the image of
digitized lines to be displayed on the computer screen. At this point, a second temporary
TIC coverage was generated in the same manner as the original TIC coverage. Additional
maps were then digitized into this temporary TIC coverage. Periodically, the temporary
coverage was joined with the original coverage using the UNION command. All lines were
then deleted from the temporary coverage. This process was repeated until all requisite
maps were digitized.
Each polygon in the coverage represented a distinct drainage basin and was attributed
with 1) a code indicating whether the polygon represented a contributing or
non-contributing area, and 2) a number based on the discharge point for the basin. These
discharge-point numbers were based on the first column of data in Table 3 in Hoggatt
(1975). An electronic file of the discharge-point numbers was sent to NRCS staff. NRCS
staff used copies of the 1:24,000 scale maps with delineated drainage basins to determine
14-digit HUs according to their guidelines in NRCS National Instruction No. 170-304
(U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service, 1992, Mapping
and digitizing watershed and subwatershed hydrologic-unit boundaries: National Instruction
no. 170-304, 26 p., accessed May 30, 1997 at URL http://www.nhq.nrcs.usda.gov/hu/ni70304.
html). NRCS staff then updated the electronic file of discharge-point numbers with the
appropriate 14-digit HUC's and returned the file to USGS staff. The USGS staff converted
the file to an INFO table and placed the 14-digit HUC into the item called HUC14_C. The
RELATE function in INFO was used, with the discharge-point number as the relate item,
to attribute each polygon with the 14-digit HUC in an item called HUC_14. This procedure
rendered several contiguous polygons with identical 14-digit HUC's (HUC_14). Lines
dividing contiguous polygons with identical 14-digit HUC's were deleted using the
DISSOLVE command to produce the final polygons in the subject data set.
The STATISTICS function in ARC was used to calculate the total non- contributing
area for each 14-digit HUC. The RELATE function in INFO was then used to attribute
each polygon in the final data set with the total non-contributing area, calculated
in acres. Manual adjustments were made where individual 14-digit HU's were represented
by two or more non-contiguous polygons.
To ensure that each 14-digit HU had the correct boundaries and the correct 14-digit HUC,
checkplots of each map were plotted at 1:24,000 scale with each HU labeled with its HUC.
These checkplots were then sent to NRCS. Any errors were noted and corrected, and new
checkplots were generated and re-checked until every map was correct. Quality-assurance
data for this activity is included in the arc-attribute table (AAT) of the final data set.
HU names, provided by the NRCS, were added to the polygon-attribute table (PAT) of in_hu14.
These names are based on the primary waterway within each HU.
The arcs were assigned a 2-digit attribute, called HU_DIV, indicating the boundary type
represented: 6 = Accounting Unit, 8 = Cataloging Unit, 11 = Watershed, 14 = Subwatershed,
or the Indiana state line. Note that arcs representing the state line have a hu_div = 0
and all other arc attributes are blank or 0.
Three colleague reviews of the final data set of 14-digit hydrologic units, the metadata
and the Fact Sheet were performed in July 1999, two reviews by USGS staff and one review
by a staff member of one of the cooperating agencies, the Indiana Department of Environmental
Management.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>drainage</srcused>
        <procdate>19960201 - 19990801</procdate>
        <srcprod>IN14_HUC</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Krysten M. Debroka and David A. Cohen; Robert E. Dunn and Bruce J. Nielson</cntper>
              <cntorg>US Geological Survey; Natural Resources Conservation Service</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>Indiana District, USGS-WRD</address>
              <address>5957 Lakeside Blvd</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46278</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-290-3333</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The source file "DIGITAL DATASET OF 14-DIGIT HYDROLOGIC
UNITS IN INDIANA downloaded from the website and converted
from ESRI ArcInfo coverage to Shapefile. A dissolve operation was
performed on the HUC_08 field using geoprocessing which merged
all subwatersheds into the larger cataloging unit polygon. Area and
perimeter fields were recalculated by software, but the hu_area
and non-contrib fields were attributed by adding the values of
those fields from the 14HU data. The number subwatersheds merged
into each cataloging unit is indicated in the "count" field.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>IN_HUC14</srcused>
        <procdate>20020801</procdate>
        <srcprod>WATERSHEDS_HUC08_CATALOG_UNITS_USGS_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Assoicates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47715-4006</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit. v 2.6.1) and
MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <srcused>HUC08_WATERSHEDS_USGS_IN</srcused>
        <procdate>20030309</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47715-4006</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Using ESRI ArcToolbox v. 8.3, the shapefile was changed from UTM Zone 16 NAD27 to UTM Zone 16 NAD83.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20040428</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>39</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>WATERSHEDS_HUC08_CATALOG_UNITS_USGS_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Huc_8</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>8-digit Hydrologic Units; unique identification</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Count</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
number of subwatersheds dissolved to
into the cataloging unit polygon
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software generated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Software computed</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of polygon in map units (Sq meters)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software generated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>83396097.7070</rdommin>
            <rdommax>7043738227.7071</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Hu_acres</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Calculated as AREA * 0.0002471053; compiled
by adding values of the subwatersheds which were dissolved
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USGS and USDA-NRCS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>20607.6000</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1740545.5000</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Noncontrib</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Area of non-contributing portion of 14-digit HU, in acres;
compiled by adding values of the subwatersheds which were dissolved
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USGS and USDA-NRCS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>216107.4000</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Division</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website:  www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
No claims to accuracy are made on this data. It is intended
to be used only for general planning purposes.
LIMITATION OF LIABILITY
The product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user.
Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates
is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20021119</metd>
    <metrd>20040428</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
          <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>IN</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cbonds@blainc.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the BLA/IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  BLA/IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the BLA/IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>