<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</origin>
        <pubdate>20111028</pubdate>
        <title>AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN: Bedrock Aquifer Systems of Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, 1:500,000, Polygon Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This shapefile was derived and modified from a pre-existing published paper map:
Gray, H.H., Ault, C.H., and Keller, S.J., 1987, Bedrock Geologic Map of Indiana, Indiana Geological Survey Miscellaneous Map 48, which was at a 1:500,000 scale.
Digital coverage of the Bedrock Geologic Map of Indiana was created by the Indiana Geological Survey (polygon shapefile, 20020318).

The Aquifer System attributes were added to the shapefile by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water. Several units were merged based on
common hydrogeologic characteristics and the lines separating the units were removed. This data set was provided to personnel of the Indiana Geological Survey
(IGS) on October 28, 2011 by Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water personnel. The data was provided in an ESRI shapefile format, and was named
"AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN.SHP". This file was approved for public distribution by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR), Division of Water (DOW).
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://inmap.indiana.edu/viewer.htm</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN is a polygon shapefile that shows bedrock aquifer systems of the State of Indiana. The source scale of the map depicting the
aquifers was 1:500,000. The attribute table for the aquifer system units include aquifer system name, aquifer system type, potential yield in gallons per minute (gpm),
total thickness (feet), and a web link to more detailed information.

A layer (AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN.lyr) file accompanies this data layer to assist the user with symbolization so that the sequence of aquifer systems can be
visualized in geographic information system (GIS) software, particularly ESRI software products.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN was created to provide a digital coverage of the bedrock aquifer systems of the State of Indiana, suitable for use in a GIS, from a
preexisting published paper map (Gray, H.H., Ault,C.H., and Keller, S.J., 1987, Bedrock Geologic Map of Indiana, Indiana Geological Survey Miscellaneous Map 48), and
associated digital coverage created by the Indiana Geological Survey (polygon shapefile, 20020318). The Aquifer Systems attribute was added to the shapefile by the
Indiana Department of Natural Resources Division of Water. Several units were merged based on common hydrogeologic characteristics and the lines separating the units
were removed. For the purpose of assessing the limits of aquifer system boundaries, the bedrock aquifer system mapping is intended for use at a scale of 1:500,000 or
smaller. Additional information can be accessed at http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/4302.htm, the statewide county-based aquifer systems project web page. The county maps,
with accompanying text and high-capacity well tables, describe characteristics such as geologic materials, aquifer system thickness, depth to bedrock, static water levels,
well yield, amount of rock penetrated, and typical well depths. Descriptions of the aquifer systems rely heavily on the IDNR/DOW digital water well record database
(about 400,000 records available online) along with other useful digital information (see Indiana Map) where available (e.g. seismic data, bedrock topography maps,
soil surveys, oil and gas wells). In addition, publications by the U.S. Geological Survey, Indiana Geological Survey, and other entities were very helpful.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Descriptions of the aquifer systems rely heavily on the IDNR/DOW digital water well record database (about 400,000 records available online
at http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/3595.htm) along with other useful digital information (see IndianaMap) where available (e.g. seismic data, bedrock topography maps, soil
surveys, oil and gas wells). In addition, publications by the U.S. Geological Survey, Indiana Geological Survey, and other entities were very helpful.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1987</begdate>
          <enddate>2011</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.160656</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.688201</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.781177</northbc>
        <southbc>37.755410</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Division of Water (DOW)</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrogeology</themekey>
        <themekey>groundwater</themekey>
        <themekey>aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>aquifer systems</themekey>
        <themekey>bedrock aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>groundwater availability mapping</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
    <useconst>Hydrology--Aquifer_Systems_Bedrock_IDNR</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The Aquifer System rock unit boundary attributes contained in this layer are those reported in Gray and others, 1987, and are intended to
be used at a scale of 1:500,000 or smaller. The accuracy of the reported aquifer characteristics is not intended to represent site-specific conditions, but to identify
types of aquifers and typical extents of rock units likely to contain and produce groundwater. The type of aquifer, total thickness ranges, and potential aquifer
yield ranges are estimates of regional aquifer characteristics.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>ESRI ArcInfo polygon topology is present.</logic>
    <complete>
In conducting the mapping, the authors evaluated hundreds of water well records, especially those having relatively complete information on
well location, construction, pump test, and lithology. There were many areas in the counties with sparse information because of lack of well records or incomplete
records. Few wells are being drilled in parts of the county served by a public water system. County-based mapping in places show the underground coal mine area coverage
(see IndianaMap, IGS  COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_IN shapefile) and discuss groundwater potential. This coverage and discussion are only available for individual counties on
the IDNR DOW Aquifer Systems Mapping page at http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/4302.htm.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The locations of many wells were field checked and the locations posted on 7.5 minute topographic maps. Visual confirmation of
wells was not always possible. Many locations were based only on the street address, driving directions, or other location information provided on the well record.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
Vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the digital production of AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN. No quantitative tests
were performed.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</origin>
            <pubdate>1987-2011</pubdate>
            <title>Bedrock Aquifer Systems of Indiana</title>
            <geoform>Paper Maps</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/4302.htm</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Paper maps and digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1987</begdate>
              <enddate>2011</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Bedrock Aquifer Systems of Indiana</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Mapped aquifer polygons and tabular data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Mapping of the aquifer systems characteristics rely heavily on the IDNR/DOW digital water well record database (about 400,000 records available online)
along with other useful digital information (see Indiana Map) where available (e.g. seismic data, bedrock topography maps, soil surveys, oil and gas wells).
In addition, publications by the U.S. Geological Survey, Indiana Geological Survey, and other entities were very helpful. Relatively uniform characteristics are
the basis for the naming of an aquifer system. However, some variation between counties is possible. See a particular county of interest at
http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/4302.htm for specific details. AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN was created from a preexisting published paper map (Gray, H.H., Ault,C.H.,
and Keller, S.J., 1987, Bedrock Geologic Map of Indiana, Indiana Geological Survey Miscellaneous Map 48), and associated digital coverage created by the Indiana
Geological Survey (polygon shapefile, 20020318). The Aquifer System attributes were added to the shapefile by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division
of Water. Several units were merged based on common hydrogeologic characteristics and the lines separating the units were removed. The resulting coverage was
converted to a shapefile named "AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN". A polygon coverage was created and attributed, and the shapefile provided to IGS
personnel. Attribute definitions are described below and listed under Entity and Attribute Information. AQ_SYSTEM is the name for the aquifer system group(s) or
other stratigraphic unit(s). AQ_TYPE is the type of geologic material within the aquifer system. TOT_THK_FT is the total thickness of the aquifer system in feet.
YIELD_GPM is the water production in gallons per minute as reported on water well records and registered significant water withdrawal facility forms; the
terms "typically, generally,and commonly" refer to the middle 60% statistically for reported domestic yield or reported capacity for registered significant
groundwater withdrawal wells (defined as 70 gpm or greater). MORE_INFO is a web link &lt;http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/4302.htm&gt; to more detailed information regarding
the Aquifer Systems Mapping program with links to individual county pages with text and a high-capacity table, and Basin Study publications.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping, IDNR water well database, various IGS and USGS data layers</srcused>
        <procdate>20111028</procdate>
        <srcprod>AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</cntorg>
              <cntper>Jerry Unterreiner</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>402 W Washington St, Rm W264</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46204-2641</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-232-4222</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>317-233-4579</cntfax>
            <cntemail>gunterreiner@dnr.IN.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>0815 to 1615 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software
written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United States Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected,
except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20111121</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>379</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AQ_SYSTEM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Name of the aquifer system group(s), or other stratigraphic unit(s), Values are as follows -- McLeansboro Group;
Carbondale Group; Raccoon Creek Group; Buffalo Wallow, Stephensport, and West Baden Groups; Blue River and Sanders Groups; Borden Group;
New Albany Shale; Coldwater, Ellsworth, and Antrim Shales Silurian and Devonian Carbonates; Maquoketa Group; Trenton, Lexington, and Black River Carbonates
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR DOW Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AQ_TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Type of geologic material within the aquifer system, Values are as follows --

McLeansboro - mostly shale and sandstone, also includes minor amounts of siltstone, limestone, clay, and coal;

Carbondale - mostly shale and sandstone, also includes thin beds of limestone, clay, and coal;

Raccoon Creek - mostly shale and sandstone, also includes thin beds of limestone, clay, and coal;

Buffalo Wallow - mostly shale and sandstone and also includes thin beds of micritic limestone;

Stephensport - sandstone, micritic and skeletal limestone, and shale;

West Baden - shale, sandstone, and micritic and skeletal limestone;

Blue River - mostly micritic, skeletal, and oolitic limestone;

Sanders - mostly skeletal limestone and is cherty in the lower part;

Borden - mostly gray argillaceous siltstone and shale, fine-grained sandstone common, some minor interbedded discontinuous lenses of limestone;

New Albany Shale - black and greenish-gray shale;

Coldwater - mostly gray shale;

Ellsworth - green shale with some black shale in the lower part;

Antrim - black shale with gray shale and limestone in the lower part;

Silurian and Devonian Carbonates - predominantly carbonate rock units (limestone and dolomite) with some interbedded shale units, not easily distinguished
on water well records and so considered as a single water-bearing system;

Maquoketa - mostly shale with some interbedded limestone;

Trenton - limestone, dolomite in NW IN;

Lexington - micritic and skeletal limestone;

Black River - dolomite, limestone, and sandstone
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR DOW Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>YIELD_GPM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Water production in gallons per minute as reported on water well records and registered significant water withdrawal facility
forms; the terms "typically, generally, and commonly" refer to the middle 60% statistically for reported domestic yield or reported capacity for
registered significant groundwater withdrawal wells (defined as 70 gpm or greater), Values are as follows --
McLeansboro Group - commonly 2-15; a few dry holes (pumped) reported;

Carbondale Group - typically 1-10, locally up to 20, some dry holes (pumped) reported;

Raccoon Creek Group - generally 1-15, in limited areas in excess of 70, some dry holes (pumped) reported;

Buffalo Wallow, Stephensport, and West Baden Groups - typically 1-15; locally up to 20, some dry holes (pumped) reported;

Blue River and Sanders Groups - generally 1-20, in limited areas in excess of 100, some dry holes (pumped) reported;

Borden Group - commonly 1-10 with significant drawdown, some dry holes (pumped) reported;

New Albany Shale - typically 1-10; many dry holes reported;

Coldwater, Ellsworth, and Antrim Shales - commonly 1-10; some dry holes (pumped) reported;

Silurian and Devonian Carbonates - typically 10-25 decreasing southward, about 650 high-capacity wells (70 gpm or more);

Maquoketa Group - generally 1-10; many dry holes reported;

Trenton, Lexington, and Black River Carbonates - 1-7 but very few wells completed in system; some dry holes (pumped) reported
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR DOW Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOT_THK_FT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The total thickness of the aquifer system unit(s) in feet (statewide range; see a specific county of interest for more information), values are
as follows --
McLeansboro Group - 0-770;

Carbondale Group - 0-470;

Raccoon Creek Group - 0-1000;

Buffalo Wallow, Stephensport, and West Baden Groups - BW 0-750; S 0-230; WB 0-260;

Blue River and Sanders Groups - BR 0-650; S 0-510;

Borden Group - 0-800;

New Albany Shale - 0-340;

Coldwater, Ellsworth, and Antrim Shales - C 0-500; E 0-200; A 0-220;

Silurian and Devonian Carbonates - 0-1000;

Maquoketa Group - 200-1000;

Trenton, Lexington, and Black River Carbonates - T 0-265 / L 0-250 / BR 100-550
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR DOW Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MORE_INFO</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Web link to more detailed information regarding the Aquifer Systems Mapping program with links to individual county pages with text
including groundwater vulnerability to contamination, a high-capacity table, and Basin Study publications
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR DOW Bedrock Aquifer Systems Mapping</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSInfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source citation should
be included: [AQUIFER_SYSTEMS_BEDROCK_IDNR_IN: Bedrock Aquifer Systems of Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water, 1:500,000,
Polygon Shapefile)]

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana Geological
Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY
Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied, including,
but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability resulting from the use of this
product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product users indirect, incidental, special, or
consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged data or other commercial or economic loss.
Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser
shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20111028</metd>
    <metrd>20111121</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</cntorg>
          <cntper>Jerry Unterreiner</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>402 W. Washington St., Rm. W264</address>
          <city>Indianapolis</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>46204-2641</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>317-232-4222</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>317-233-4579</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gunterreiner@dnr.IN.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>0815 to 1615 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It should not to be altered or summarized. IGS does
not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may
lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>