<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS) (Data originator)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR), Division of Water (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis (CGDA) (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Sally Letsinger (Data compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20081022</pubdate>
        <title>OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN: Water Wells for Monitoring Ground Water in Indiana (United States Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
The following is excerpted from the USGS Web site &lt;http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis/help?nwisweb_overview&gt;:

"As part of the U.S. Geological Survey's (USGS) program for disseminating water data within USGS, to USGS cooperators, and to the general public, the USGS maintains a distributed network of computers and fileservers for the acquisition, processing, review, and long-term storage of water data. This water data is collected at over 1.5 million sites around the country and at some border and territorial sites. This distributed network of computers is called the National Water Information System (NWIS). Many types of data are stored in NWIS, including comprehensive information for site characteristics, well-construction details, time-series data for gage height, streamflow, ground-water level, precipitation, and physical and chemical properties of water. Additionally, peak flows, chemical analyses for discrete samples of water, sediment, and biological media are accessible within NWIS.

"NWISWeb is the USGS public web interface to much of the data stored and managed within NWIS. Data provided by NWISWeb are updated from NWIS on a regularly scheduled basis, and real-time data are generally updated upon receipt at local Water Science Centers. NWISWeb provides several output options including: graphs of real-time streamflow, water levels, and water quality; tabular output in HTML and ASCII tab-delimited files; and summary lists for selected sites that can be used as a basis for reselection to acquire refined details.

"NWISWeb provides a framework to obtain data on the basis of category, such as surface water, ground water, or water quality, and by geographic area. Further refinement is possible by choosing specific site-selection criteria and by defining the output desired. In addition, there are nearly 70 million water-quality results from nearly 4.5 million water samples collected at hundreds of thousands of sites."
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
This point shapefile was created to display in a geographic information systems (GIS)
environment the data points that represent the locations of ground-water monitoring locations in Indiana.
</abstract>
      <purpose>OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN was developed as a tool for displaying the Indiana observation (monitoring) well network in a GIS environment. The data set includes records for wells that are currently active and inactive. Ground-water levels in aquifers throughout the state are used in conjunction with climate and soil-moisture data to monitor drought severity in Indiana.</purpose>
      <supplinf>
The attribute table provides URL links to United States Geological Survey (USGS) Web pages for individual monitoring wells in Indiana. The links provide additional station information and access to water-level measurements collected in the monitoring-well network.

The U.S. Geological Survey, in cooperation with the Indiana Department of Natural Resources has collected ground-water data in Indiana since 1935. Today, the state observation well network consists of 37 active wells located throughout the state. Nine of these observation wells have been selected for monitoring, one in each climate division, to represent the general ground-water condition throughout the state.

The IDNR, Division of Water analysis can be accessed through their Web site:
Indiana Department of Natural Resources, 2008, Status of ground water levels: Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water Web site, &lt;http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/7138.htm&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.

Data from all 37 observation wells are collected in the field periodically by USGS personnel, checked for accuracy, and entered into a computerized database. The data are then downloaded by IDNR, Division of Water, graphed and analyzed.

A primary purpose of monitoring ground-water levels in the state is to monitor drought severity. Additional information on drought severity can be obtained through the following IDNR Web sites:

Indiana Department of Natural Resources, 2008, Climatic onditions: Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water Web site, &lt;http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/7150.htm&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.

Indiana Department of Natural Resources, 2008, Review of available drought indices: Indiana Department of Natural Resources Web site, &lt;http://www.in.gov/dnr/files/ws-drought_indices_2008.pdf&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.

Indiana Department of Natural Resources, 2008, Palmer drought severity index: Indiana Department of Natural Resources Web site, &lt;http://www.in.gov/dnr/files/wa-PDSI_state.pdf&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1935</begdate>
          <enddate>2008</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Data collection date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1606</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.6883</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7810</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7554</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>geoscientific information</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Division of Water</themekey>
        <themekey>water well</themekey>
        <themekey>ground water</themekey>
        <themekey>aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrogeology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>National Water Information System (NWIS)</themekey>
        <themekey>observation well</themekey>
        <themekey>water level</themekey>
        <themekey>ground-water level</themekey>
        <themekey>monitoring well</themekey>
        <themekey>bedrock aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>unconsolidated aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>confined aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>artesian aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>unconfined aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>water-table aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrogeologic interference</themekey>
        <themekey>cone of depression</themekey>
        <themekey>drought monitoring</themekey>
        <themekey>drought severity</themekey>
        <themekey>climate division</themekey>
        <themekey>significant water withdrawal facility (SWWF)</themekey>
        <themekey>water-table drawdown</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS shapefile format, Microsoft Windows XP, approximately 164 Kb</native>
    <useconst>Hydrology--Water_Wells_Observation_Wells</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The ESRI ArcMap point shapefile and Microsoft Excel spreadsheet from which the data were generated were provided by personnel of the IDNR, Division of Water. Many of the attributes in the shapefile attribute table were created by IDNR, Division of Water staff. The accuracy of these attributes was not evaluated. Some clarifications and changes were made for consistency, and obvious typographical errors were corrected to produce OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN.

The following is from the "NWISWeb" site:

United States Geological Survey, 2008, USGS Ground-water data for the nation: National Water Information System Web site, &lt;http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis/gw&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.

"Real-time data are time-series (recorded at fixed intervals) data from automated equipment and represent the most current hydrologic conditions. Measurements are commonly recorded at 5-60 minute intervals and transmitted to the NWIS database every 1-4 hours. Real-time data are available online for 31 days.

"Daily values are summarized from time-series data for each day for the period of record and may represent the daily mean, median, maximum, minimum, and/or other derived value. Daily values include approved, quality-assured data that may be published, and more recent provisional data, whose accuracy has not been verified.

"Manual measurements of depth to water in wells. These measurements are often used to supplement and (or) verify the accuracy of the instantaneous measurements."
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Checks for duplicates (unique values in unique records) were performed on this data set. No checks on topology were performed on this data set.</logic>
    <complete>This data set includes records for 91 active (37) and inactive (54) ground-water observation (monitoring) wells in Indiana, as of 2008.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Accuracy is no better than that of the source material used to compile OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN.SHP. The method of location of the observation wells is unknown; and therefore the positional accuracy is unknown. However, the accuracy is assumed to be at least that of the high-quality points in WATERWELLS_IDNR_IN: Water-Well Locations in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Point Shapefile), which is at a scale of 1:24,000, or about 100 feet on the ground.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Vertical accuracy was not a factor in the digital production of the data set. No quantitative tests were performed.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</origin>
            <pubdate>20061121</pubdate>
            <title>wells_90.shp: point shapefile; this file is an informal working version of a shapefile, not a published product.</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Web server</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1935</begdate>
              <enddate>2006</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data collection date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS observation wells in Indiana</srccitea>
        <srccontr>This data set was used as the basis for the point shapefile representing the locations of ground-water observation wells in Indiana.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</origin>
            <pubdate>20080825</pubdate>
            <title>wells.xls: list of observation (monitoring) wells active in 2008; this file is an informal working copy of a spreadsheet, not a published product.</title>
            <geoform>Spreadsheet</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Web server</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1935</begdate>
              <enddate>2008</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data collection date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>IDNR Water Well Database</srccitea>
        <srccontr>This data set was used as the basis for updating the field "STATUS2008" in OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN to denote observation wells active in Indiana during 2008.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</origin>
            <origin>National Water Information System (NWIS)</origin>
            <pubdate>20080904</pubdate>
            <title>United States Geological Survey, 2008, USGS Ground-water data for the nation: National Water Information System Web site &lt;http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis/gw&gt;, date accessed, September 4, 2008.</title>
            <geoform>Tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Web server</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1935</begdate>
              <enddate>2006</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data access date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USGS observation well station information and downloadable water-level data</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Links to station information and available water-level data are provided in the attribute table of OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The wells_90.shp shapefile was loaded into ESRI ArcMap for editing. The following fields were deleted, ID, 1988_DROUG, MONTHLY_RE, _EASTING_U, NORTHING_U, RANKING, and 2004_activ.

The following fields were retained in OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN but renamed, CLIMATIC_D (now, CLIM_DIV), _AQUIFER_S, (now, AQ_SYS), ARTESIAN, (now, CONFINED), NEAR_SIGNI (now, NEAR_SWWF), WELL_NO__1 (now, WELL_NO), REF_NUMBER (now, IDNR_REF).

The following fields were added and populated, SITEID, STN_INFO, STATUS2008, AQ_TYPE, and URL_Link.

The file was projected from UTM Zone 16 NAD27 to UTM Zone 16 NAD83.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>wells_90.shp, wells.xls, USGS observation well station information and downloadable water-level data (NWIS)</srcused>
        <procdate>20080805</procdate>
        <srcprod>OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Sally Letsinger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1356</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata
Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated
by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution"
and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20081022</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1356</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>91</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Observation_Wells_USGS_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile attribute table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Well_name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Station names (usually the county name followed by a number)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USGS National Water Information System</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Well_no</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Station numbers (abbreviated code representing the station name)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USGS National Water Information System</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IDNR_ref</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique reference number for each corresponding water-well log in the IDNR water-well-log database</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>IDNR water-well-log database reference identification numbers</codesetn>
            <codesets>IDNR, Division of Water</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Siteid</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique number assigned to each water measurement station; in this data set, monitoring wells</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USGS National Water Information System</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Stn_info</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Uniform resource locator (URL) link to United States Geological Survey National Water Information System (NWIS) Web page with station information. Available site descriptive information includes well location information such as latitude and longitude, well depth, and aquifer.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Record_beg</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Beginning year of data record</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1935</rdommin>
            <rdommax>2008</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Status2008</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Active or inactive status of observation wells in the network. If active, the type of active monitoring is denoted.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water and Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Active: Daily</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Monitoring well active in 2008; daily water levels
collected and uploaded periodically
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Active: Real Time</edomv>
            <edomvd>Station active in 2008; real-time data available</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Inactive</edomv>
            <edomvd>Station not active in 2008</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Remarks</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Comments regarding the monitoring well that might affect the interpretation of the measured water-level data. Most comments are observations of hydrogeologic interference from pumping of nearby ground-water wells.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Confined</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Designation of aquifer water-table type</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water and Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>confined</edomv>
            <edomvd>Confined (artesian) aquifer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>unconfined</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unconfined (water table) aquifer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Clim_div</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Climate divisions. This field is included because monitoring well data is used to identify climatic trends, assessing drought conditions, and observing responses to hydrologic events (for example, flooding, drought, snowmelt).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: Northwest Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: North central Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>3</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: Northeast Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>4</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: West central Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>5</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: Central Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>6</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: East central Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>7</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: Southwest Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>8</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: South central Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>9</edomv>
            <edomvd>Climate division: Southeast Indiana</edomvd>
            <edomvds>National Climatic Data Center</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aq_type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of aquifer in which the observation (monitoring) well is developed</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>bedrock</edomv>
            <edomvd>Well monitors water level in a bedrock aquifer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>unconsolidated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Well monitors water level in an unconsolidated aquifer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aq_sys</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Aquifer system, informal name designation</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Near_swwf</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field indicates whether a monitoring well is near a significant water withdrawal facility (defined as a registered facility that has wells or surface-water pumps that have the capacity to withdraw 100,000 gallons per day). Such facilities can often create hydrogeologic interference by drawing down the water in an aquifer ("cone of depression"). This field is included to provide information that might affect the interpretation of the measured water-level data.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR, Division of Water</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NR</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not reported</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>no</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not near significant water withdrawal facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDNR, Division of Water</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>yes</edomv>
            <edomvd>Near significant water withdrawal facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDNR, Division of Water</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Url_link</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Uniform resource locator (URL) link to United States Geological Survey Web page displaying graphs and other links to data from each monitoring well. The type of Web page displayed is based on the well status (see STATUS2008); therefore, an "Active: Real time" station will display different data than an "Active: Daily" station.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable data</resdesc>
    <distliab>

COPYRIGHT 2008, THE TRUSTEES OF INDIANA UNIVERSITY, INDIANA GEOLOGICAL SURVEY, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

The information on these media is proprietary to Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey. Any copying, adaptation, distribution, public performance, or public display of this information without the express written consent of Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is discouraged.

CREDIT:
It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any
products generated from this data. The following source citation should be
included: OBSERVATION_WELLS_USGS_IN: Water Wells for Monitoring Ground Water in Indiana (United States Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile), data compilation by Sally Letsinger, 2008

WARRANTY:
Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405
2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY:
Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20081022</metd>
    <metrd>20081022</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 1356</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2781</cntfax>
        <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS. It is not to be altered
or summarized. IGS does not support secondary distribution. If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>