<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Agnieszka Drobniak</origin>
        <pubdate>20110815</pubdate>
        <title>
COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.SHP: Elevation Ranges of the Seelyville Coal Member (Linton Formation, Pennsylvanian) in Southwestern
Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:125,000, Polygon Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This shapefile was compiled based on data from the National Coal Resource Data System Database (NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb)
(Indiana Geological Survey, Access Database). Mastalerz, M., and Drobniak, A., 2011, The Indiana Geological Survey Coal Stratigraphic Database:
Indiana Geological Survey Report of Progress 39.
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/LayerGallery.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
In the past a series of reports on coal resources of selected counties in Indiana was published as part of the Special Report series of the Indiana Geological
Survey (IGS). These reports included maps showing elevation of the Seelyville Coal Member (Linton Formation, Pennsylvanian). The elevation maps were based on
coal-test records, mine-map notations, and interpretations of geophysical logs that are included in the files of the Indiana Geological Survey. Different
elevation ranges were utilized in the various counties and for different purposes.

Since 1980, staff members of the Indiana Geological Survey have also collected and entered coal resource information into the NCRDS Database as a cooperative
project with the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). The purpose of NCRDS Database is to provide a means of rapid retrieval of point-source coal resource information,
including coal location, elevation, depth, and other parameters. Based on all available data as of October 2010, a new map of Seelyville Coal Member elevation
was created. It is the most current elevation map of the Seelyville Coal Member. Because additional data on coal elevations are obtained by the Indiana Geological
Survey on an annual basis, interested users may wish to contact the IGS for information on these more up-to-date sources.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.SHP was created to provide a multi-county digital shapefile, suitable for use in a GIS, from the Indiana Geological Survey
National Coal Resource Data System Database (NCRDS) a Microsoft Access database of public, point-source coal-resource data in Indiana.
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19850101</begdate>
          <enddate>20110815</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1286</westbc>
        <eastbc>-87.0871</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.9239</northbc>
        <southbc>38.7705</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>energy</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>National Coal Resources Data System (NCRDS)</themekey>
        <themekey>coal</themekey>
        <themekey>elevation</themekey>
        <themekey>coal elevation</themekey>
        <themekey>geology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Seelyville Coal Member</themekey>
        <themekey>Linton Formation</themekey>
        <themekey>Carbondale Group</themekey>
        <themekey>Pennsylvanian</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>
Esri ArcGIS version 10.0 polygon shapefile, Microsoft Windows 7.0, file size 1.87 Mb
</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Coal_Seelyville_Elevation</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012 contains internal attributes with designations that refer to minimum and maximum values (in feet) of various
elevation ranges. This shapefile was created using the NCRDS Database, which contains information coming from several different sources, including
logs from coal-test drilling, interpretations of geophysical logs, and mine notations. The accuracy, precision, and distribution of these three types
of data vary greatly. Mine-map notations are probably the most accurate, followed by drilling logs of good quality. Interpretations of geophysical
logs are the least accurate source of information. The low resolution and the small scale of these logs make estimating coal elevation difficult. Because
different types of data were used in the compilation of this shapefile, the user should assume that attribute values are no better than that achievable
from the least accurate and precise source (namely, interpretations of geophysical logs).
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Visual inspection only; no quantitative tests were performed.</logic>
    <complete>The digital shapefile was derived from the NCRDS Database and is limited to extent of the Seelyville Coal Member in Indiana.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The accuracy of this Esri ArcGIS shapefile is dependent upon the accuracy of the source data of each data point, and the
accuracy with which these data were manually entered into the database.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
Vertical positional accuracy of the published paper source map is unknown.
No quantitative tests were performed.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20110815</pubdate>
            <title>
NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb: The Indiana Geological Survey National Coal Resources Data System database, a Microsoft Access database of public,
point-source coal resource data in Indiana, published as Indiana Geological Survey Report of Progress 39.
</title>
            <geoform>Digital tabular data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Microsoft Access database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19800101</begdate>
              <enddate>20110815</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Date of most recent update to the database</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The source contributed location and attribute information for 3,692 public point-source coal resource data points in Indiana.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A Microsoft Access database named "NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb" compiled as Indiana Geological Survey Report of Progress 39 was used to create this Esri
ArcGIS shapefile. 3,692 datapoints showing the elevation information of the Seelyville Coal Member were exported from the NCRDS database and using "Add X Y"
command displayed in ArcMap. The "Export" command was then used to export the datapoints as a shapefile named "SEEL_NCRDS_PT_2011.shp." Using Topo to
Raster interpolation low-resolution elevation digital raster was created. The raster was reclasiffied into 25-feet ranges and exported as an Esri
shapefile named "COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.SHP." Mapped elevation ranges from -825 to 700 feet. The shapefile was then converted to a polyline,
with attributes being preserved, and smoothed using "Smooth Line" option in ArcToolbox (ArcToolbox &gt; Cartography Tools &gt; Generalization &gt; Smooth line). Finally,
the polygon was reconstructed using Feature to Polygon option.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb</srcused>
        <procdate>2011016</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Agnieszka Drobniak</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5805</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>agdrobni@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written
by Peter N. Schweitzer (United States Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that
no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20161003</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Agnieszka Drobniak</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 N. Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 8505</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>agdrobni@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>466</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Elevation</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation interval values (in feet) for the Seelyville Coal Member</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data.  The following source citation should be
included: COAL_SEELYVILLE_ELEVATION_NCRDS_IN_2012.SHP: Elevation Ranges of the Seelyville Coal Member (Linton Formation, Pennsylvanian) in Southwestern
Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:125,000, Polygon Shapefile) by Agnieszka Drobniak, 2012.

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405 2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or
damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20110815</metd>
    <metrd>20161003</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Agnieszka Drobniak</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 N. Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 5805</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>agdrobni@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It should not to be altered or summarized.
IGS does not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>