<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</origin>
        <origin>Ned Bleuer (data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Steve Brown (data compiler, digital compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Jennifer Olejnik (data compiler, digital compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Marni Karaffa (data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Jack Haddan (data compiler, digital compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Denver Harper (digital processor)</origin>
        <pubdate>20120509</pubdate>
        <title>
GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN: Wells with Natural Gamma-Ray Logs or Physical Samples in Unconsolidated Sediments in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey,
1:100,000, Point Shapefile)
</title>
        <edition>1.0</edition>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>None</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp shows the locations of the Indiana Geological Survey's natural gamma-ray logs that were collected from 1978 to 2012.
It was updated by Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) personnel on May 9, 2012 to add new data and to include existing locations of wells with "sample
only" designations (rotary cuttings or cores) that were formerly excluded. Additionally, the dataset now contains an attribute field named
"SAMPLE_ID" for referencing physical samples in the IGS Archives. Data were updated in the attribute field named "Type" to differentiate between wells
which have only gamma-ray logs (value of "GL"), wells with gamma-ray logs and physical samples (value of "LS"), or wells where only samples (value of
"SO") were collected. This shapefile also includes information concerning coordinate locations, surface elevation, and vertical depths of gamma-logs.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
This shapefile was created to show the locations in Indiana where gamma-ray log records have been collected, as well as some locations where only samples
(rotary cuttings or cores) were collected to describe the detail of subsurface geology of Indiana. Some verification have been done on location
information in the database.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
This gamma-ray log data was collected using MLS Widco logging equipment (through 2007), and Mount Sopris logging equipment (2007 to present).
This data was taken as analog through 1993, and also as digital data after 1993. Various scales were used to record the data depending on the conditions
of each well location and the environment in which they were located. The database was started in 1990 by data entry of information into county-based
spreadsheets. The numbering system of the gamma-logs changed from a county-based number such as MA-1 (Marion County 1) to a vehicle-based number system.
At that time there were two vans and one was given odd numbers, the other even numbers, and these sequential numbers were preceded by the last two digits
of the year followed by a dash. At that time, all unnumbered logs were given a number and the ones from the county-based system retained their old number
for reference and were renumbered. Two files were created for each log: an “original” file and a “county” file. In either 1992 or 1993, the separate county
spreadsheets were merged into a single database using Paradox V3.5 software. Fields and general organization were still being refined. In 1997, the database was
converted from Paradox to Microsoft Access, which is still used as the database’s software. In 1993 work was done with the Indiana University
Electronics Department to devise a way to collect digital logs. Using laptops in the field, IGS summer field personnel collected the digital logs and
entered new data into the database. This field-entered data was added to the main database at the end of each field year. Location information was
plotted on topographic maps in 1994 and then digitized to obtain UTM coordinates for gamma-logs that had a location. In 1998 field personnel began
using GPS units in the field to record UTM coordinates for each location of gamma-ray log. Following 1998 additional fields were added and certain location
fields were verified, using the UTM coordinates, including the county, quadrangle, township, range, and section. The UTM coordinates were converted to
NAD 83 from NAD 27. Surface elevation values are derived from the U.S. Geological Survey National Elevation Dataset.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19780101</begdate>
          <enddate>20120509</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Data collection date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>Continually</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.0185</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.7543</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7689</northbc>
        <southbc>37.8943</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>aquifer</themekey>
        <themekey>borehole</themekey>
        <themekey>boring</themekey>
        <themekey>domestic water supply</themekey>
        <themekey>gamma-ray log</themekey>
        <themekey>global positioning system (GPS)</themekey>
        <themekey>ground water</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrogeology</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Division of Water (IDNR DOW)</themekey>
        <themekey>organization</themekey>
        <themekey>public water supply</themekey>
        <themekey>rural water supply</themekey>
        <themekey>tools and techniques</themekey>
        <themekey>water</themekey>
        <themekey>water supply</themekey>
        <themekey>water well</themekey>
        <themekey>well</themekey>
        <themekey>well drilling</themekey>
        <themekey>well log</themekey>
        <themekey>well logging</themekey>
        <themekey>rock sample</themekey>
        <themekey>rock cutting</themekey>
        <themekey>rock core</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaGrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Windows 7, ESRI ArcMap 10 shapefile format, approximately 6.8 Mb</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Surficial_Gamma_Ray_Logs</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The locations were initially plotted on paper-based 7.5-minute U.S. Geological Survey quadrangle maps in the fieldand then transferred to a
1:100,000-scale map in the office. The original UTM coordinates were derived from the 7.5-minute U.S. Geological Survey quadrangle maps using
the UTM tics on the edge of the paper-based map. After 1997, the location was taken with a GPS unit and compared to the 7.5-minute U.S. Geological
Survey quadrangle paper maps. The location information such as the county, quadrangle, township, range, and section was checked against the UTM
coordinates for accuracy. The point data were plotted using the UTM coordinates. The bottom depth of the log was taken from the gamma-logging
equipment as the gamma-log was being produced.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Point features present.</logic>
    <complete>
GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp contains locations forall gamma-ray logs, or physical rock material samples collected as part of the
IGS Gamma-Log database.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The accuracy of this data has not been formally tested. The locations were initially plotted on paper-based 7.5-minute
quadrangle maps in the field and then transferred to a 1:100,000-scale map in the office. The UTM coordinates were
derived from these maps. After 1997, the location was taken with a GPS unit and compared to the 7.5-minute quadrangle paper maps. The
location information such as the county, quadrangle, township, range, and section was checked against the UTM coordinates for accuracy.
The point data was plotted using the UTM coordinates. The data collected before 1999 used UTM NAD 27; data collected
after 1999 used UTM NAD 83.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Surface elevation values for all wells have been obtained from the U.S. Geological Survey National Elevation Dataset (30-meter grid).</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
            <title>UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IN_2012.XLSX, internal gamma-log database</title>
            <edition>3.0</edition>
            <geoform>Tabular digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Microsoft Excel Spreadsheet</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19780101</begdate>
              <enddate>20120509</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data collection date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IN_2012.XLSX</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IN_2012.XLSX provides locations and detailed information for gamma-logs that
were taken by the Indiana Geological Survey from 1978 to 2012.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The following is a list of steps describing the procedure to select the data included in this shapefile.
1. The original data were taken from the working database, GLDB.mdb. All the
manipulations to restrict this data set were performed in the database subset_gldb_redo.mdb using Microsoft Access 2002.
The data was first restricted to 17 columns from 83. There were 4,683 original records.

2. A delete query was performed to remove records with the designation SO (samples only). This reduced
the number of records by 141 from 4,683 to 4,542.

3. A delete query was performed to remove records with incomplete UTM records. This reduced the number
of records by 237 from 4,542 to 4,305 records.

4. A new table showing the following fields, INDEX, the unique IGS identification number, and the checklist fields that make
up the paper file inventory, ORIGINAL and COUNTY, were imported from the working database, GLDB.mdb.
This table was combined with the columns from the table in step 3, resulting in a new table containing 4,305 records. This new table
contained the new columns "original" and "county" from the working database, which were updated from a recent file inventory, and deleted
the old fields original and county from the table in the previous step.

5. The table created in the previous step 4 was used to query out records that did not contain either an original or
county paper file. This resulted in a new table containing 4,269 records by removing 36 records without paper gamma-logs.

6. A new table was imported from the working database GLDB.mdb containing the 2005 gamma-log data set with 51 records. The data from this table
was appended to the table from the previous step 5 containing 4,269 records. This combined data set resulted in 4,320 records.

7. The newest table containing 4,320 records was imported into ESRI ArcView 3.X using SQL connect. The data table was displayed using the "Add Event Theme"
command. This was converted into a point shapefile using the "Convert To Shapefile" command. Another shapefile, Indiana_statebdy_24k_igs_p.shp was also
brought into the view. Indiana_statebdy_24k_igs_p.shp was selected using the select tool. The "Select By Theme" command was
used to select the gamma-log points that intersected the theme Indiana_statebdy_24k_igs_p.shp. These highlighted points were converted into a new shapefile,
UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMA_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp.

8. Unconsolidated_gamma_logs_in.dbf file was copied, pasted and renamed in its directory to 4270_gl.dbf to import into the subset_gldb_redo.mdb database.
It was imported into the database and used in the creation of the final data set with limited fields.

9. The table 4270_gl.dbf was queried for fields, "INDEX", "UTM_83X", "UTM_83Y" and the table, LOCATION, from the working database; GLDB.mdb, was
queried for the field depth_logged. The depth_logged column was missing 66 values. These were obtained by examination of the paper records and
updated in the working database. The identical query was rerun to combine the four final database fields that were used.  This also caused
another four records to be removed owing to their status changing from having a gamma-log, GL to a SO, samples only file. Two records were also
removed becuase of the absence of paper gamma-logs. The final table created had 4,264 records.

10. The shapefile UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMA_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp's table Unconsolidated_gamma_logs_in.dbf was renamed unconsolidated_gamma_logs_in1.dbf and
was replaced with the tbl_fnl_4_col_4264 table exported as a .dbf file from Microsoft Access 2002.The exported table was renamed
unconsolidated_gamma_logs_in.dbf. This resulted in a final shapefile UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMA_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp with 4,264 records and four columns of data.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>GLDB.mdb</srcused>
        <procdate>20060314</procdate>
        <srcprod>UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMA_LOGS_IGS_IN.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Jennifer Olejnik</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Assistant Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1347</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jolejnik@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A shapefile named "UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IGS_2010" was obtained from personnel ofthe Indiana Geological Survey. The shapefile was a successor
shapefile of UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMA_LOGS_IGS_IN. The shapefile had been updated with information that was current through 2010. Using ESRI ArcMAP,
wells that were outside of Indiana were removed. In the field named "Type2," all records with a value of "SO" ("sample only")
were deleted. Numerous fields that were related to location and ownership of the well were deleted. The field named "Z_DEMFT_83" was renamed as
"SURFELEV." The field named "TYPE2" was renamed as "TYPE." The shapefile was then renamed "GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20110124</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Denver Harper</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Geologist and GIS Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1369</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>dharper@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A Microsoft Excel spreadsheed named "UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IN_2012.XLSX" was obtained from personnel of the Indiana Geological Survey on May 9, 2012.
This new data is considered a successor to the shapefile named "GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.SHP" that was updated in 2011 (which contained 4455
locations). The data now includes a total of 4738 locations along with attribute information (field named "Type") about whether the locations
have only gamma-ray logs (value of "GL"), gamma-ray logs and physical samples (value of "LS"), or samples only (value of "SO").
The spreadsheet was loaded into ESRI ArcMap software and exported to a shapefile format and saved as "GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN_2012UPDATE.SHP."
An attribute field named "ARCHIVE_ID" was then added to the shapefile using data provided in a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet named
"GammLogs_SedimentSampleBarCodes2011.XLSX." This field provides bar code IDs of sample cuttings and cores in the IGS archives.
The resultant shapefile was then exported and saved as "GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.SHP"
</procdesc>
        <srcused>UNCONSOLIDATED_GAMMAS_IN_2012.XLSX, GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN_2012UPDATE.SHP, GammLogs_SedimentSampleBarCodes2011.XLSX</srcused>
        <procdate>20120625</procdate>
        <srcprod>GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Geologist and GIS Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.8.27) software
written by Peter N. Schweitzer (USGS). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except
that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20120718</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Geologist and GIS Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>4738</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indiana County name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INDEX</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique index number given to each gamma-log</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>
The values for the index are listed as year-number. For example, an index number of 06-1000
indicates that the gamma-ray-log was collected in 2006, while a number of 98-1000 indicates
that the log was collected in 1998.These numbers were used in numeric order, the values
in this shapefile represent the gamma-logs that exist in paper format with a location.
</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>UTM_83X</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The Universal Transverse Mercator, Zone 16 Easting, North American Datum 1983</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>415342</rdommin>
            <rdommax>686708</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>UTM_83Y</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The Universal Transverse Mercator, Zone 16 Northing, North American Datum 1983</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>4196210</rdommin>
            <rdommax>4633033</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Depth_logg</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The depth to which the gamma-log reaches</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1061</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Feet</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SurfElev</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Elevation of the ground surface where the well was located. A value of "0" indicates
that no data are available.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>353</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1228</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Feet</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The type of data that are available from the well</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>LS</edomv>
            <edomvd>Gamma-ray log and sample (rotary cuttings or core)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>GL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Gamma-ray log only</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SO</edomv>
            <edomvd>Sample only (rotary cuttings or core)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PDF_FILES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates whether the Gamma-ray logs have been scanned and made available as an Adobe PDF file (Yes/No)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PDF_URL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Web site URL Address for PDF scans of Gamma-ray log files</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SAMPLES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates whether the physical samples associated with a well have been archived and assigned "Sample identification number(s)" in the IGS Archives (Yes/No)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SAMPLE_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Sample identification number(s) that are used to reference the physical samples in the IGS Archive</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>

CREDIT

It is required that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source citation must be included:
GAMMA_RAY_LOGS_IGS_IN: Wells with Natural Gamma-Ray Logs or Physical Samples in Unconsolidated Sediments in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey,
1:100,000, Point Shapefile), compiled by Ned Bleuer (data compiler), Steve Brown (data compiler, digital compiler), Jennifer Olejnik (data compiler,
digital compiler), Marni Karaffa (data compiler) Jack Haddan, (data compiler, digital compiler), 2012.

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect
in materials and workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication
Sales, Indiana Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405 2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILIT

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability resulting
from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product users indirect,
incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged data or other
commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The maximum aggregate
liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20110124</metd>
    <metrd>20120718</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Marni Karaffa</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Glacial Research Geologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 1366</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>karaffam@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC-CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It is not to be altered or summarized. IGS
does not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone other than the IGS, this metadata file and the data set
it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>