<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>20150108</pubdate>
        <title>PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP: Petroleum Reservoir Fields (Oil and Gas) in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:63,360, Polygon Shapefile)</title>
        <edition>2015qtr1</edition>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This dataset was created by comparing digital lines from IGS Miscellaneous Map 58 (MM58) with one quarter mile buffers of
producitve petroleum wells. New petroleum field outlines were then manually digitized on screen using the shape information from MM58 and the
buffer extents. In some cases, the IGS Petroleum Exploration Map (PEM) series was consulted to verify spatial and attribute data. Petroleum
well information was queried from the Indiana Geological Survey Petroleum Well Database, which is a component of the IGS Petroleum Database
Management System (PDMS).

NOTE: As of January 8, 2015, the Indiana Geological Survey began scheduling regular quarterly updates for this dataset. Therefore, this information
is only as current as the publication date of this data set. If more current data are needed, please use the subscription-based services of the
PDMS Web site: ( http://igs.indiana.edu/PDMS/ ).
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/layerGallery.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP is an Esri polygon shapefile that depicts the locations and extents of all petroleum reservoir fields in Indiana, as of
January 8, 2015. PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP shows boundaries of petroleum reservoir fields that enclose petroleum wells that are classified as producing
from a single field, but does not necessarily indicate the maximum extent of the producing reservoir field.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP was created to provide the Indiana Geological Survey and the public with a functional digital representation of petroleum
reservoir fields in Indiana for use in geographic information systems.
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20150108</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1571</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.7080</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7664</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7688</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>economy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS)</themekey>
        <themekey>petroleum reservoir</themekey>
        <themekey>petroleum</themekey>
        <themekey>oil</themekey>
        <themekey>gas</themekey>
        <themekey>gas storage</themekey>
        <themekey>petroleum field</themekey>
        <themekey>economic geology</themekey>
        <themekey>energy resources</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS point shapefile (version 10.2), Windows 7, 1.0 MB</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Petroleum_Fields</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The attributes associated with the item FIELD_NAME were transcribed from labels shown on the Indiana Geological Survey's existing Petroleum Exploration Maps.
Therefore, attribute accuracy of this coverage is dependent on the accuracy of the original maps. The attribute accuracy was tested by manual comparison of
the source with hard copy plots and (or) symbolized display of the digital petroleum fields data on screen. Despite the use of careful procedures and proofing
of the entered data, human error always remains a possibility.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Polygon topology is present</logic>
    <complete>This dataset is assumed to be complete up to the publication date, but is continually being updated by IGS personnel.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
Petroleum reservoir field boundaries are derived from the locations of specific wells in the IGS Petroleum Well Database, a component of the Petroluem Database
Management System (PDMS). Therefore, the horizontal positional accuracy of this dataset is dependent on the locational accuracy of those well locations. The petroleum
well locations have varying levels of accuracy. Location coordinates of wells contained within the Indiana Geological Survey’s Petroleum Database Management System
are believed to be reasonably accurate when portrayed on a scale of 1 inch to 1 mile (1:63,360).  Although the coordinates for a great many locations in the database
have been very accurately determined, past practices and inherent limitations on the accuracy with which a well was spotted on a 1:24,000-scale USGS topographic map have
resulted in well coordinates that locate wells a small distance from their actual locations. Depending on circumstances, this distance could be as great as 100 feet,
or rarely, somewhat more. In general, such locations are sufficiently accurate for most petroleum exploration and field mapping purposes. Additionally, it is important
to note that new and revised data continually are being entered into the Petroleum Well Database and, despite the use of careful procedures and proofing of the
entered data, human error always remains a possibility.  Every effort is made to correct errors and discrepancies whenever they are identified, but it is the responsibility
of the user to verify any information to the extent it is deemed important.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the digital production of this dataset.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1998</pubdate>
            <title>IGS Miscellaneous Map 58, Map Showing Oil, Gas, and Gas Storage Fields in Indiana (MM58)</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>This is statewide map which delineates the petroleum fields in Indiana.</othercit>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>550000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1998</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MM58</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
This source provided the basis for the shape of field outlines digitized to create this dataset. Because MM58 was drawn at 1:550,000 on a now-obsolete
basemap, the field outlines had to be re-digitized. Lines from MM58 provided a guide for that digitization, but the lines were not simply copied.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20150108</pubdate>
            <title>Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS)</title>
            <geoform>Microsoft Access Database</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
Only a select set of wells from the PDMS were used to generate buffers to use as guides for digitizing petroleum field outlines. All productive
wells were used including those with the following symbol classifications: oil, gas, oil and gas, shut-in gas, gas storage, gas storage formerly oil, gas storage
formerly gas, water injection, water injection formerly oil, water injection formerly gas, water injection formerly oil and gas, salt water disposal formerly oil,
salt water disposal formerly gas, nonpotable water supply formerly oil, and nonpotable water supply formerly gas. Also included are the modifying statuses; abandoned,
completion type uncertain, and (or) location uncertain.

Location coordinates of wells contained within the Indiana Geological Survey’s Petroleum Database Management System and their corresponding locations as shown on maps
are believed to be reasonably accurate when portrayed on a scale of 1 inch to 1 mile (1:63,360). Although the coordinates for a great many locations in the database
have been very accurately determined, past practices and inherent limitations on the accuracy with which a well was spotted on a 1:24,000-scale USGS topographic map
have resulted in well coordinates that locate wells a small distance from their actual locations.  Depending on circumstances, this distance could be as great as 100
feet, or rarely, somewhat more. In general, such locations are sufficiently accurate for most petroleum exploration and field mapping purposes. Additionally, it is
important to note that new and revised data continually are being entered into the Petroleum Database Management System and, despite the use of careful procedures
and proofing of the entered data, human error always remains a possibility. Every effort is made to correct errors and discrepancies whenever they are identified,
but it is the responsibility of the user to verify any information to the extent it is deemed important.
</othercit>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>63,360</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20150108</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>PDMS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
This source provided the location and attribute information for petroleum wells which were buffered to create layers showing the approximate extent
of petroleum reservoir field boundaries (one quarter mile radius around producing wells).
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <title>Petroleum Exploration Map (PEM) series</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
The Petroleum Exploration Map (PEM) series published by the Indiana Geological Survey is a set of 92 county maps that depict locations of
known petroleum wells, petroleum fields, and gas storage projects. The maps are printed at 1:63,360-scale and utilize the old "General Highway and Transportation" base,
which is known to contain a significant degree of horizontal spatial error.
</othercit>
            <onlink>None</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>63,360</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Stable-base material</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2000</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>PEM</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
This source is the original basis for lines originally digitized to produce IGS MM58. For PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP, the PEMs were used to verify
spatial and attribute field information. Lines were not digitized from these maps to create PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This process step outlines the procedures used to update the petroleum reservoir field boundaries. The Petroleum Database Management System
is continually being updated. As petroleum wells are added and well locations are updated, PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP often needs to be revised. This is carried
out by IGS personnel who edit PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP when necessary. PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP reservoir field boundaries are updated by using the
most current petroleum well record data to buffer boundaries around petroleum wells that are classified as producing from a specific reservoir field, as contained
in the IGS Petroleum Well Database, a component of the Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS).
</procdesc>
        <srcused>PDMS well records from the IGS Petroleum Well Database</srcused>
        <procdate>20150108</procdate>
        <srcprod>PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Charles W. Zuppann</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Petroleum Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5412</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>czuppann@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United States
Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20150130</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>_Method: Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>627</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.DBF</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIELD_NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of petroleum field</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA_METER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification number of the well (IGS, internal)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>305087.37683</rdommin>
            <rdommax>12034836100.0</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA_ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification number of the well (IGS, internal)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>75.388424</rdommin>
            <rdommax>2973860.583224</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>F_TYPE_NEW</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of petroleum reservoir field</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>G</edomv>
            <edomvd>petroleum field consisting of Gas production</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>O</edomv>
            <edomvd>petroleum field consisting of Oil production</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>OG</edomv>
            <edomvd>petroleum field consisting of Oil and Gas production</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IGS_FIELD_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification number for the petroleum reservoir field (Indiana Geological Survey, internal)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of the petroleum field polygon (square meters)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software computed</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>305087.37683</rdommin>
            <rdommax>12034836100.0</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of the perimeter of the polygon boundary (meters)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software computed</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>2275.879339</rdommin>
            <rdommax>963177.603807</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday-Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source citation should be included:
[PETROLEUM_FIELDS_IGS_IN.SHP: Petroleum Reservoir Fields (Oil and Gas) in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:63,360, Polygon Shapefile), 20150108].

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and workmanship
for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana Geological Survey, 611 North
Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied, including, but not
limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability resulting from the use of this product is assumed
by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey
is not responsible for claims by a third party. The  maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20150108</metd>
    <metrd>20150130</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It should not to be altered or summarized.
IGS does not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>