<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</origin>
        <origin>Jill Flachskam (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Licia Weber (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Becky Meyer (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Nathan Eaton (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Paul Irwin (Data compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20171115</pubdate>
        <title>COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mines in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation, Polygon Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Jasonville, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
NOTE: An Esri file geodatabase named "CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB" (containing the polygon feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED") was originally provided to
personnel of the Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS) personnel on November 15, 2017, by personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation. It has been converted to an Esri point shapefile and has been named "COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP" to conform to naming
conventions of the IGS. Also, portions of this metadata have adapted content that was originally authored by IDNR personnel.

This shapefile contains information that is related to two additional GIS datasets produced by the Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, Division of Reclamation: [1) Coal_Mine_Surface_DNR_IN.SHP: Surface Coal Mines in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, Division of Reclamation, Polygon Shapefile)] and 2) [Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mine Entrances in
Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation, Point Shapefile)].
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/layerGallery.html</onlink>
        <onlink>http://www.in.gov/dnr/reclamation/9310.htm</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP provides the locations of all documented underground coal mines that have operated in the coal region of Indiana since the mid-1880s,
up to December 31, 2016. COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP is attributed with mine number (IDNR), map number (IDNR), start dates, and end dates.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "SURFACE_AFFECTED":

"Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN is a polygon-based ESRI ArcGIS shapefile that shows the location and extent of underground coal mines
in the coal region of west-central and southwestern Indiana. Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN includes mine locations from documented
underground mines that operated in Indiana since the late 1800s. Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN is attributed to allow the mine polygons
to be differentiated based on mine number, source information, and dates of mining."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
This data provides access to an Esri polygon shapefile containing the most current information for underground coal mines in Indiana, as provided by
personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED":

"Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN is a composite of all underground mine locations in Indiana. It was compiled by the Indiana Geological
Survey (IGS) as part of a contract deliverable for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation. Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN incorporates underground mine locations compiled by the IGS in the early 1980s
with hundreds of historic underground mine locations digitized in 1998-1999 and contemporary mine outlines digitized from maps
collected from coal companies or the Indiana Bureau of Mines. Original source information for Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN includes
company mine maps, field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and Indiana State Mine Inspector Reports. All mine data
included in Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN are organized in a GIS using ESRI ArcGIS software of the Environmental Systems Research Institute
(ESRI) on the Windows platform. Scale of source data ranges from 1:4,800 to 1:100,000. Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN includes attributes
which allow the mine polygons to be differentiated based on mine type, mine number, source information, and dates of mining."
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>18351231</begdate>
          <enddate>20161231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Annual</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.0651</westbc>
        <eastbc>-86.5858</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.0278</northbc>
        <southbc>37.8390</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>economy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Division of Reclamation (DOR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>coal mine</themekey>
        <themekey>underground mine</themekey>
        <themekey>coal</themekey>
        <themekey>subsidence</themekey>
        <themekey>reclamation</themekey>
        <themekey>mining</themekey>
        <themekey>energy resources</themekey>
        <themekey>economic geology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Illinois Basin</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Esri ArcGIS version 10.4 shapefile format, approximately 5.9 Mb</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Coal_Mines_Underground</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
This data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be accurate.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED":

"The attribute values were checked to ensure that the values were within the range that should be expected based upon the values of
the input data that were used to create the shapefile. Two tests for attribute consistency were performed using the QueryBuilder Tool
in Esri ArcView: (1) Completeness of values was verified. No values were left blank. (2) Validity of values was verified. All features
were attributed with values in the appropriate range and format."
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Esri ArcInfo polygon topology is present</logic>
    <complete>
This data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be complete.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED":

"Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN includes all documented underground mines in Indiana. Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN was compiled
by the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) as part of a contract deliverable for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana
Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.

"All underground coal mines included in this shapefile were compiled as part of the Indiana Coal Mine Information System (CMIS)
project at the Indiana Geological Survey. The CMIS is an integrated geographic information system (GIS) and database management
system (DBMS) created to maintain spatial and tabular data related to coal mines in the Indiana portion of the Illinois Basin.
The CMIS includes spatial mine data compiled from all known sources including: company mine maps (from the Indiana Bureau of
Mines, county courthouses, coal companies), field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and Indiana State Mine
Inspector Reports. In compiling data for the CMIS, every effort was made to ensure data accuracy and completeness. However, it
is known that undocumented underground mining has occurred in the study area. Also, because of inconsistency in source map quality
and completeness, the actual extent of underground mining may not coincide with the boundaries portrayed in this shapefile."
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
This preliminary data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be horizontally accurate, per IDNR standards.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED":

"Mine outlines included in this shapefile were compiled from several sources with varying map scales. Thus, the horizontal positional accuracy
of individual polygons may vary. If highly detailed mine location and layout information is needed, contact the Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, Divison of  Reclamation for additional information. Because of inconsistency in source map quality and completeness, the actual
extent of underground mining may not coincide with the boundaries portrayed in this shapefile."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the creation of these data. No quantitative tests were performed.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</origin>
            <pubdate>20171115</pubdate>
            <title>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB - polygon feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED" - Underground Coal Mines in Indiana (as of December 31, 2016)</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Jasonville, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Vector digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1835</begdate>
              <enddate>20161231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB (polygon feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED")</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Underground coal mine locations in Indiana, as of December 31, 2016.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1987</pubdate>
            <title>1:24,000-scale Underground Coal Mine Maps</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Mylar</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>18351231</begdate>
              <enddate>19871231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>1987</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Underground Mine Quadrangle Maps</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
Used to create the first complete compilation of underground mine locations in Indiana.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Mine outlines from a variety of sources including company mine maps, field maps and notes of IGS Geologists, IGS publications,
and Indiana State Mine Inspector Reports were rescaled and hand-plotted on 1:24,000-scale quadrangle maps. This data set,
comprised of nearly 100 quadrangle maps, was compiled by IGS personnel in the mid-1980s to create the first complete compilation
of underground mine locations in Indiana.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>1985-1988</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Licia Weber</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1364</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>weber@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Polygons from the Indiana Geological Survey 1:24,000-scale Underground Coal Mine Maps
were digitized by Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) personnel in the late 1980s to
create the first coal mine GIS for the IGS and the Indiana Division of Reclamation.
Outlines were digitized using ESRI PC ArcInfo and geo-referenced using 8 tics
from 1:24,000-scale quadrangle maps.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>1988-1991</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Paul Irwin</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-5812</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>irwinp@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Data from the early coal mine GIS were converted to a new GIS format and updated
with new mine data. Using ESRI ArcInfo version 7.2.1, polygons were extracted
from the old GIS coverages and integrated into a new REGION-based GIS format.
Each polygon was attributed with source information, dates of mining, and coal seam data.
The resulting reformatted mine coverages (over 4,000 including surface and
underground coal mines) constitute the primary mine GIS data for the
Indiana Coal Mine Information System (CMIS), an integrated geographic information
system and database management system. In addition to the reformatting, over 1,000 mine
coverages were added to the GIS, including approximately 225 new surface mines,
20 new underground mines, and nearly 1,200 historic underground mine entrance locations.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>1997-1999</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geotechnical Systems Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
CMIS mine data were updated with information collected for the Directory of Coal
Mines and Producers in Indiana - 2000. The update included approximately 40
surface mine polygons and 5 underground mine polygons. Most data were
received in digital format from mining companies and converted to suitable
format by IGS personnel.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20000501</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geotechnical Systems Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Mine coverages from the Indiana Coal Mine Information System were appended
using an AML running in ESRI ArcInfo version 7.2.1. The
resulting coverage included all mines in the Indiana coal region.
This coverage was then projected to UTM zone 16 Nad 83 using the ESRI ArcView
Projector extension. COAL_UND was created in ESRI ArcView by using the ESRI ArcView
QueryBuilder to select only underground mines and then by using the
Convert-to-Shapefile command to create a new shapefile from the selected data.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20000729</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geotechnical Systems Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>neaton@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
ArcInfo underground mine coverages were converted to an ESRI
personal geodatabase feature dataset. COAL_UND was renamed COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_IN.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>2002</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Becky Meyer</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-6641</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>reameyer@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Active underground mine outlines were digitized from maps collected annually
from the Indiana Bureau of Mines.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>2002 to 2013</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Becky Meyer</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-6641</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>reameyer@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_IN was obtained from the Indiana Geological Survey
as part of a contract deliverable for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of
the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.
COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_IN was renamed to Coal_Mine_Underground_DNR_IN
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20151028</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jill Flachskam</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Inventory Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>14619 West State Road 48</address>
              <city>Jasonville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47438</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-665-2207</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-665-5041</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jflachskam@dnr.in.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1630 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
An Esri file geodatabase named "CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB" (containing the polygon feature class named "UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED") was originally provided to
personnel of the Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS) personnel on November 15, 2017, by personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation. The feature class UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED was then converted to an Esri polygon shapefile and was renamed
"COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP" to conform to naming conventions of the IGS. Also, portions of this metadata have adapted content that was originally
authored by IDNR personnel.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB, UNDERGROUND_AFFECTED (polygon feature class)</srcused>
        <procdate>20171115</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) an MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter Schweitzer
(U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20171212</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>2430</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Mine_Number</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mine ID Number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>800001</rdommin>
            <rdommax>810979</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Source_Confidence</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Describes the source of the data as either Primary or Secondary</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Primary</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mapped from company mine map</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Secondary</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Mapped from source other than a company mine map, including IGS publications,
field notes and maps of IGS geologists, and Reports of the State Inspector of Mines
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Year_start</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Approximate date that mine opened ('1001' indicates an uncertain start date)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1001 (1835)</rdommin>
            <rdommax>2015</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Year_end</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Approximate date that mine closed ('9009' indicates an uncertain end date)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1845</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9009 (2015)</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_Number</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>ID number for source data</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>
999999 Straw, W.T., Gray, H. and Powell, R.L., 1977, Environmental geology of the Evansville area southwestern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 12.
999997 Ashley, G.H., 1898, The coal deposits of Indiana, in Blatchley, W.S., 1898, Twenty-third annual report of geology and natural resources: Indiana Department of Geology and Natural Resources, Indianapolis.
999995 Collett, J., 1883, Thirteenth annual report of geology and natural resources: Indiana Department of Geology and Natural Resources, Indianapolis.
999990 Wier, C.E. and Stanley, J.T., 1953, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Pike County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 3.
999985 Cox, E.T., 1874, Fifth annual report of the Geological Survey of Indiana: Sentinel Company, Indianapolis.
999984 Cox, E.T., 1872, Third and fourth annual reports of the Geological Survey of Indiana: R.J. Bright, State Printer, Indianapolis.
999971 State Mine Inspector, 1890-1947, Annual report of the State Inspector of Mines: Indiana Department of Geology and Natural Resources Annual Reports.
999968 Survey Geologists, Approximately 1945-1965, Geologists' field notebooks listing locations and descriptions of coal mines: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
999967 Aerial Photograph, 1940, Photographs interpreted by IGS geologists to determine the extent of areas affected by surface coal mining: Indiana Geological Survey Petroleum Files.
999966 Hasenmueller, W.A., 1985, Directory of coal producers in Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Directory.
999961 Weir, C.E. and Powell, R.L., 1967, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Knox County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 12.
999960 Hutchison, H.C., 1971, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Daviess County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 15.
999959 Hutchison, H.C., Field work maps (quadrangles) showing geology and features related to coal and mining: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
999957 Weber, Licia, 1986-1989, Maps showing features related to subsidence in southwest Indiana (7.5-minute) quadrangles: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
999950 Hutchison, H.C., 1967, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Martin County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 11.
999949 Owen, David, 1859, Report of a geological reconnaissance of Indiana: H.H. Dodd and Co., Indianapolis.
999948 Hutchison, H.C. and Hasenmueller, W.A., 1988, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Greene County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 17.
999946 Kottlowski, Frank, 1960, Geology and coal deposits of the Switz City quadrangle, Greene County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 41.
999940 Kottlowski, Frank, 1959, Geology and coal deposits of the Coal City quadrangle, Greene, Clay, and Owen Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 28.
999938 Weir, C.E., 1951, Geology and coal deposits of the Linton quadrangle, Greene and Sullivan Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 9. 999937 Weir, C.E., 1953, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Sullivan County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 2.
999936 Weir, C.E., 1954, Geology and coal deposits of the Hymera quadrangle, Sullivan County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 16.
999935 Kottlowski, 1954, Geology and coal deposits of the Dugger quadrangle, Sullivan county, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 11.
999933 Hutchison, H.C., 1959, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Spencer County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 8.
999930 Hutchison, H.C., 1956, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Clay County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 6.
999929 Weir, C.E., 1950, Geology and coal deposits of the Jasonville quadrangle, Clay, Greene, and Sullivan Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 1.
999928 Hutchison, H.C., 1960, Geology and coal deposits of the Brazil quadrangles, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Bulletin 16.
999925 Hutchison, H.C., 1964, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Dubois County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 10. 999923 Hutchison, H.C., 1971, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Perry County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 14.
999920 Weir, C.E., 1952, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Vigo County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 1.
999919 Friedman, S.A., 1989, Geology and coal deposits of the Clinton area, west-central Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 42.
999916 Hutchinson, H.C., 1958, Geology and coal deposits of the Seelyville quadrangle, Vigo County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 2.
999915 Friedman, S.A., 1961, Geology and coal deposits of the Terre Haute and Dennison quadrangles, Vigo County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 44.
999913 Friedman, S.A., 1961, Work map showing extent, distribution, and structure of coal VII, and mine shafts and extent of mining, and coal test boreholes with data (New Goshen quadrangle): Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
999908 Powell, R.L., 1968, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Parke County and southern Vermillion County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 13.
999907 Hutchison, H.C., 1961, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Fountain, Warren and Vermillion Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 3.
999901 Hunt, Raymond S., 1925, The geology and natural resources of an area in the vicinity of Bloomington, Indiana: Indiana University, Bloomington, Masters Thesis.
610596-305545 Original or reproduced company mine map, Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
2853-738 Coal data card, Indiana Geological Survey Coal Records.
</edomv>
            <edomvd>Included in Domain Values</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>County_Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of the county in which the site is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Acres</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of the mine polygon (in Acres)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>igsinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological and Water Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source citation should
be included: [COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mines in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation, Polygon
Shapefile), 20171115].

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or
damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party.
The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20151028</metd>
    <metrd>20171212</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGWS. It is not to be altered or summarized. IGS does
not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone other than the IGWS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>