<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Agnieszka Drobniak</origin>
        <pubdate>20110815</pubdate>
        <title>
COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011: Thickness Ranges of the Danville Coal Member (Dugger Formation,
Pennsylvanian) in Southwestern Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:125,000, Polygon Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This shapefile was compiled based on data from the National Coal Resource Data System Database (NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb)
(Indiana Geological Survey, Access Database).
Mastalerz, M., and Drobniak, A., 2011, The Indiana Geological Survey Coal Stratigraphic Database:
Indiana Geological Survey Report of Progress 39.
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
In the past a series of reports on coal resources of selected counties in Indiana was published
as part of the Special Report series of the Indiana Geological Survey. These reports included maps
showing thickness of the Danville Coal Member (Dugger Formation, Pennsylvanian). The thickness
maps were based on coal-test records, mine-map notations, and interpretations of geophysical logs that
are included in the files of the Indiana Geological Survey. Different thickness ranges were
used in the various counties and for different purposes.
Since 1980, staff members of the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) have also collected and entered coal
resource information into the NCRDS database as a cooperative project with the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS).
The purpose of NCRDS database is to provide a means of rapid retrieval of point-source coal resource information,
including coal location, thickness, depth, and other parameters. Based on all available data as of October 2010, a
new map of Danville Coal Member thickness was created. It is the most current thickness map
of the Danville Coal Member. Because additional data on coal thicknesses are obtained by the Indiana Geological
Survey on an annual basis, interested users may wish to contact the Indiana Geological Survey for information on
these more up-to-date sources.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011 was created to provide a multicounty digital shapefile, suitable for use in a GIS, from
Indiana Geological Survey National Coal Resource Data System Database (NCRDS) a Microsoft Access database
of public point-source coal-resource data in Indiana.
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19830101</begdate>
          <enddate>20110815</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1286</westbc>
        <eastbc>-87.0871</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.9239</northbc>
        <southbc>38.7705</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>energy</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>National Coal Resources Data System (NCRDS)</themekey>
        <themekey>coal</themekey>
        <themekey>thickness</themekey>
        <themekey>coal thickness</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Danville Coal Member</themekey>
        <themekey>Dugger Formation</themekey>
        <themekey>Carbondale Group</themekey>
        <themekey>Pennsylvanian</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS version 10.0 polygon shapefile, Microsoft Windows 7.0, file size 3.26 Mb</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Coal_Danville_Thickness</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011 contains internal attributes with designations that refer to minimum and maximum values (in feet)
of various thickness ranges. This shapefile was created using the NCRDS database, which contains information coming from several
different sources including logs from coal-test drilling, interpretations of geophysical logs, and mine notations.
The accuracy, precision, and distribution of these three types of data vary greatly. Mine-map notations
are probably the most accurate, followed by drilling logs of good quality. Interpretations of geophysical
logs are the least accurate source of information. The low resolution and the small scale of these logs make estimating coal
thickness difficult. Because different types of data were used in the compilation of this shapefile,
the user should assume that attribute values are no better than that achievable from the least accurate and precise source (namely
interpretations of geophysical logs).
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Visual inspection only; no quantitative tests were performed.</logic>
    <complete>The digital shapefile was derived from the NCRDS database and is limited to extent of the Danville Coal Member in Indiana.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The accuracy of this ESRI ArcGIS shapefile is dependent upon the accuracy of the source data of each data point, and the
accuracy with which these data were manually entered into the database.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Vertical accuracy was not a factor in a digital production of this data set.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20110815</pubdate>
            <title>
NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb: The Indiana Geological Survey National Coal Resources Data System
database, a Microsoft Access database of public point-source coal resource data in
Indiana, published as Indiana Geological Survey Report of Progress 39.
</title>
            <geoform>Digital tabular data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Microsoft Access database</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>19800101</begdate>
              <enddate>20110815</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Date of most recent update to the database</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
The source contributed location and attribute information for 3,588 public point-source
coal resource data points in Indiana.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
A Microsoft Access database named "NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb," compiled as Indiana Geological Survey
Report of Progress 39, was used to create this ESRI ArcGIS shapefile. 3,588 datapoints showing the thickness
information of the Danville Coal Member were exported from the NCRDS database and using "Add X Y"
command displayed in ArcMap. The "Export" command was then used to export the datapoints as a shapefile
named "DAN_NCRDS_PT_2011.shp." Using Topo to Raster interpolation low-resolution thickness digital raster
was created. The raster was reclasiffied into 1-foot ranges and exported as a COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011
shapefile. The shapefile was then smoothed using "smooth polygon" option in ArcToolbox.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NCRDS_Indiana2011.mdb</srcused>
        <procdate>2011016</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Agnieszka Drobniak</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 N. Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5805</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>agdrobni@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and  MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written
by Peter N. Schweitzer (United States Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that
no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20110929</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 N. Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>dintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>770</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Thickness</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Thickness interval values (in feet) for the Danville Coal Member</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any
products generated from this data.  The following source citation should be
included: COAL_DANVILLE_THICKNESS_NCRDS_IN_2011: Thickness Ranges of the Danville Coal Member
(Dugger Formation, Pennsylvanian) in Southwestern Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:125,000, Polygon
Shapefile) by Agnieszka Drobniak, 2011.

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405 2208,
and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20110815</metd>
    <metrd>20111121</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Agnieszka Drobniak</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 N. Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 5805</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>agdrobni@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>