<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Joseph F. Whaley (author)</origin>
        <origin>Robert F. Blakely (author)</origin>
        <origin>Karen K. Like (database compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Christina L. James (digital compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20021007</pubdate>
        <title>
SEISMIC_DATA_IN: Seismic Refraction Data for Indiana
(Indiana Geological Survey, Point Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
SEISMIC_DATA_IN is a point shapefile created from a shapefile
named SEISMIC_DATA, which was derived from a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet named
SEISMIC_DECODED. The spreadsheet contains seismic shot information (13,949
points) collected by the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) across Indiana.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
The Refraction Seismic Data Table of the Indiana Geological Survey is a collection
of data assembled over a number of years between 1950 and 1983. The primary purpose
was to determine the depth to bedrock at locations throughout the state (indicated
by asterisks in the fields named "Vela," "Velb," "Velc," "Veld," "Deptha," "Depthb,"
"Depthc," "Eleva," "Elevb," and "Elevc"). A secondary purpose
was to infer the lithology of the bedrock, indicated by the seismic
velocity of the layer. Many different goals were served, ranging from the
delineation of subterranean river valleys to the thickness of radioactive
shale deposits. Analog data were recorded photographically and analyzed by
picking first-energy arrivals. The energy source was dynamite.  Apparent velocities
and cross-over distances were determined graphically from travel-time plots by
estimation of values with two or three significant figures.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Joseph F. Whaley and other IGS employees shot seismic refraction profiles using
dynamite and a spread of twelve geophones. The analog wiggly-trace records were
recorded photographically. Whaley and others picked arrival times and plotted
these on graph paper to graphically determine slopes of straight-line fits
(reciprocal apparent velocities of direct arrivals and critically refracted
first-arrival events). Mr. Whaley, who
also assigned stratigraphic names using codes derived by Robert F.
Blakely, analyzed the recorded refractions for velocity, depth, and
lithology. Many of the shots are reverse shots and defined with the
A and B extension on the seismic station identification number.
The information was keypunched by staff and transferred to
magnetic tape around 1980. New records were periodically added to the
magnetic tape. Due to possible degradation of the tape over time, it
is known that the tape was copied to another tape at least once. The
tape was then read and saved as a text file in 2000. The codes,
created by Robert Blakely, were manually replaced with the explanations
defined on the four-page "Explanation of Seismic Data on Computer
Printout Sheets" using the Excel search and replace function.
Christina James then visually checked the information against the
original text file and explanation sheet. There were entries in
various fields that did not follow the explanation sheet. Karen Like
investigated these entries against the original field sheets and
corrected the information. (See the second process step, descriptions
3 and 4.)  Additional information such as charge, spread, shot hole,
topography, and supplementary location information are recorded on the
field sheets that were not coded onto the magnetic tape.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1950</begdate>
          <enddate>1983</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>1983</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.0622</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.7654</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7722</northbc>
        <southbc>37.8019</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey</themekey>
        <themekey>IGS</themekey>
        <themekey>geophysical data</themekey>
        <themekey>seismic shot</themekey>
        <themekey>seismic data</themekey>
        <themekey>seismic refraction</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Windows 2000; ESRI ArcView shapefile version 3.2, approximately 3.0 Mb</native>
    <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
    <useconst>Geology--Seismic_Data</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The information in the point shapefile was derived
from the Microsoft Excel spreadsheet that came from the reading of the second edition
of the magnetic tape. A few changes were made when an entry did not fit in the range
of information for that field. The original paper field record was checked if it could be located.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
Each field was queried for unique values identifying gross errors that were then
investigated. Not all original paper field records could be found and therefore
not all errors could be checked and/or corrected.
</logic>
    <complete>
All coded data were not checked against the original field sheets. Only gross errors
were investigated when the original paper records could be found.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
Each original seismic shot
location was measured using a tape from the nearest benchmark.
Punch cards have the limitation of 80 characters. All the seismic
shot data were coded so that it could be stored on computer punch cards and
transferred to magnetic tape.  A coding system was derived to
identify the location of the seismic shot within a section.  Seismic
shots within a section are located by a code using four numbers.  The
first number represents the 1/4 section within which the seismic shot
was taken.  The second number represents the 1/4 of 1/4 section
location.  The third number the 1/4 of 1/4 of 1/4 section location, and
the fourth number the nearest corner location of the 1/4 of 1/4 of 1/4
section.  The quarters were numbered clockwise, with the northeastern
quarter being "1," the southeastern being "2," the southwestern "3,"
and the northwestern "4."  The fourth number applies to the quarter
corner.  See the "Explanation of Seismic Data on Computer
Printout Sheets" for a graphical representation of this description.
Additional location information can be found on the original field
paper records.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
A barometer was used to ascertain the ground elevation in the field.
Joseph F. Whaley of the Indiana Geological Survey calculated the elevations
of velocity interfaces. For more information see the original seismic shot
records stored in the Environmental Section map room of the Indiana Geological Survey.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>2002</pubdate>
            <title>Untitled geophysical data</title>
            <geoform>Spreadsheet</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Unpublished geophysical data of the IGS</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Magnetic tape</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1950</begdate>
              <enddate>1983</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data collection date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>None</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Unpublished geophysical data of the IGS</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
1) The text file created from reading the magnetic tape was copied from
the IGS network drive and imported into Microsoft Excel using the
comma-delimited option.

2) William Herring, Indiana Department of Natural Resources, provided a
copy of the original code sheet titled "Explanation of Seismic Data
on Computer Printout Sheets."

3) Using the Excel search and replace function, the codes were replaced
with the defined explanation.

4) A few fields were not defined on the explanation sheets and the
definitions were obtained verbally through a meeting in 2002 with Robert
Blakely.

5) Additional columns were added to process the locations into Universal
Transverse Mercator (UTM) North American Datum (NAD) 1983 zone 16.
The public land survey descriptions were formatted for input into the
software program GeoGraphix to calculate the UTM NAD 27 zone 16
information.  The coordinates were then projected through decimal
degrees into UTM NAD 83 zone 16 using ESRI ArcTools 8.1.  Linking
through the StationID, the three new location formats decimal
degrees, UTM NAD 27 zone 16, and UTM NAD 83 zone 16, were added to the
Excel spreadsheet.
Source_Used_Citiation_Abbreviation: seisfil_original.txt
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20020105</procdate>
        <srcprod>seismic_finished.xls</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Christina L. James</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geological Technician</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 2504</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cjames@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
1) The explanations that were used to replace the codes were checked
against the original code sheet. Modifications were made to match the
code sheet exactly.  Fields 7, 9, and 10 were corrected for
capitalization, spacing, spelling, and complete entry, (for example, "N" in "No
good" was capitalized, "T road" changed to "T-road," "Silurian" was spelled
"Silurain," changed "New Albany" to "New Albany, Antrim, Elsworth or
Sunbury shales.")

2) Each field was filtered for unique values and gross errors checked
against the original paper field records.

MY073 section changed from 43 to 3.

MY074 section changed from 44 to 10.

All zeros in the third and (or) fourth quarter columns were deleted.
Extra quotation marks were deleted.

OU073B Landmark was deleted.

Blank defined with a "-" in this field.

PB217A and PD137A Landmark changed to Farm drive.

OW016A thru OW018B original Bedrock Lithology SL (not defined).

OI034A Stratigraphy is 3800 (Borden shales and siltstones).

NM332A and NQ238 is 4000 (Devonian undifferentiated).

NM173 is 4220 (New Albany, Antrim, Elsworth, or Sunbury shales).

3880, 4200, 4222, and no explanations on the code sheet.

3880 is Borden shale and siltstone per Robert Blakely.

4200 and 4222 are New Albany… per Robert Blakely.

PH236A quality changed from 8 to Good.

HW160 only record without quality information (original not found).

Elevations with zero were changed to blank per originals.

3) Duplicate Station IDs were identified from AM008A through AM020A; the
original AM series was shot in 1950.  In 1981 it was realized that
the depths were not correct because of a missing layer problem.  The
shot points were not reoccupied nor were new data taken.  The old
data were simply reviewed and recalculated using missing layer
theory.  The AM008A shot with quality "Minimum depth" has a date of
recalculation, 1981.  The other AM008A point should have the original
shot date, 1950. Note that there are some data (from AM013A through
AM016A) that did not have a missing layer problem.  Thus, recalculations
were not done and these shot dates should be 1950. All the
AM series showed a date of 1981 and the dates were changed as per the
previous instructions from Robert Blakely.

4) Since this spreadsheet is to contain seismic shot data, all records
defined with a quality value of "Drilled depth" or "Augered depth" were
deleted as per Robert Blakely.

5) It was observed that the information in fields 8 and 9 did not always
correspond (namely, limestone for New Albany, Antrim, Elsworth, or
Sunbury shales), however, this would take additional analysis to check, so
changes were not made.

6) There are location description questions, but these were not
investigated.  For example, one Station ID may have
multiple survey descriptions, GeoGraphix was not always able to
process the survey descriptions, and so on.

Source_Used_Citiation_Abbreviation: seismic_finished.xls
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20020201</procdate>
        <srcprod>SEISMIC_DECODED.xls</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Karen K. Like</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Cartographic Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5976</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>klike@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
SEISMIC_DECODED.xls was converted into an ESRI ArcView version 3.2
shapefile named SEISMIC_DATA_IN.shp.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20030225</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Christina L. James</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-2504</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cjames@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and
MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20030424</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>13888</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>SEISMIC_DATA_IN.SHP</enttypl>
        <enttypd>ESRI Point Shapefile</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Stationid</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Seismic station identification number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Landmark</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Shot within 330 feet of identifiable landmark</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Robert Blakely, verbal communication</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>(blank)</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Blank</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Bridge</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>G</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Cross roads</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>X</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Farm drive</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>D</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Farm lane</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>L</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Fence line</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>F</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Railroad and road crossing</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>R</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Road bend</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>B</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>T-road</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>T</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y-road</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Y</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Bdrklith</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Bedrock Lithology</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Robert Blakely, oral communication</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>(blank)</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Blank</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Limestone</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Maximum shale added</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>SM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Sandstone</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>SS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Shale</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>SH</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>SL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Not known</edomvd>
            <edomvds>SL</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Stratigraphy</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stratigraphy of Bedrock Surface</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Borden shales and siltstones</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Borden shales and siltstones
(includes Coldwater)
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>3800</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Devonian undifferentiated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Devonian undifferentiated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>4000</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Liston Creek Formation</edomv>
            <edomvd>Liston Creek Formation</edomvd>
            <edomvds>5320</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Mississippian undifferentiated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mississippian undifferentiated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>3000</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>New Albany, Antrim, Elsworth, or Sunbury shales</edomv>
            <edomvd>New Albany, Antrim, Elsworth, or Sunbury shales</edomvd>
            <edomvds>4220</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Ordovician limestone interbedded with shale</edomv>
            <edomvd>Ordovician limestone interbedded with shale</edomvd>
            <edomvds>6020</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Ordovician undifferentiated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Ordovician undifferentiated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>6000</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Pennsylvanian sandstone</edomv>
            <edomvd>Pennsylvanian sandstone</edomvd>
            <edomvds>2070</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Pennsylvanian undifferentiated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Pennsylvanian undifferentiated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>2000</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Rockford Limestone</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rockford Limestone</edomvd>
            <edomvds>3910</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Silurian undifferentiated</edomv>
            <edomvd>Silurian undifferentiated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>5000</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Quality</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Record evaluation</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>
Based on technical factors such as energy
transmittal, arrival alignments, etc.)
</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>(blank)</edomv>
            <edomvd>IGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Blank</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Excellent</edomv>
            <edomvd>Excellent</edomvd>
            <edomvds>E</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Fair</edomv>
            <edomvd>Fair</edomvd>
            <edomvds>F</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Good</edomv>
            <edomvd>Good</edomvd>
            <edomvds>G</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Minimum depth</edomv>
            <edomvd>Minimum depth</edomvd>
            <edomvds>M</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>No good</edomv>
            <edomvd>No good</edomvd>
            <edomvds>X</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Poor</edomv>
            <edomvd>Poor</edomvd>
            <edomvds>P</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Special computation</edomv>
            <edomvd>Special computation (missed shale, etc.)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>S</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Velocity record</edomv>
            <edomvd>Velocity record</edomvd>
            <edomvds>V</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Elevation</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of surface at shot point (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>353</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1235</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Vela</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorded velocity A (feet/second)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Velb</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorded velocity B (feet/second)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Velc</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorded velocity C (feet/second)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Veld</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorded velocity D (feet/second)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Deptha</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Depth to recorded velocity interface A (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Depthb</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Depth to recorded velocity interface B (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Depthc</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Depth to recorded velocity interface C (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Eleva</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of velocity interface A (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Elevb</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of velocity interface B (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Elevc</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Elevation of velocity interface C (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Year</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>4-digit year in which seismic data was obtained</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IGS</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1950</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1983</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday – Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products
generated from this data set.  The following citation should be included:
SEISMIC_DATA_IN: Seismic Refraction Data for Indiana (Indiana Geological
Survey, Point Shapefile).

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to, Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, IN 47405-2208,
and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020907</metd>
    <metrd>20030225</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Christina L. James</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geological Technician</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 2504</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cjames@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data
set identified and received from the IGS.  It is not to be altered or
summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this data
set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the
data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>