<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</origin>
        <origin>Jill Flachskam (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Licia Weber (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Becky Meyer (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Nathan Eaton (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Paul Irwin (Data compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20171115</pubdate>
        <title>
COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mine Entrances in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation,
Point Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Jasonville, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
NOTE: An Esri file geodatabase named "CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB" (containing the point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF") was originally provided to
personnel of the Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS) personnel on November 15, 2017, by personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation. It has been converted to an Esri point shapefile and has been named "COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP" to conform to naming
conventions of the IGS. Also, portions of this metadata have adapted content that was originally authored by IDNR personnel.

This shapefile contains information that is related to two additional GIS datasets produced by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation: 1) [COAL_MINE_UNDERGROUND_DNR_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mines in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation, Polygon Shapefile)] and 2) [COAL_MINE_SURFACE_DNR_IN.SHP: Surface Coal Mines in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, Division of Reclamation, Polygon Shapefile)].
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/layerGallery.html</onlink>
        <onlink>http://www.in.gov/dnr/reclamation/9310.htm</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP contains the entrance locations of all documented underground coal mine entrances that have operated in the coal region
of Indiana since the mid-1880s, up to December 31, 2016. COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP is attributed to allow the mine entrances to be differentiated
based on entrance type (hoist shaft, other shafts, slope, unknown), depth, mine number, and source information (map number).

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF":

"Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN is a compilation of all documented underground coal mine entrances in Indiana.
Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN was compiled by the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) as part of a contract deliverable
for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.
Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN incorporates mine entrance locations compiled as part of the Indiana Coal Mine Information
System (CMIS), an integrated geographic information system (GIS) and database management system (DBMS) created to
store, analyze, and help distribute coal mine data in Indiana. The system contains data for surface and underground
coal mines that operated in Indiana from the mid-1830s to 2007. Original source information for Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN
includes company mine maps, field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and Reports of the Indiana State
Mine Inspector. All mine data included in Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN are organized in a GIS using ESRI ArcGIS software
of the Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI) on the Windows platform. Scale of source data ranges
from 1:4,800 to 1:100,000."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
This data provides access to an Esri point shapefile containing the most current information for coal mine entries in Indiana, as provided by
personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF":

"Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN was originally compiled by the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) as part of a contract deliverable
for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.
Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN incorporates mine entrance locations compiled as part of the Indiana Coal Mine Information System
(CMIS), an integrated geographic information system (GIS) and database management system (DBMS) created to store, analyze,
and help distribute coal mine data in Indiana. The system contains data for surface and underground coal mines that operated
in Indiana from the mid-1830s to 2007. Original source information for Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN.SHP includes company mine
maps, field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and Reports of the Indiana State Mine Inspector. Scale
of source data ranges from 1:4,800 to 1:100,000."
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1883</begdate>
          <enddate>20161231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Annual</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-87.8657</westbc>
        <eastbc>-86.5850</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.2105</northbc>
        <southbc>37.8407</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>economy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Division of Reclamation (DOR)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>mining</themekey>
        <themekey>energy resources</themekey>
        <themekey>economic geology</themekey>
        <themekey>coal mine</themekey>
        <themekey>mine entry</themekey>
        <themekey>mine entrance</themekey>
        <themekey>underground mine</themekey>
        <themekey>deep mine</themekey>
        <themekey>coal</themekey>
        <themekey>shaft</themekey>
        <themekey>slope</themekey>
        <themekey>hoist shaft</themekey>
        <themekey>reclamation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Illinois Basin</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>
Esri ArcGIS version 10.4 shapefile format, approximately 944 Kb
</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Coal_Mines_Entries</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
This data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be accurate.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF":

"The attribute values were checked to ensure that the values were within the range that should be expected based upon the values of
the input data that were used to create the shapefile. Two tests for attribute consistency were performed using the QueryBuilder Tool
in Esri ArcView: (1) Completeness of values was verified. No values were left blank. (2) Validity of values was verified. All features
were attributed with values in the appropriate range and format."
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Esri ArcInfo point topology is present</logic>
    <complete>
This data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be complete.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF":

"Coal mine entrances included in this shapefile were compiled by the  Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) as part of a contract deliverable for
the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation. Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN incorporates mine
entrance locations compiled as part of the Indiana Coal Mine Information System (CMIS), an integrated geographic information system (GIS) and
database management system (DBMS) created to maintain spatial and tabular data related to coal mines in the Indiana portion of the Illinois Basin.
The CMIS includes spatial mine data compiled from all known sources including: company mine maps (from the Indiana Division of Reclamation and from coal
companies), field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and reports of the State Mine Inspector. In compiling data for the
CMIS, every effort was made to ensure data accuracy and completeness. However, it is known that undocumented mining has occurred in the study
area. Also, because of inconsistency in source map quality and completeness, the actual locations of mine entrances may not coincide
with the points as portrayed in this shapefile. A detailed on-the-ground survey and historical analysis of a specific site may differ from this
shapefile."
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
This preliminary data set was provided by IDNR personnel and is assumed to be horizontally accurate, per IDNR standards.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDNR, Division of Reclamation, for the source point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF":

"Mine entrances included in this shapefile were compiled from several sources having varying map scales. Thus, the horizontal positional
accuracy of individual points may vary. If highly detailed mine entrance location information is needed, contact the Indiana Department
of Natural Resources, Divison of Reclamation for additional information.  Because of inconsistency in source map quality and completeness,
the actual location of mine entrances may not coincide with the points portrayed in this shapefile."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the creation of these data. No quantitative tests were performed.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>Various</pubdate>
            <title>Multiple titles</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Various</pubplace>
              <publish>Various</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Various</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1872</begdate>
              <enddate>1989</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Various miscellaneous maps and publications</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
Many mine entrances were added to the dataset from
a variety of sources, all of which are listed in the attribute
section of this document under the Mapnumb attribute field. The number
of sources actually consulted is too great to list here. These sources
also provided much of the attribute information found in the final
dataset.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1988</pubdate>
            <title>1:24,000-scale Features Related to Subsidence Maps</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Mylar</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1835</begdate>
              <enddate>1987</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data compilation date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Underground Mine Quadrangle Maps</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
The majority of the mine entrances included in this dataset were
originally digitized from the Mylar Underground Mine Quadrangle
Maps.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20000501</pubdate>
            <title>Indiana Coal Mine Information System</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Network drive</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1835</begdate>
              <enddate>20000501</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>CMIS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
CMIS mine data were updated with information collected in 2000
for the publication of the Directory of Coal Mines and Producers
in Indiana - 2000. The update included three new underground mine
entrances.  The 2000 Coal Directory was not a source of new
information, but rather a medium to distribute updated information
obtained from the Coal Mine Information System.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</origin>
            <pubdate>20171115</pubdate>
            <title>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB - point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF" - Coal Mine Entries (as of December 31, 2016)</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Jasonville, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Vector digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1835</begdate>
              <enddate>20161231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB (point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF")</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Coal mine entrance locations in Indiana, as of December 31, 2016.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Mine entrances from a variety of sources including company mine maps,
field maps and notes of IGS geologists, IGS publications, and Reports
of the State Mine Inspector were hand-plotted on 1:24,000-scale
topographic maps. This data set, comprised of nearly 100 quadrangle
maps, was compiled by IGS personnel in the mid-1980s to create the
first complete compilation of mine entrance locations in Indiana.
Although mine entrances were originally plotted on paper quadrangle
maps, those work maps were soon replaced by a set of Mylar maps that
constitute the suite of 1:24,000-scale Features Related to Subsidence
Maps.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Various miscellaneous maps and publications</srcused>
        <procdate>1985 to 1988</procdate>
        <srcprod>Underground Mine Quadrangle Maps</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Licia Weber</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1364</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>weber@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Entrance locations from the Mylar Indiana Geological Survey
1:24,000-scale subsidence maps were digitized by Indiana
Geological Survey (IGS) personnel in the late 1980s as a
component of the first coal mine GIS for the IGS and the Indiana
Division of Reclamation. Points were digitized using ESRI PC
ArcInfo and georeferenced using 8 tics from 1:24,000-scale
topographic maps. Points were digitized, but no attribute
information was associated with the points at that time.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Underground Mine Quadrangle Maps</srcused>
        <procdate>1988 to 1991</procdate>
        <srcprod>Coal mine entry coverages</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Paul Irwin</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5812</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>irwinp@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Data from the early coal mine GIS (coal mine entry coverages)
were converted to a new GIS format and updated with new mine
data. Using ESRI ArcView version 3.1, points were extracted
from the old GIS coverages and attributed with source information,
entry type, depth, and symbol rotation angle. In addition,
several historic and contemporary mine entrances were added to
the dataset by reviewing an exhaustive list of various miscellaneous
maps and publications. This effort was required to rectify positional
errors and entry omissions discovered in the Coal mine entry coverages.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>
Coal mine entry coverage, Underground Mine Quadrangle Maps, Various
miscellaneous maps and publications
</srcused>
        <procdate>1997 to 1999</procdate>
        <srcprod>
Coal_Entry shapefile (a component of the Indiana Coal Mine Information
System (CMIS)
</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan K. Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>neaton@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Coal Mine Information System CMIS mine data were updated
with information collected for publication of the Directory of
Coal Mines and Producers in Indiana - 2000. The update included
three new underground mine entrances.  The 2000 Coal Directory
was not a source of new information, but rather a medium to
distribute updated information obtained from the Coal Mine
Information System.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>CMIS Coal_Entry shapefiles</srcused>
        <procdate>20000501</procdate>
        <srcprod>Updated CMIS Coal_Entry shapefiles</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan K. Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>neaton@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
County-based mine entrance shapefiles were combined to a regional
shapefile using the merge function in ESRI ArcView's Geoprocessing
Wizard. The resulting shapefile included all underground mine
entrances in the Indiana coal region.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Updated CMIS Coal_Entry shapefiles</srcused>
        <procdate>20000814</procdate>
        <srcprod>SW_COAL_ENTRY.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan K. Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>neaton@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The Coal Mine Information System CMIS mine data were updated
with active underground mine information collected annually from
from the Indiana Bureau of Mines. In addition, several mine entrances
were added or relocated by georeferencing recently scanned mine workings
maps and reviewing mine entry locations. SW_COAL_ENTRY was imported to an
ESRI personal geodatabase point feature class and renamed COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_IN.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Updated CMIS Coal_Entry shapefiles</srcused>
        <procdate>2002 to 2007</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_IN.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Becky Meyer</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS/Database Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-6641</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>reameyer@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_IN was obtained from the Indiana Geological Survey
as part of a contract deliverable for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of
the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.
COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_IN was renamed to Coal_Mine_Entries_DNR_IN
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20151028</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jill Flachskam</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Inventory Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>14619 West State Road 48</address>
              <city>Jasonville</city>
              <state>IN</state>
              <postal>47438</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-665-2207</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-665-5041</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jflachskam@dnr.in.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1630 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
An Esri file geodatabase named "CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB" (containing the point feature class named "COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF") was originally provided to
personnel of the Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGS) personnel on November 15, 2017, by personnel of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources,
Division of Reclamation. The feature class COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF was then converted to an Esri point shapefile and was renamed "COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP"
to conform to naming conventions of the IGS. Also, portions of this metadata have adapted content that was originally authored by IDNR personnel.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>CMIS_GDB_MAIN.MDB, COAL_ENTRY_GEOREF (point feature class)</srcused>
        <procdate>20171115</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) an MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter Schweitzer
(U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20171212</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>
Monday through Friday, except holidays
</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>3701</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_DNR_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>number field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Entry_Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of Underground Mine Entrance</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Hoist</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Vertical mine entrance (shaft); utilized for coal removal
and entry of mine workers
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Other</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Vertical mine entrance (shaft); secondary entrance utilized as
an air or escape shaft
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Slope</edomv>
            <edomvd>Horizontal or subhorizontal mine entrance</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Unknown</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown mine entrance type</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Entry_Depth</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Depth of mine entrance below ground surface in feet (unknown depths are listed as -9999)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>506</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Feet</attrunit>
            <attrmres>1</attrmres>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Mine_Number</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Mine ID Number; unique number used to identify information related to a mine in the Coal Mine Information
System database (-9999 indicates a record for which mine data is either unavailable or has yet to be been entered into the Coal
Mine Information System GIS or tabular database)
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>999999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_Number</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>ID number used to identify source data used to determine location of mine entrance</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>
999999	Straw, W.T., Gray, H. and Powell, R.L.,  1977,  Environmental geology of
the Evansville area southwestern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special
Report 12.
999997	Ashley, G.H.,  1898,  The coal deposits of Indiana, in Blatchley, W.S.,
1898, Twenty-third annual report of geology and natural resources: Indiana
Department of Geology and Natural Resources, Indianapolis.
999995	Collett, J., 1883, Thirteenth annual report of geology and natural resources:
Indiana Department of Geology and Natural Resources, Indianapolis.
999993	Unpublished aerial photograph, date uncertain (probably 1940, 1954, or 1978),
Unpublished aerial photographs from the aerial photo archive of the IGS that were used
by IGS geologists to determine the extent of areas affected by surface coal mining: Indiana
Geological Survey Petroleum Files.
999990	Wier, C.E. and Stanley, J.T., 1953, Distribution, structure, and mined areas
of coals in Pike County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal
Map 3.
999985	Cox, E.T., 1874, Fifth annual report of the Geological Survey of Indiana:
Sentinel Company, Indianapolis.
999984	Cox, E.T., 1872, Third and fourth annual reports of the Geological Survey of
Indiana: R.J. Bright, State Printer, Indianapolis.
999971	State Mine Inspector, 1890-1947, Annual report of the State Inspector of Mines:
Indiana Department of Geology and Natural Resources Annual Reports.
999970	Weir, C.E., 1958, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Warrick County,
Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 7.
999961	Weir, C.E. and Powell, R.L., 1967, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of
coals in Knox County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 12.
999960	Hutchison, H.C., 1971, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Daviess County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 15.
999959	Hutchison, H.C., 1952-1975, Field work maps (quadrangles) showing geology and features
related to coal and mining: Indiana Geological Survey IGS Coal Records.
999957	Weber, Licia, 1986-1989, Maps showing features related to subsidence in
southwest Indiana - 7.5' quadrangles: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Files.
999950	Hutchison, H.C., 1967, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Martin County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 11.
999948	Hutchison, H.C. and Hasenmueller, W.A., 1988, Distribution, structure, and
mined areas of coals in Greene County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey
Preliminary Coal Map 17.
999946	Kottlowski, Frank, 1960, Geology and coal deposits of the Switz City quadrangle,
Greene County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 41.
999940	Kottlowski, Frank, 1959, Geology and coal deposits of the Coal City quadrangle,
Greene, Clay, and Owen Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal
Investigations Map 28.
999938	Weir, C.E., 1951, Geology and coal deposits of the Linton quadrangle, Greene
and Sullivan Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations
Map 9.
999937	Weir, C.E., 1953, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Sullivan
County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 2.
999936	Weir, C.E., 1954, Geology and coal deposits of the Hymera quadrangle, Sullivan
County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 16.
999935	Kottlowski, 1954, Geology and coal deposits of the Dugger quadrangle, Sullivan
County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 11.
999933	Hutchison, H.C., 1959, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Spencer County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 8.
999930	Hutchison, H.C., 1956, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Clay County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 6.
999929	Weir, C.E., 1950, Geology and coal deposits of the Jasonville quadrangle, Clay,
Greene, and Sullivan Counties, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal
Investigations Map 1.
999928	Hutchison, H.C., 1960, Geology and coal deposits of the Brazil quadrangles,
Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Bulletin 16.
999925	Hutchison, H.C., 1964, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Dubois County, Indiana:  Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 10.
999923	Hutchison, H.C., 1971, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in
Perry County, Indiana:  Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 14.
999920	Weir, C.E., 1952, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Vigo
County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Preliminary Coal Map 1.
999919	Friedman, S.A., 1989, Geology and coal deposits of the Clinton area,
west-central Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 42.
999916	Hutchinson, H.C., 1958, Geology and coal deposits of the Seelyville quadrangle,
Vigo County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal Investigations Map 2.
999915	Friedman, S.A., 1961, Geology and coal deposits of the Terre Haute and Dennison
quadrangles, Vigo County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Coal
Investigations Map 44.
999913	Friedman, S.A., 1961, Work map showing extent, distribution, and structure of
coal VII, &amp; mine shafts and extent of mining, &amp; coal test boreholes with data
(New Goshen Quadrangle): Indiana Geological Survey Unpublished Coal Records.
999908	Powell, R.L., 1968, Distribution, structure, and mined areas of coals in Parke
County and southern Vermillion County, Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey
Preliminary Coal Map 13.
999904	Cox, E.T., 1872b, Third and fourth annual reports of the Geological Survey of
Indiana: R.J. Bright, State Printer, Indianapolis.
999903      Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation, Abandoned
Mine Lands Program, 1999, field reconnaissance.
999901	Hunt, Raymond S., 1925, The geology and natural resources of an area in the
vicinity of Bloomington, Indiana, Unpublished M.S. Thesis, Indiana University, Bloomington.
610312-305545  Original or reproduced company mine map.

-9999    Unknown data source. Records need to be investigated to determine source information.

3141-1161      Coal data card, IGS coal card file.
</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Symbol_Rotation</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Symbol rotation angle; a numeric value between 0 and 360 used in ArcGIS to rotate the slope entrance symbols
to the approximate orientation of the actual mine entrances. The values were determined based on a value of 360 pointing due west
and a value of 90 pointing due south. Note that Hoist, Other, and Unknown entry types are all attributed with values
of 0 because those symbols don't need to be rotated.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>360</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>County_Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of the county in which the site is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>igsinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological and Water Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following citation should be included:
[COAL_MINE_ENTRIES_IN.SHP: Underground Coal Mine Entrances in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, Scale, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile), 20171115].

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or
damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party.
The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20151028</metd>
    <metrd>20171212</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-856-5456</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGWS. It is not to be altered or summarized. IGS does
not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone other than the IGWS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>