<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis (CGDA)</origin>
        <origin>Henry H. Gray (Data compiler)</origin>
        <origin>Sally L. Letsinger  (GIS compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20100510</pubdate>
        <title>PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN: Southern extent of glaciation in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:500,000, Line Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>

The mapping conducted was based on the best available information. The glacial limit in southern Indiana has been the subject of study and refinement for many years. Among the most important early attempts at delineating the limit through field mapping were those of G. F. Wright, who presented a map of the glacial limit in 1884 and slightly refined the line in 1890. Frank Leverett (1896) contributed to the understanding of the glacial limit through a long career of mapping the Pleistocene deposits of Indiana and adjacent states. Malott summed up previous mapping efforts in 1926; at that time, the outer (older) glacial limit in Indiana became defined sufficiently to establish a standard that held for many years without much change. The pre-Wisconsin glacial limit in some areas of Indiana is discontinuous and is defined primarily by scattered patches of till and erratics, as shown by Thornbury (1937). Most of this work was summarized and improved upon by H. H. Gray in: Gray, H. H., 1988, Map of southern Indiana showing geomorphic features relevant to ice marginal relict drainage, in Gray, H. H., 1989, Relict drainageways associated with the glacial boundary in southern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 45, 9 p.

This data layer is a single line representing the southern limit of glaciation in the state of Indiana. It was derived by digitizing the glacial limit line from Plate 1 of Gray (1989).

Gray, H. H., 1988, Map of southern Indiana showing geomorphic features relevant to ice marginal relict drainage, in Gray, H. H., 1989, Relict drainageways associated with the glacial boundary in southern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 45, 9 p.

Leverett, F., 1896, The glacial deposits of Indiana: Inland Educator, v. 3, p. 24-32. (Additional discussion in v. 3, p. 327.)

Malott, C. A., 1926, The glacial boundary in Indiana: Indiana Academy of Science Proceedings for 1925, v. 35, p. 93-107.

Thornbury, W. D., 1937, Glacial geology of southern and south-central Indiana: Indiana Division of Geology, 138 p.

Wright, G. F., 1884, The glacial boundary in Indiana, Ohio, and Kentucky: Cleveland, Ohio, Western Reserve Historical Society, 86 p.

Wright, G. F., 1890, The glacial boundary in western Pennsylvania, Ohio, Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois: U.S. Geological Survey Bulletin 58, 112 p.
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://inmap.indiana.edu/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN.shp is a line shapefile that shows the extent of glaciation in Indiana as delineated by mapped glacial deposits of various types and ages at a scale of 1:500,000. The mapped units include Pleistocene sediments of glacial origin that are interpreted to have been deposited during multiple episodes of continental glaciation by the North American Laurentide ice sheet. The term "pre-Wisconsin" is meant to distinguish this glacial limit from that represented in a companion data set [WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN: Extent of Wisconsin Glaciation in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:500,000, Line Shapefile)] that represents the (later or younger) limit of Wisconsin glaciation in Indiana.</abstract>
      <purpose>PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN.shp was digitized from the glacial limit line represented on Plate 1 (1988) of Gray, H. H., 1988, Map of southern Indiana showing geomorphic features relevant to ice marginal relict drainage in Gray, H. H., 1989, Relict drainageways associated with the glacial boundary in southern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 45, 9 p. PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN.shp was created to provide a digital shapefile of the southern extent of glaciation in the state of Indiana, suitable for use in a GIS.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1988</begdate>
          <enddate>1988</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.0334</westbc>
        <eastbc>-85.7997</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.3280</northbc>
        <southbc>37.9799</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis (CGDA)</themekey>
        <themekey>Geology</themekey>
        <themekey>Surficial Geology</themekey>
        <themekey>Quaternary</themekey>
        <themekey>pre-Wisconsin glaciation</themekey>
        <themekey>Glaciation</themekey>
        <themekey>Continental glaciation</themekey>
        <themekey>Glacial till</themekey>
        <themekey>Diamict</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS (v 9.3.1) Shapefile format, Microsoft Windows XP, approximately 48 KB</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Glacial_PreWisconsin_Glacial_Limit</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The attributes included in the attribute table were checked for completeness.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>This data layer consists of one continuous line. The line was digitized at a zoom scale of 1:24,000, so the lines should be sufficiently continuous for use at the recommended scale (1:500,000).</logic>
    <complete>The digital shapefile was derived with modifications from a preexisting published map (Gray, 1988) and is assumed to embody the same definitions and generalizations as were used in the creation of the published map. Additional information can be found concerning the certainty of the mapping in Citation Details above and in the statements of accuracy given below.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
No records exist regarding horizontal positional accuracy of this shapefile. The coordinates used in this layer were derived from a paper map published at 1:500,000 scale, which equates to a horizontal accuracy of 254 meters. No quantitative tests were performed.

The following was excerpted from H. H. Gray (in preparation), "A principal reason is that deposits of the older glaciations have for a long time suffered the vicissitudes of weathering and erosion. As a result, they are patchy, discontinuous, hard to find, hard to delimit, hard to interpret, and their influence on the landscape has been severely diminished. In many places it is difficult to determine whether the deposit in question was truly ice-lain. And although there were several pre-Wisconsin glacial events in Indiana, they have not yet been definitively sorted out. Earlier attempts to establish an orderly sequence of events have been shown to be faulty. Furthermore, a blanket of wind-blown silt known as loess, which is principally of Wisconsin age, spreads eastward from the Wabash River valley, covers considerable areas of the deposits of the older glaciations, and obscures a part of the glacial boundary.

And so, although it is known that ice of the older glaciations several times covered a large part of southern Indiana, the line that can be drawn marking their extent is discontinuously and uncertainly drawn. It is also subject to revision. The discovery of a patch of erratic boulders, a few previously unknown glacial striations on bedrock, or data from a new bore-hole may cause the boundary to be shifted by a kilometer or two. Thus the “Glacial Boundary” is very much a work in progress."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
The vertical positional accuracy of the published paper
source map is unknown. Other than using the same vertical datum as the source data, vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the digital production of this dataset. No quantitative tests were performed. Vertical accuracy of the published paper source map is unknown.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>1989</pubdate>
            <title>Gray, H. H., 1988, Map of southern Indiana showing geomorphic features relevant to ice marginal relict drainage, in Gray, H. H., 1989, Relict drainageways associated with the glacial boundary in southern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 45, 9 p.</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>500000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Paper map</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1988</begdate>
              <enddate>1988</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SR45</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The map (Plate 1) included in this publication is the source of the line feature representing the southern extent of pre-Wisconsin glaciation in Indiana.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Plate 1, Gray, H. H., 1988, Map of southern Indiana showing geomorphic features relevant to ice marginal relict drainage, in Gray, H. H., 1989, Relict drainageways associated with the glacial boundary in southern Indiana: Indiana Geological Survey Special Report 45, 9 p. (SR45) was scanned at 600 dpi on a wide-bed color scanner to get a digital image of the map. The map image was saved in PNG format. The original map was published at a scale of 1:500,000 and the original projection was Lambert conformal conic projection with standard parallels at 33 degrees and 45 degrees. Using ESRI ArcMap software and the Georeferencing Toolbar, the map was georeferenced to both an Indiana county vector polygon shapefile and public land survey system vector polygon shapefile in UTM NAD1983 Zone 16 projection. The paper map and original projection did not accommodate a simple affine georeferencing transformation, so a spline was used to get the best fit to the desired UTM projection. Over 50 control points were used, with a resultant error of less than 200 meters.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SR45</srcused>
        <procdate>20090713</procdate>
        <srcprod>SR45_spline83.png</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1356</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>After Plate 1 of SR45 was georeferenced, the resultant shapefile was assigned the UTM projection (NAD 1983, Zone 16) upon which the georeferencing was based. The line described as "Probable limit of pre-Wisconsin ice" in the legend of Plate 1 of SR45 was digitized at a zoom scale of at least 1:24,000 to achieve a smooth line when viewed or used at the appropriate scale of 1:500,000. One attribute "LIMIT" was added to the attribute table.</procdesc>
        <srcused>SR45_spline83.png</srcused>
        <procdate>20100215</procdate>
        <srcprod>PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1356</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and
MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20100510</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 1356</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Complete Chain</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Limit</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification of feature represented in the data layer.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>pre-Wisconsin glacial limit</edomv>
            <edomvd>Southernmost advance of glaciation in Indiana.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSInfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>

COPYRIGHT 2010, THE TRUSTEES OF INDIANA UNIVERSITY, INDIANA GEOLOGICAL SURVEY, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any
products generated from this data.  The following source citation should be
included: [PRE-WISCONSIN_GLACIAL_LIMIT_IN: Southern extent of glaciation in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:500,000, Line Shapefile)]

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405 2208,
and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20100510</metd>
    <metrd>20100510</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Sally L. Letsinger</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey, Center for Geospatial Data Analysis</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Research Hydrogeologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 1356</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>sletsing@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>