<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>20150108</pubdate>
        <title>PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP: Petroleum Well Locations in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile)</title>
        <edition>2015qtr1</edition>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP was created from data in the Indiana Geological Survey Petroleum Well Database, which is a component of the IGS Petroleum Database
Management System (PDMS). The database includes records obtained from the IGS petroleum well files, which represent the most comprehensive collection of
petroleum-related well records in the state. Well records were first obtained by W. S. Blatchley, State Geologist, beginning in 1896. A formal system of collecting
petroleum well records and procedures for its maintenance were started in the early 1950s by Thomas A. Dawson, former Head of the IGS Petroleum Section. The information
contained in these records came from the following sources: the Indiana Division of Oil and Gas, records and plats from the Ohio Oil Company,and Indiana Geological
Survey Publication 108 (William N. Logan, 1931, The subsurface strata of Indiana: Indiana Department of Conservation Publication 108, 790 p., 16 figs.).

NOTE: As of January 8, 2015, the Indiana Geological Survey began scheduling regular quarterly updates for this dataset. Therefore, well information is only as current
as the publication date of this data set. If more current data are needed, please use the subscription-based services of the PDMS Web site: ( http://igs.indiana.edu/PDMS/ ).
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/layerGallery.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP is an ESRI ArcGIS point shapefile of locations of all known petroleum test wells in Indiana as of January 8, 2015, as contained in
the Indiana Geological Survey's Petroleum Well Database. The IGS has limited the attribute information contained in these data to the following; well identification
numbers, total well depth, well type symbols (well description), and the oil/gas field names. If users require more detailed information regarding well record tables or
petroleum field production histories please visit the IGS Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS): ( http://igs.indiana.edu/PDMS/ ).

The PDMS Web site is comprised of an interactive map that offers users the ability to examine and build customized maps, query data, and interactively link to
a "Table Viewer," where detailed tables provide well header and event information, as well as production histories, etc. The PDMS is a subscription-based Web site,
where users can choose to view petroluem records and maps at no cost using the "Basic Subscription" option. The PDMS "Premium Subscription" option does charge a fee,
but adds even more value to well records, reports, logs, and geological interpretations related to a well. It also allows for more efficient access to data from multiple
wells during a single user session. If users require more detailed information regarding well record tables or petroleum field production histories please visit the
IGS Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS): ( http://igs.indiana.edu/PDMS/ ).
</abstract>
      <purpose>PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP was created to provide a statewide GIS layer showing all known petroleum test well locations in Indiana, as of January 8, 2015.</purpose>
      <supplinf>
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP was created from data in the Indiana Geological Survey Petroleum Well Database (Microsoft Access). By the year 2001,  well locations in UTM
(Universal Transverse Mercator) coordinates had been tentatively determined for every well in Indiana. The determination of these coordinates spanned some 7 years and
involved a variety of methods, including digitizing from 1:24,000 topographic maps, batch processing software (GeoGraphix GES 97.5) for converting descriptive locations
to coordinate locations, and interactive on-screen measuring using DRGs (digital raster graphics). The end result of these methods varied and some current well spots may be
slightly mislocated. Well locations in the PDMS are being reviewed at present for accuracy. The method by which a well is located is recorded in the PDMS as either
(1) MEASURED, (2) GPS, or (3) IMPORTED.

(1) MEASURED refers to locations that have been measured on-screen using Digital Raster Graphic Quads (DRG - digital USGS 1:24,000 topographic maps) in ESRI ArcView
(before 2001) or ArcGIS. Measured locations generally are considered accurate to the limits of the well description translated to a map resolution of 1:24,000 (roughly 50 ft,
however, the relative accuracy of a location, as compared with other measured locations nearby, normally would be much greater).

(2) GPS refers to locations with coordinates determined by Global Positioning System (GPS). Locations have not, as yet, been determined using GPS.

(3) IMPORTED refers to wells with a location determined by digitizing from paper 1:24,000 topographic maps or by batch processing software.

All well locations in Indiana have been visually examined and compared with earlier manually spotted well location maps at a scale 1 inch = 1 mile. Obvious discrepancies have
been corrected by measuring the well locations on-screen on a DRG. However, lesser accuracy is likely for the well locations in many densely drilled areas. These locations will
eventually become MEASURED as time permits.

NOTE: Several wells in this dataset fall slightly outside the state boundary as depicted on USGS 1:24,000-scale topographic maps. The location of these wells have been verified,
and the wells are valid components of the database. Therefore, clipping this dataset to the state boundary would result in a spatial dataset that does not fully reflect the
contents of the IGS Petroleum Well Database which can be accessed via the Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS).
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1886</begdate>
          <enddate>20150108</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1562</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.7104</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7708</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7668</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>economy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Petroleum Database Management System (PDMS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Petroleum Well Database</themekey>
        <themekey>petroleum</themekey>
        <themekey>oil</themekey>
        <themekey>gas</themekey>
        <themekey>gas storage</themekey>
        <themekey>well</themekey>
        <themekey>energy resources</themekey>
        <themekey>economic geology</themekey>
        <themekey>petroleum field</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS point shapefile (version 10.2), Windows 7, 10.8 MB</native>
    <useconst>Geology--Petroleum_Wells</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
Well location coordinates and other data in the Indiana Geological Survey's Petroleum Well Database and the locations shown on digital maps using
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP are believed to be reasonably accurate when portrayed on a scale of 1 inch to 1 mile. Although the coordinates for a great
many locations in the database have been accurately determined, past practices and inherent limitations on the accuracy to which a well may be spotted
on a scale of 1:24,000 (USGS Topographic Map standard), have resulted in well coordinates that may be spotted some small distance from their actual locations.
Depending on circumstances, this distance could be as great as 100 feet, or more in rare instances. In general, such discrepancies should be sufficiently accurate
for most petroleum exploration and field mapping purposes.

Additionally, it is important to note that new and revised data are continually being entered into the Petroleum Well Database, and despite the use of
careful procedures and proofing of the data after it has been entered, human error always remains a possibility. Every effort is made to correct errors
and discrepancies when they are identified, but it is the responsibility of the user to verify any information to the extent it is deemed important.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Point features present</logic>
    <complete>PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP contains locations of all known petroleum test wells in Indiana as of January 8, 2015.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
Well location coordinates and other data in the Indiana Geological Survey's Petroleum Well Database and the locations shown on
digital maps using that data are believed to be reasonably accurate when portrayed on a scale of 1 inch to 1 mile.  Although
the coordinates for a great many locations in the database have been very accurately determined, past practices and inherent
limitations on the accuracy to which a well may be spotted on a scale of 1:24,000 (USGS Topographic Map standard), have resulted
in well coordinates that may be spotted some small distance from their actual locations. Depending on circumstances, this distance
could be as great as 100 ft or, rarely, somewhat more. In general, such discrepancies are sufficiently accurate for most petroleum
exploration and field mapping purposes.

Additionally, it is important to note that new and revised data are continually being entered into the Petroleum Well Database, and
despite the use of careful procedures and proofing of the data after it has been entered, human error always remains a possibility.
Every effort is made to correct errors and discrepancies when they are identified, but it is the responsibility of the user to verify
any information to the extent it is deemed important.

NOTE: Several wells in this dataset fall slightly outside the state boundary as depicted on USGS 1:24,000-scale topographic maps.
The location of these wells have been verified, and the wells are valid components of the PDMS Database. Therefore, clipping this dataset
to the state boundary would result in a spatial dataset that does not fully reflect the contents of the IGS Petroleum Database Management
System (PDMS Database).
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
Although well locations are normally staked by a registered surveyor, the IGS has determined that the locations and elevations reported
are occasionally erroneous. Consequently, in the 1950s, the IGS began checking the locations and elevations of new and older wells in the
field. Most well locations in Indiana have been verified in the field, however, the locations of many older wells (pre-1920s) are not
accurately known.

Well locations are checked in the field using a surveyor's altimeter and USGS topographic map, and their accuracy is subject to the abilities
of the geologist, the accuracy of the altimeter (generally in the range of 3 feet), the reliability of the base elevations posted on the topographic
map, the status of the location when checked (staked locations are sometimes moved a short distance by operators; locations checked after a dry
hole has been plugged are subject to greater error).
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20150108</pubdate>
            <title>Indiana Geological Survey Petrolem Well Database</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP was created using data from the Indiana Geological Survey Petroleum Well Database, a component of the IGS Petroleum
Database Management System (PDMS). No single citation can be given regarding the source of records in the IGS Petroleum Database.
The PDMS database contains information from the thousands of operators of numerous petroleum wells in the state of Indiana. Since 1938,
most petroleum well records have been processed by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Oil and Gas. Data for
earlier wells were compiled from various sources including the Indiana Division of Oil and Gas, records and plats from the Ohio Oil Company,
and Publication 108 (William N. Logan, 1931, The subsurface strata of Indiana: Indiana Department of Conservation Publication 108, 790 p.,
16 figs.). Data received from the Division of Oil and Gas are sent to the Indiana Geological Survey and the information is entered into the
IGS PDMS database. Each petroleum operator must apply for a drilling permit with the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of
Oil and Gas. Upon completion of drilling, the operator is required to submit drilling records to the Division of Oil and Gas. For more
information on the drilling permit process, contact:

Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Oil and Gas, 402 W. Washington St., Rm 293, Indianapolis, Indiana 46204 (317 232 4055).
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1886</begdate>
              <enddate>20150108</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>IGS Petroleum Well Database (Microsoft SQL)</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Locations of all known petroleum test wells in Indiana, as of January 8, 2015.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This process step outlines the procedures that IGS personnel use to update the IGS Petroleum Well Database, which is used to produce regular updates to
the shapefile named "PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP":

Once the drilling reports are received from the Division of Oil and Gas, well information, such as operator, geological data, and locational
information, are entered into the IGS Petroleum Well Database. IGS personnel then field check the location information of the well.
All location information is entered into the database, using the Congressional Township and Range system or, in some cases, other irregular
land description systems. The locational information is then converted to X-Y coordinates (UTM Zone 16, NAD 1983 coordinate system) by spotting
the well locations on 1:24,000-scale USGS digital raster graphic (DRGs) quadrangle maps in ESRI ArcView. For this dataset, detailed symbol information
in the database was generalized from over 70 categories into five categories: gas (GAS), gas storage (GS), abandoned gas storage (AGS), oil (OIL),
and other petroleum test (OPT) wells.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>IGS Petroleum Well Database</srcused>
        <procdate>20020531 to present</procdate>
        <srcprod>IGS Petroleum Well Database</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Charles W. Zuppann</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Petroleum Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5412</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>czuppann@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
IGS personnel used ArcToolBox to extract the locations of all known petroleum test wells from the IGS Petroleum Well Database on January 8, 2015, as a temporary
x-y tabular dataset. ArcToolBox was then used to convert the temporary x-y tabular data into an Esri point shapefile. It was named PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP to
conform to the internal naming conventions of the IGS.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>IGS Petroleum Well Database</srcused>
        <procdate>20150108</procdate>
        <srcprod>PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United States
Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20150130</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 855 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>_Method: Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>83052</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.DBF</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IGS_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification number of the well (IGS, internal)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>100001</rdommin>
            <rdommax>181752</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POSTED_TD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The deepest total depth of any operation conducted on a well. For deviated wells (horizontal and directional wells), the value has
been corrected to true vertical depth. The value is retrieved from a query of the TD data field in the Well Events Table and from the Pick TVD value in
the Picks Table in the Records for Event Section. The posted TD is the total depth that is posted by the IGS on a map showing total depths. (Note: A value
of "zero" indicates no data.)
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>10</rdommin>
            <rdommax>11734</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ALT_SYMBOL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Symbol abbreviations of the description of the well type, (see the "Entity and Attribute, Overview Section" above for a detailed description)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of the county for which the well is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>
The following was extracted from the PDMS Website ( http://igs.indiana.edu/pdms/ ) regarding
the attribute field titled "SYMBOL":

"SYMBOL SCHEMA

A graphic symbol is used to indicate the location and "designation" of a well on IGS maps.
The IGS Petroleum Well Symbols are similar to those used in the petroleum industry and by
other geological surveys, although no recognized standard exists.

A well's Symbol designation is based on its status and history. The symbol scheme employs a
set of basic symbols to which "modifiers" can be added to impart additional information. This
scheme is explained in the IGS Petroleum Well Symbol Explanation.

SYMBOL CODES

Each graphic symbol corresponds to a Symbol Code labeled Symbol in a well's Well Header. The
meanings of the symbols and their associated symbol codes are shown in the table below."
</eaover>
      <eadetcit>
The following table provides a description of the attribute field classifications used for the attribute field named "SYMBOL" for
PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP and on the Petroluem Database Management System (PDMS).

SYMBOL information ("well type") can be generalized from over 80 categories into five "GENERAL" categories: gas (GAS), gas storage (GS),
abandoned gas storage (AGS), oil (OIL), and other petroleum test (OPT) wells.

This information was extracted from a PDF document titled "PDMS_WELL_SYMBOLS_TABLE.PDF" of the PDMS database,
( http://igs.indiana.edu/PDMS/Help/PDMS_Well_Symbols_Table.pdf )

"GENERAL	SYMBOL 	       Full Class Name
_________________________________________________

OPT         AGAS           abandoned gas

OPT         AGAS-C         abandoned gas, completion type uncertain

OPT         AGAS-L         abandoned gas, location uncertain

OPT         AGAS-LC        abandoned gas, location and completion type uncertain

AGS         AGS            abandoned gas storage

AGS         AGS-C          abandoned gas storage, completion type uncertain

AGS         AGSG           abandoned gas and gas storage

AGS         AGS-L          abandoned gas storage, location uncertain

AGS         AGS-LC         abandoned gas storage, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AOAG           abandoned oil and gas

OPT         AOAG-C         abandoned oil and gas, completion type uncertain

OPT         AOAG-L         abandoned oil and gas, location uncertain

OPT         AOAG-LC        abandoned oil and gas, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AOBS           abandoned observation

OPT         AOBS-C         abandoned observation, completion type uncertain

OPT         AOBS-L         abandoned observation, location uncertain

OPT         AOBS-LC        abandoned observation, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AOIL           abandoned oil

OPT         AOIL-C         abandoned oil, completion type uncertain

OPT         AOIL-L         abandoned oil, location uncertain

OPT         AOIL-LC        abandoned oil, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         ASWD           abandoned salt water disposal

OPT         ASWD-C         abandoned salt water disposal, completion type uncertain

OPT         ASWD-L         abandoned salt water disposal, location uncertain

OPT         ASWD-LC        abandoned salt water disposal, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AWD            abandoned waste disposal

OPT         AWD-C          abandoned waste disposal, completion type uncertain

OPT         AWD-L          abandoned waste disposal, location uncertain

OPT         AWD-LC         abandoned waste disposal, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AWI            abandoned water injection

OPT         AWI-C          abandoned water injection, completion type uncertain

OPT         AWIG           abandoned gas, water injection

OPT         AWI-L          abandoned water injection, location uncertain

OPT         AWI-LC         abandoned water injection, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         AWIO           abandoned oil, water injection

OPT         AWIOG          abandoned oil and gas, water injection

OPT         BOR            other boring

OPT         BOR-L          other boring, location uncertain

OPT         CCB            confidential coal boring

OPT         CONF           confidential

OPT         CWO            confidential work over

OPT         DRY            dry hole

OPT         DRY-C          dry hole, completion type uncertain

OPT         DRY-L          dry hole, location and completion type uncertain

OPT         DRY-LC         abandoned dry, location and completion type uncertain

EXP         EXP            expired permit

GAS         GAS            gas

GS          GS             gas storage

GS          GSG            gas storage formerly gas

GS          GSO            gas storage formerly oil

OPT         LOC            location

OPT         MAP            nothing known, old Trenton well from map

OPT         NPWS           non-potable water supply

OPT         NPWSG          non-potable water supply, formerly gas

OPT         NPWSO          non-potable water supply, formerly oil

OIL         OAG            oil and gas

OPT         OBG            observation formerly gas

OPT         OBGS           observation formerly gas storage

OPT         OBS            observation

OIL         OIL            oil

OPT         PWS            potable water supply

GAS         SIG            shut-in gas

OPT         STRT           stratigraphic/structure test

GAS			TAGAS          temporarily abandoned gas

AGS			TAGS           temporarily abandoned gas storage

OPT			TANEW          temporarily abandoned new well

OPT			TAOBS          temporarily abandoned observation

OIL			TAOG           temporarily abandoned oil and gas

OIL			TAOIL          temporarily abandoned oil

OPT			TASTRT         temporarily abandoned stratigraphic/structure test

OPT			TASWD          temporarily abandoned salt water disposal

OPT			TAWD           temporarily abandoned waste disposal

OPT			TAWI           temporarily abandoned water injection

OPT			TAWS           temporarily abandoned non-potable water supply"
</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source citation should be included:
[PETROLEUM_WELLS_IGS_IN.SHP: Petroleum Well Locations in Indiana (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile), 20150108].

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and workmanship
for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana Geological Survey, 611 North
Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied, including, but not
limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability resulting from the use of this product is assumed
by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey
is not responsible for claims by a third party. The  maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20150108</metd>
    <metrd>20150130</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 5654</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It should not to be altered or summarized. IGS does
not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>