<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>United States Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>20020418</pubdate>
        <title>
LNDCV_USGS_IN: Land Cover in Indiana, Derived from the USGS, Version 06-03-99 (United
States Geological Survey, 30-Meter Grid)
</title>
        <edition>version 06-03-99</edition>
        <geoform>Map</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
          <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
        <lworkcit>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>USGS: USEPA</origin>
            <pubdate>19990603</pubdate>
            <title>National Land Cover Data</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </lworkcit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
LNDCV_USGS_IN is a grid showing land cover data in Indiana. This grid is a subset of the National
Land Cover Data (NLCD) set. There are eighteen categories of land use shown in this data set when
the associated *.avl is loaded.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
LNDCV_USGS_IN is a subset of the NLCD information. The NLCD created this dataset to provide updated
multipurpose land cover information.
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19780807</begdate>
          <enddate>19940916</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>data collection date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1607</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.6882</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7753</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7554</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>land use</themekey>
        <themekey>land cover</themekey>
        <themekey>Landsat</themekey>
        <themekey>National Land Cover Data</themekey>
        <themekey>NLCD</themekey>
        <themekey>USGS</themekey>
        <themekey>United States Geological Survey</themekey>
        <themekey>USEPA</themekey>
        <themekey>United States Environmental Protection Agency</themekey>
        <themekey>IGS</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
      <themekt>
Theme_Keyword  environment
Theme_Keyword  imageryBaseMapsEarthCover
</themekt>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>State Geologist</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Director</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>
Environmental Systems Research Institute's (ESRI's) ArcInfo
version 8.0.2 and ArcView 3.2
Windows 2000
ESRI grid format
</native>
    <useconst>Environment--Land_Cover_1992</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Accuracy assessment is pending (USGS)</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Not available</logic>
    <complete>Not available</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Not available</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Not available</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>USGS and USEPA joint effort</origin>
            <pubdate>19990603</pubdate>
            <title>National Land Cover Data (NLCD)</title>
            <edition>99-06</edition>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
The following information was extracted from information provided by the
U.S. Geological Survey --

National Land Cover Data
Indiana

Version 06-03-99
(Updated: December, 1998; June, 1999)

Introduction

This land cover data set was produced as part of a cooperative project
between the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) and the U.S. Environmental
Protection Agency (USEPA) to produce a consistent, land cover data layer
for the conterminous U.S. based on 30-meter Landsat thematic mapper (TM)
data.  National Land Cover Data (NLCD) was developed from TM data
acquired by the Multi-resolution Land Characterization (MRLC) Consortium.
The MRLC Consortium is a partnership of federal agencies that produce or
use land cover data.  Partners include the USGS (National Mapping,
Biological Resources, and Water Resources Divisions), USEPA, the U.S.
Forest Service, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.

Indiana

The Indiana NLCD set was produced as part of a project area encompassing
portions of Federal Region V, including the states of Illinois, Indiana,
Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin.  This data set was produced
under the direction of the MRLC Regional Land Cover Characterization
Project of the USGS EROS Data Center (EDC), Sioux Falls, SD.  Questions
about the data set can be directed to the MRLC Regional Team at
(605) 594-6114 or mrlc@edcmail.cr.usgs.gov.

Version/Revisions:

Version 98-12
-- Initial masking and distribution of the state of Indiana.

Version 99-06
-- Additional 300 meters of data (10 pixels) added beyond Indiana border
to facilitate creation of multi-state mosaics.

Projection Information:

The initial Landsat TM mosaics, all ancillary data sets, and the land cover
product are all map-registered to an Albers Conical Equal Area projection.
The following represents projection information for the final land cover
product for the state of Indiana.

Projection: Albers Conical Equal Area
Datum: NAD83
Spheroid: GRS80
Standard Parallels: 29.5 degrees North Latitude
45.5 degrees North Latitude
Central Meridian:  96 degrees  West Longitude
Origin of the Projection: 23 degrees North Latitude
False Easting:   0 meters
False Northing:  0 meters

Number of Lines (rows):  15757
Number of Samples (columns):  9184
Number of Bands: 1   Pixel size: 30 X 30 meters
Projection Coordinates (center of pixel, projection meters)
Upper Left Corner:  686850 meters(X),
2139030 meters(Y)
Lower Right Corner:   962340 meters(X),
1666350 meters(Y)

NOTE: Each state data set was extracted from the larger regional data set.
State boundaries from the USGS 1:100,000 Digital Line Graph (DLG) series
were used as the basis for extracting the state data.  In many instances, the
precision of the boundaries in the 1:100,000 DLG data does not match the
spatial precision of the Landsat TM data.  This is most apparent where state
boundaries follow small rivers.  To overcome the possibility of data being
lost in the extraction process, a 300 meter (10 pixel) buffer was added to the
state boundary used to extract the state data.

Data Sources:

The base data set for this project was leaves-off Landsat TM data,
nominal-1992 acquisitions.  Other ancillary data layers included leaves-on
TM, USGS 3-arc second Digital Terrain Elevation Data (DTED) and derived
slope, aspect and shaded relief, Bureau of the Census population and housing
density data, USGS land use and land cover (LUDA), and National Wetlands
Inventory (NWI) data if available.  Other additional data sets included
STATSGO soils information.

Landsat thematic mapper (TM) scenes:

Path   Row      Date
020    032      24-Dec-91
020    033      21-Oct-91
021    031      05-Apr-92
021    032      05-Apr-92
021    033      05-Apr-92
021    034      05-Apr-92
022    031      09-Nov-93
022    032      17-Nov-90
022    033      25-Mar-91
022    034      25-Mar-91

LEAF ON:
020    032      02-Oct-90
020    033      02-Oct-90
021    031      18-Sep-94
021    032      25-Aug-91
021    033      12-Sep-92
021    034      14-Oct-92
022    031      29-Aug-90
022    032      07-Aug-78
022    033      20-Jul-93
022    034      31-Jul-91

Caveats and Concerns:

1)  Quantitative accuracy checks have yet to be conducted.  We plan to make
comparisons with existing data sets in order to develop a general overview
regarding the quality of the land cover data set developed.  Feedback from
users of the data will be greatly appreciated.

Accuracy Assessment:

Accuracy assessment is pending.

23-Class National Land Cover Data Key:

NOTE - All Classes May NOT Be Represented in a specific state data set.
The class number represents the digital value of the class in the data set.

NLCD Land Cover Classification System Key - Rev. July 20, 1999

Water
11 Open Water
12 Perennial Ice/Snow

Developed
21 Low Intensity Residential
22 High Intensity Residential
23 Commercial/Industrial/Transportation

Barren
31 Bare Rock/Sand/Clay
32 Quarries/Strip Mines/Gravel Pits
33 Transitional

Forested Upland
41 Deciduous Forest
42 Evergreen Forest
43 Mixed Forest

Shrubland
51 Shrubland

Non-natural Woody
61 Orchards/Vineyards/Other

Herbaceous Upland
71 Grasslands/Herbaceous

Herbaceous Planted/Cultivated
81 Pasture/Hay
82 Row Crops
83 Small Grains
84 Fallow
85 Urban/Recreational Grasses

Wetlands
91 Woody Wetlands
92 Emergent Herbaceous Wetlands

NLCD Land Cover Classification System Land Cover Class Definitions

Water - All areas of open water or permanent ice/snow cover.

11.  Open Water - All areas of open water; typically 25 percent or greater
cover of water (per pixel).

12.  Perennial Ice/Snow - All areas characterized by year-long cover of ice
and/or snow.

Developed - Areas characterized by a high percentage (30 percent or greater)
of constructed materials  (e.g. asphalt, concrete, buildings, etc).

21.  Low Intensity Residential - Includes areas with a mixture of constructed
materials and vegetation.  Constructed materials account for 30-80 percent of
the cover. Vegetation may account for 20 to 70 percent of the cover.  These
areas most commonly include single-family housing units.  Population
densities will be lower than in high intensity residential areas.

22.  High Intensity Residential - Includes highly developed areas where
people reside in high numbers.  Examples include apartment complexes and
row houses.  Vegetation accounts for less than 20 percent of the cover.
Constructed materials account for 80 to100 percent of the cover.

23. Commercial/Industrial/Transportation  - Includes infrastructure (e.g.
roads, railroads, etc.) and all highly developed areas not classified as High
Intensity Residential.

Barren - Areas characterized by bare rock, gravel, sand, silt, clay, or other
earthen material, with little or no "green" vegetation present regardless  of its
inherent ability to support life. Vegetation, if present,  is more widely spaced
and scrubby than that in the "green" vegetated categories; lichen cover may be
extensive.

31.  Bare Rock/Sand/Clay - Perennially  barren areas of bedrock, desert
pavement, scarps, talus, slides, volcanic material, glacial debris, beaches, and
other accumulations of earthen material.

32.  Quarries/Strip Mines/Gravel Pits - Areas of  extractive mining activities
with significant surface expression.

33.  Transitional - Areas of sparse vegetative cover (less than 25 percent of
cover) that are dynamically changing from one land cover to another, often
because of land use activities.  Examples include forest clear cuts, a transition
phase between forest and agricultural land, the temporary clearing of
vegetation, and changes due to natural causes (e.g. fire, flood, etc.).

Forested Upland  - Areas characterized by tree cover (natural or semi-natural
woody vegetation, generally greater than 6 meters tall); tree canopy accounts
for 25-100 percent of the cover.

41.  Deciduous Forest - Areas dominated by trees where 75 percent or more
of the tree species shed foliage simultaneously in response to seasonal
change.

42.  Evergreen Forest - Areas dominated by trees where 75 percent or more of
the tree species maintain their leaves all year.  Canopy is never without green
foliage.

43.  Mixed Forest - Areas dominated by trees where neither deciduous nor
evergreen species represent more than 75 percent of the cover present.

Shrubland - Areas characterized by natural or semi-natural woody vegetation
with aerial stems, generally less than 6 meters  tall,  with individuals or
clumps not touching to interlocking.   Both evergreen and deciduous species
of  true shrubs, young trees, and trees or shrubs  that are small or stunted
because of environmental conditions are included.

51.  Shrubland - Areas dominated by shrubs; shrub canopy accounts for
25-100 percent of the cover.  Shrub cover is generally  greater than 25 percent
when tree cover is less than 25 percent.  Shrub cover may be less than 25
percent in cases when the cover of other life forms (e.g. herbaceous or tree) is
less than 25 percent and shrubs cover exceeds the cover of the other life
forms.

Non-natural Woody - Areas dominated by non-natural woody vegetation;
non-natural woody vegetative canopy accounts for 25-100 percent of the
cover.   The non-natural woody classification is subject to the availability of
sufficient ancillary data to differentiate non-natural woody vegetation from
natural woody vegetation.

61.  Orchards/Vineyards/Other - Orchards, vineyards, and other areas planted
or maintained for the production of fruits, nuts, berries, or ornamentals.

Herbaceous Upland - Upland areas characterized by natural or semi-natural
herbaceous vegetation; herbaceous vegetation accounts for 75-100 percent of
the cover.

71.  Grasslands/Herbaceous - Areas dominated  by upland grasses and forbs.
In rare cases, herbaceous cover is less than 25 percent, but exceeds the
combined cover of the woody species present.  These areas are not subject to
intensive management, but they are often utilized for  grazing.

Planted/Cultivated - Areas characterized by herbaceous vegetation that
has been planted or is intensively managed for the production of food, feed,
or fiber; or is maintained in developed settings for specific purposes.
Herbaceous vegetation accounts for 75-100 percent of the cover.

81.  Pasture/Hay - Areas of grasses, legumes, or grass-legume  mixtures
planted for livestock grazing or the production of seed or hay crops.

82. Row Crops - Areas used for the production of crops, such as corn,
soybeans, vegetables, tobacco, and cotton.

83.  Small Grains - Areas used for the production of graminoid crops such as
wheat, barley, oats, and rice.

84.  Fallow - Areas used for the production of crops that are temporarily
barren or with sparse  vegetative cover as a result of  being tilled in a
management practice that incorporates prescribed alternation between
cropping and tillage.

85.  Urban/Recreational Grasses - Vegetation (primarily grasses) planted in
developed settings for recreation, erosion control, or aesthetic purposes.
Examples include parks, lawns, golf courses, airport grasses, and industrial
site grasses.

Wetlands - Areas where the soil or substrate is periodically saturated with or
covered with water as defined by Cowardin et al.

91.  Woody Wetlands - Areas where forest or shrub land vegetation accounts
for 25-100 percent of the cover and  the soil or substrate is periodically
saturated with or covered with water.

92.  Emergent Herbaceous Wetlands - Areas where  perennial herbaceous
vegetation accounts for 75-100 percent of the cover and the soil or substrate
is periodically saturated with or covered with water.

General Procedures

Land Cover Characterization:

The project is being carried out on the basis of 10 Federal Regions that make
up the conterminous United States; each region is comprised of multiple
states; each region is processed in sub regional units that are limited to the
area covered by no more than 18 Landsat TM scenes. The general NLCD
procedure is to: (1) mosaic sub regional TM scenes and classify them using an
unsupervised clustering algorithm, (2) interpret and label the clusters/classes
using aerial photographs as reference data, (3) resolve the labeling of
confused clusters/classes using the appropriate  ancillary data source(s), and
(4) incorporate land cover information from other data sets and perform
manual edits to augment and refine the "basic" classification developed
above.

Two seasonally distinct TM mosaics are produced, a leaves-on version
(summer) and a leaves-off (spring/fall) version.  TM bands 3 4 5 and 7 are
mosaicked for both the leaves-on and leaves-off versions.  For mosaicking
purposes, a base scene is selected for each mosaic and the other scenes are
adjusted to mimic spectral properties of the base scene using histogram
matching in regions of spatial overlap.

Following mosaicking, either the leaves-off version or leaves-on version is
selected to be the "base" for the land cover mapping process.  The 4 TM
bands of the "base" mosaic are clustered to produce a single 100-class image
using an unsupervised clustering algorithm. Each of the spectrally distinct
clusters/classes is then assigned to one or more Anderson level 1 and 2 land
cover classes using National High Altitude Photography program (NHAP)
and National Aerial l Photography program (NAPP) aerial photographs as a
reference.  Almost invariably, individual spectral clusters/classes are
confused between two or more land cover classes.

Separation of the confused spectral clusters/classes into appropriate NLCD
class is accomplished using ancillary data layers.  Standard ancillary data
layers include: the "non-base" mosaic TM bands and 100-class cluster image;
derived TM normalized vegetation index (NDVI), various TM band ratios,
TM date bands; 3-arc second Digital Terrain Elevation Data (DTED) and
derived slope, aspect and shaded relief; population and housing density data;
USGS land use and land cover (LUDA); and National Wetlands Inventory
(NWI) data if available.  Other ancillary data sources may include soils data,
unique state or regional land cover data sets, or data from other federal
programs such as the National Gap Analysis Program (GAP) of the USGS
Biological Resources Division (BRD).  For a given confused spectral
cluster/class, digital values of the various ancillary data layers are compared
to determine: (1) which data layers are the most effective for splitting the
confused cluster/class into the appropriate NLCD class, and (2) the
appropriate layer thresholds for making the split(s).  Models are then
developed using one to several ancillary data layers to split the confused
cluster/class into the NLCD class.  For example, a population density
threshold is used to separate high-intensity residential areas from
commercial/industrial/transportation.  Or a cluster/class might be confused
between row crop and grasslands.  To split this particular cluster/class, a TM
NDVI threshold might be identified and used with an elevation threshold in a
class-splitting model to make the appropriate NLCD class assignments.  A
purely spectral example is using the temporally opposite TM layers to
discriminate confused cluster/classes such as hay pasture vs. row crops and
deciduous forests vs. evergreen forests; simple thresholds that contrast the
seasonal differences in vegetation between leaves-on vs. leaves-off.

Not all cluster/class confusion can be successfully modeled out.  Certain
classes such as urban/recreational grasses or quarries/strip mines/gravel pits
that are not spectrally unique require manual editing.  These class features are
typically visually identified and then reclassified using on-screen digitizing
and recoding.  Other classes such as wetlands require the use of specific data
sets such as NWI to provide the most accurate classification.  Areas lacking
NWI data are typically subset out and modeling is used to estimate wetlands
in these localized areas.  The final NLCD product results from the
classification (interpretation and labeling) of the 100-class "base” cluster
mosaic using both automated and manual processes, incorporating both
spectral and conditional data layers.  For a more detailed explanation please
see Vogelmann et al. 1998 and Vogelmann et al. 1998.

Accuracy Assessment:

An accuracy assessment is done on all NLCD on a Federal Region basis
following a revision cycle that incorporates feedback from MRLC
Consortium partners and affiliated users.  The accuracy assessments are
conducted by private sector vendors under contract to the USEPA.  A
protocol has been established by the USGS and USEPA that incorporates a
two-stage, geographically stratified cluster sampling plan (Zhu et al., 1999)
utilizing National Aerial Photography Program (NAPP) photographs as the
sampling frame and the basic sampling unit.  In this design a NAPP
photograph is defined as a 1st stage or primary sampling unit (PSU), and a
sampled pixel within each PSU is treated as a 2nd stage or secondary
sampling unit (SSU).

PSU's are selected from a sampling grid based on NAPP flight-lines and
photo centers, each grid cell measures 15' X 15' (minutes of
latitude/longitude) and consists of 32 NHAP photographs.  A geographically
stratified random sampling is performed with 1 NAPP photo being randomly
selected from each cell (geographic strata), if a sampled photo falls outside of
the regional boundary it is not used.  Second stage sampling is accomplished
by selecting SSU's (pixels) within each PSU (NAPP photo) to provide the
actual locations for the reference land cover classification.

The SSU's are manually interpreted and misclassification errors are estimated
and described using a traditional error matrix as well as a number of other
important measures including the overall proportion of pixels correctly
classified, user's and producer's accuracies, and omission and commission
error probabilities.

Discussion:

While we believe that the approach taken has yielded a very good general
land cover classification product for a large region, it is important to indicate
to the user where there might be some potential problems.  The biggest
concerns are listed below:

1)  Some of the TM data sets are not temporally ideal. Leaves-off data sets
are heavily relied upon for discriminating between hay/pasture and row crop,
and also for discriminating between forest classes.  The success of
discriminating between these classes using leaves-off data sets hinges on the
time of data acquisition.  When hay/pasture areas are non-green, they are not
easily distinguishable from other agricultural areas using remotely sensed
data.  However, there is a temporal window during which hay and pasture
areas green up before most other vegetation (excluding evergreens, which
have different spectral properties); during this window these areas are easily
distinguishable from other crop areas. The discrimination between
hay/pasture and deciduous forest is likewise optimized by selecting data in
a temporal window  where deciduous vegetation has yet to leaf out. It is
difficult to acquire a single-date of imagery (leaves-on or leaves-off) that
adequately differentiates between both deciduous/hay and pasture and
hay-pasture/row crop.

2)  The data sets used cover a range of years (see data sources), and changes
that have taken place across the landscape over the time period may not have
been captured.  While this is not viewed as a major problem for most classes,
it is possible that some land cover features change more rapidly than might be
expected (e.g. hay one year, row crop the next).

3)  Wetlands classes are extremely difficult to extract from Landsat TM
spectral information alone.  The  use of ancillary information such as
National Wetlands Inventory (NWI) data is highly desirable.  We relied on
GAP, LUDA, or proximity to streams and rivers as well as spectral data to
delineate wetlands in areas without NWI data.

4) Separation of natural grass and shrub is problematic. Areas observed on
the ground to be shrub or grass are not always distinguishable spectrally.
Likewise, there was often disagreement between LUDA and GAP on these
classes.

Acknowledgments

This work was performed by the Raytheon STX Corporation under U.S.
Geological Survey Contract 1434-CR-97-CN-40274.

References

More detailed information on the methodologies and techniques employed in
this work can be found in the following:

Kelly, P.M., and White, J.M., 1993. Preprocessing remotely sensed data for
efficient analysis and classification, Applications of Artificial Intelligence
1993: Knowledge-Based Systems in Aerospace and Industry, Proceeding of
SPIE, 1993, 24-30.

Cowardin, L.M., V. Carter, F.C. Golet, and E.T. LaRoe, 1979. Classification
of Wetlands and Deepwater Habitats of the United States, Fish and Wildlife
Service, U.S. Department of the Interior, Washington, D.C.

Vogelmann, J.E., Sohl, T., and Howard, S.M., 1998. "Regional
Characterization of Land Cover Using Multiple Sources of Data."
Photogrammetric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing, Vol. 64, No. 1,  pp. 45-47.

Vogelmann, J.E., Sohl, T., Campbell, P.V., and Shaw, D.M., 1998. "Regional
Land Cover Characterization Using Landsat Thematic Mapper Data and
Ancillary Data Sources." Environmental Monitoring and Assessment, Vol.
51, pp. 415-428.

Zhu, Z., Yang, L., Stehman, S., and Czaplewski, R., 1999. "Designing an
Accuracy Assessment for USGS Regional Land Cover Mapping Program."
(In review) Photogrametric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Grid</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>Unknown</begdate>
              <enddate>Unknown</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Unknown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>None</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Land cover data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>USDA - NRCS</origin>
            <pubdate>19991001</pubdate>
            <title>Indiana Land Cover Data</title>
            <edition>99-06</edition>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <lworkcit>
              <citeinfo>
                <origin>USGS</origin>
                <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
                <title>National Land Cover Data</title>
                <pubinfo>
                  <pubplace>Not available</pubplace>
                  <publish>Not available</publish>
                </pubinfo>
              </citeinfo>
            </lworkcit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Grid</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>Unknown</begdate>
              <enddate>Unknown</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Unknown</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>None</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Land cover data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The original image in Albers was broken into six approximately equal sections (two columns by
three rows) and each sub-grid was projected separately. Then ESRI ArcInfo's ADDIMAGE command was used to
recreate the statewide UTM-based grid.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NLCD</srcused>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Bruce Nielsen</cntper>
              <cntorg>USDA -NRCS</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6013 Lakeside Blvd.</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46278</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-290-3200-x349</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>317-290-3225</cntfax>
            <cntemail>bruce.nielsen@in.usda.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>

1) The statewide image was converted into a grid using ESRI ArcInfo's IMAGEGRID
command with the default settings.
2) This grid was then clipped using the coverage INCLP83, containing the area
within the state of Indiana, which was compiled at a scale of 1:24,000.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>NLCD</srcused>
        <procdate>20020321</procdate>
        <srcprod>LNDCV_USGS_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>awalls@exchange.indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit) and
MP (Metadata Parser) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20020523</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>awalls@exchange.indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
      <rowcount>14818</rowcount>
      <colcount>9621</colcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>lndcv_usgs_in.vat</enttypl>
        <enttypd>GRID Value Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Pixel value</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software generated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>0</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>11</edomv>
            <edomvd>Open Water</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>21</edomv>
            <edomvd>Low Intensity Residential</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>22</edomv>
            <edomvd>High Intensity Residential</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>23</edomv>
            <edomvd>Commercial/Industrial/Transportation</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>31</edomv>
            <edomvd>Bare rock/Sand/Clay</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>32</edomv>
            <edomvd>Quarries/Strip Mines/Gravel Pits</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>33</edomv>
            <edomvd>Transitional</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>41</edomv>
            <edomvd>Deciduous Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>42</edomv>
            <edomvd>Evergreen Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>43</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mixed Forest</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>51</edomv>
            <edomvd>Shrubland</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>71</edomv>
            <edomvd>Grasslands/Herbaceous</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>81</edomv>
            <edomvd>Pasture/Hay</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>82</edomv>
            <edomvd>Row Crops</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>83</edomv>
            <edomvd>Small Grains</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>85</edomv>
            <edomvd>Urban/Recreational Grasses</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>91</edomv>
            <edomvd>Woody Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>92</edomv>
            <edomvd>Emergent Herbaceous Wetlands</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>No Data</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>USGS</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Count</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Number of pixels with same value</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Software generated</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Software computed</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
WARRANTY
Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208,
and it will be replaced free of charge.
LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY
Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020417</metd>
    <metrd>20020523</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>awalls@exchange.indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>