<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Office of Water Quality</origin>
        <pubdate>20131008</pubdate>
        <title>NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN: Facilities in the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Point Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Office of Water Quality</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This data set was provided to personnel of the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) by Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Office of Water
Quality personnel on December 12, 2002. The data set provided was in an ESRI shapefile format, and was named "A-NPDES-FACILITY."

It was subsequently updated on October 8, 2013 by IDEM OLQ personnel, and was provided as an ESRI geodatabase point feature class named "ICIS_FACILITIES."
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/LayerGallery.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN is a point shapefile that contains National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) Program Facilities in Indiana, provided
by personnel of Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Office of Water Quality (IDEM, OWQ) as of October 8, 2013. The most recent update provided
by IDEM was an ESRI point feature class named "ICIS_FACILITIES." NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN is attributed with facility information, contact information, and
addresses. Facility information and locational coordinates were originally obtained by IDEM from the Environnmental Protection Agency (EPA) Integrated
Compliance Information System (ICIS) database (website location: http://www.epa.gov/compliance/data/systems/icis/).

NOTE: The original feature class named "ICIS_FACILITIES" provided by IDEM contains many attribute records that do not contain location and coordinate
system information. There are a total of 1,792 attribute records provided in this data layer. Of those, a total of only 1,441 records contain locational
information and are displayed in a spatial map view. The remaining 351 records have been retained in the attribute table to aid users of these data in
performing environmental accessments in the state of Indiana.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDEM, OWQ for the source feature class ICIS_FACILITIES:

"The data set provides an important map layer for the Indiana Department of Environmental Management staff in
conducting environmental assessments as well as a direct source or contact and mailing information. Although
the database record set depicts all available information on regulated wastewater discharge sites as of the date
of extraction, the locational and coordinate information is not complete, therefore queries and other searches
are best handled through the attribute tables rather than from visually on maps where not all sites are represented.

This database is extracted from the national EPA Integrated Compliance Information System (ICIS) database and
includes all available records listed in Indiana associated with "Active" surface water discharges. It consists
of primarily of state permitted and regulated wastewater facility related information. The files are point locations
and are projected into a UTM NAD83 zone 16 North coordinate system. Facility name, contacts, and a variety of mailing
addresses are included for each permit along with locational data as available. Additionally, records for Stormwater
permits under Rule 6, stormwater associated with industrial activities, have been appended into the tables."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
This data set was developed to provide accurate coordinate information for employees and customers of the Indiana Department of Environmental Management
to conduct environmental assessments and to obtain locations and contact information for permitted and regulated wastewater facilities in Indiana.
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDEM, OWQ for the previously published source shapefile A-NPDES-FACILITY:

"The primary block of data centers on state regulated Wastewater facility permits discharging into surface water bodies under the
National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System program, but does include many 'Rule 6' stormwater permits. Treatment plant records
for which there are locational coordinates have mostly been collected using 5 meter mapping grade GPS field units. Other locational
coordinates have been either map interpolated from USGS 1:24,000 topographical quadrangle maps or were provided as unverified numeric
information by teh regulated facility or it's representative. Locations for the stormwater permits were provided by the facility and
have not been verified."
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20131008</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.25</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.56</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.92</northbc>
        <southbc>37.59</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Environmental Management (IDEM)</themekey>
        <themekey>Office of Water Quality (OWQ)</themekey>
        <themekey>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</themekey>
        <themekey>Integrated Compliance Information System (ICIS)</themekey>
        <themekey>National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES)</themekey>
        <themekey>water quality</themekey>
        <themekey>regulated facilities</themekey>
        <themekey>stormwater</themekey>
        <themekey>wastewater</themekey>
        <themekey>point source</themekey>
        <themekey>water pollution</themekey>
        <themekey>treatment plant</themekey>
        <themekey>pollution</themekey>
        <themekey>point dischargers</themekey>
        <themekey>wastewater treatment plant (WWTP)</themekey>
        <themekey>sewage treatment plant (STP)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Midwest</placekey>
        <placekey>EPA Region 5</placekey>
        <placekey>Environmental Protection Agency Region 5</placekey>
        <placekey>Great Lakes</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio River</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash River</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>La Porte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcGIS version 10.2 shapefile format, approximately XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX Mb</native>
    <useconst>Environment--Waste_Water_NPDES_Facilities</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
This data set was provided by IDEM OWQ personnel. IDEM OWQ personnel downloaded the data found in the source feature class named "ICIS_FACILTIES" from the
Environnmental Protection Agency (EPA) Integrated Compliance Information System (ICIS) database (website location: http://www.epa.gov/compliance/data/systems/icis/).
This data has been compiled for many years from many different sources. Therefore various levels of qualitative accuracy are present in this data set.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
This data set was provided by IDEM personnel and is assumed to be as accurate as the data stored on the Environnmental Protection Agency (EPA) Integrated Compliance
Information System (ICIS) database (website location: http://www.epa.gov/compliance/data/systems/icis/).
</logic>
    <complete>
This data set consists of locations of facilities contained within the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) within the state of Indiana.
This data set is incomplete and personnel at a time previous to publication. However the data set may be incomplete and/or inaccurate due to the ever-changing
status of managed facilities and sites, and due to the data collection and processing efforts of IDEM staff. It is an ever-changing work in progress.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDEM, OWQ for the source feature class ICIS_FACILITIES:

"This data has been compiled over a long period of time from a wide range of sources. Recent efforts are geared
towards using GPS mapping grade units to collect accurate locations at +/- 5 meters. Some other records are map
interpolated from 1:24,000 USGS Topographical Quadrangle maps, and lastly some records still reflect coordinates
provided by unknown sources. All stormwater locations were provided by outside sources and have not been verified
in any way."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDEM, OWQ for the source feature class ICIS_FACILITIES:

"No attempt to collect or maintain vertical information on these sites at this time."
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>IDEM Office of Water Quality</origin>
            <pubdate>20131008</pubdate>
            <title>ICIS_FACILITIES (ESRI file geodatabase point feature class)</title>
            <edition>1</edition>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>IDEM OWQ</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
IGS personnel requested locational information for various environmental GIS data in Indiana from IDEM, OWQ personnel.
On December 12, 2002, Kevin Miller (IDEM, OLQ) provided a CD-ROM that contained the shapefile A-NPDES-FACILITY. E.J. McNaughton (IDEM OLQ)
subsequently provided an update for these data to IGS personnel on October 08, 2013, as an ESRI file geodatabase point feature class named
"ICIS_FACILITIES."
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>ESRI file geodatabase point feature class</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20131008</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Based on metadata provided by IDEM, OWQ for the source data named ICIS_FACILITIES.</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ICIS_FACILITIES (ESRI file geodatabase point feature class)</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Facilities in the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) in Indiana</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Field inspectors were trained in the use of Trimble Inc. GeoExplorer 2 hand-held mapping grade GPS equipment by an in-house trainer to ensure consistancy
in data collection and processing techniques. All units use a standardized Data Dictionary (feature attribute tables) to collect coordinates during routine
inspection trips. Field files are then sent to the office for post-processing by one individual and incorporated into MicroSoft Access data tables.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>GPS field data, NPDES permits, permit applications, correspondence, USGS Topo maps, etc.</srcused>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <srcprod>PCS, owm-pcs.mdb, pcs-facilty.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
              <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46206-6015</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
            <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
            <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
            <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm EST, Monday - Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>N/A</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
MS Access database tables composed of individual GPS records for point locations associated with NPDES permitted facilities and outfalls are checked for proper
ID values matching known permits, any edit changes to data records are made, and then coordinate values in degrees, minutes, seconds are calculated. Records are
evaluated to see if they meet the requirements for input into the EPA mainframe system.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
              <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46206-6015</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
            <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
            <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
            <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm, Monday - Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>N/A</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Locational coordinates and all other field data are hand entered into the EPA mainframe computer database system titled the Permit Compliance System (PCS) in Raliegh, NC.
Fields are checked and updated whenever new information becomes available.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
              <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46206-6015</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
            <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
            <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
            <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm, Monday - Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>N/A</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
PCS database records are downloaded via ASCII undelimited text files and imported into a MS Access 97 database. Coordinate data is converted back to decimal degrees and then
original GPS coordinates overwrite those calculated values were appropriate. Also field collection metadata fields are added to the datatables and data appended from field tables
where available.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
              <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46206-6015</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
            <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
            <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
            <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm, Monday - Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>N/A</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Access database tables are exported into generic DBase table format then added to ESRI ArcGIS map software. The tables are used to create map feature shapefiles from the coordinate
information. The files are finally saved as point shapefiles in the ArcGIS format and metadata added.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>Not complete</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
              <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46206-6015</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
            <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
            <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
            <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
            <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm, Monday - Friday</hours>
            <cntinst>N/A</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
IGS personnel received an ESRI point shapefile named A-NPDES-FACILITY from IDEM personnel on December 12, 2002. A-NPDES-FACILITY was loaded
into ESRI ArcView 3.3 and the following fields were deleted from the associated attribute table: FNORTHING, LAT_D, LAT_M, LAT_S, LAT_DS,
FEASTING, LON_D, LON_M, LON_S, LON_DS, ACCURACY_D, DATUM_DESC, SCALE_DESC, FLAT_DD, FLON_DD, LGND_SORT, LEGEND1, NORTHING, EASTING, and
DESCRIPTIO. The shapefile was also visually checked to insure that all data points provided actually fell within the accepted IGS state boundary.

NOTE: 3234 points were deleted from the A-NPDES-FACILITY.DBF because there were no associated UTM values represented in the shapefile. IGS personnel
then saved the edited shapefile as NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN.

It should also be noted that portions of the associated metadata provided by IDEM for A-NPDES-FACILITY were extracted and included in this metadata file.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>A-NPDES-FACILITY.SHP</srcused>
        <procdate>20021216</procdate>
        <srcprod>NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
IGS personnel received an ESRI file geodatabase point feature class named "ICIS_FACILITIES" from IDEM personnel on October 8, 2013. ICIS_FACILITIES was loaded
into ESRI ArcMap 10.2 to be visually inspected to insure that all data points provided actually fell within the state boundary of Indiana. The following
attribute fields were deleted from the associated attribute table: CURMAJMINS, HORIZACCUR, REFPTDESC, GEOMTYPEDE, SRCMAPSCAL, PRIMFACSIC, and PERMITTYPE.

NOTE: There are a total of 1,792 attribute records provided in this data layer. Of those, a total of only 1,441 records contain locational information and
are displayed in a spatial map view. It should also be noted that portions of the associated metadata provided by IDEM for ICIS_FACILITIES were extracted and
included in this metadata file.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>ICIS_FACILITIES (ESRI file geodatabase point feature class)</srcused>
        <procdate>20131008</procdate>
        <srcprod>NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20131025</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1792</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NPDES_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Identification number for individual records, composed of two digit state id, 1 digit permit code, and 6 digit number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FACNAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Common name associated with the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FACTYPECOD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Coded value describing the type of facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FACTYPEDES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Description of the general category in which the owning entity of the facility falls</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>City Government</edomv>
            <edomvd>Municipally Owned</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Federal Facility (U.S. Government)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Federally owned and operated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Mixed Ownership (e.g., Public/Private)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Privately owned but servicing the general public; subdivisions, mobile home parks, etc.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Municipal or Water District</edomv>
            <edomvd>Municipally Owned</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Privately Owned Facility</edomv>
            <edomvd>Privately owned</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>State Government</edomv>
            <edomvd>State owned and operated</edomvd>
            <edomvds>IDEM</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERMITSTAT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Status of the facilities IDEM permit (Admin Continued, Effective, Expired, Not Needed, Pending, or Terminated)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTLAVGFLO</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Total average volume of wastewater the treatment plant handles (Millions of gallons per day)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>812.5643</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Millions of gallons per day</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTALDSGNF</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Generally the maximum volume of wastewater the treatment plant was designed to handle</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1095</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Millions of gallons per day</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LOCATEADDR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street address of the actual field location of the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SUPPLMENTLA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Supplemental information aiding the address location of the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CITY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>City where the facility is located or where mail is processed</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATECODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State abbreviation (IN = Indiana)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ZIP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Zip code for the facility address or where mail is processed</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>N/A</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Zip code</udom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrmfrq>As needed</attrmfrq>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTYNAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of the county in Indiana in which the facility is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ISSUEDATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date on which the permit was issued</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>4/12/1973</rdommin>
            <rdommax>5/7/2010</rdommax>
            <attrunit>standard date format (dd/mm/yyyy)</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EFFECTIVED</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The date on which the permit was deemed effective</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>6/1/1973</rdommin>
            <rdommax>6/1/2010</rdommax>
            <attrunit>standard date format (dd/mm/yyyy)</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EXPIRATION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The date on which the permit was deemed expired</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>12/31/1974</rdommin>
            <rdommax>5/31/2015</rdommax>
            <attrunit>standard date format (dd/mm/yyyy)</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DDLATITUDE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Locational value of Latitude for the facility (units are Decimal Degrees, coordinate system unknown)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DDLONGITUD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Locational value of Longitude for the facility (units are Decimal Degrees, coordinate system unknown)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HORIZCOLLM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Description of the method used to collect the locational information of the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HORIZREFDA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Description of the coordinate system datum for the locational information of the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATEWATER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Description or accepted name of the water body (river, stream, lake, etc.) that recieves the discharge from the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DMRCOGNIZA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of the person officially authorized by permit holder as the responsible party or cognizant official for the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DMRCOGNOFF</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Phone number of the cognizant official for the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PRIMFACS_1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Description of the primary function of the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERMITTY_1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Notes pertaining to the permit, or changes made to permit for the facility</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDEM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Department of Environmental Management, Office of Water Quality be cited in any products generated from this data. The
following source citation should be included: [NPDES_FACILITY_IDEM_IN: Facilities in the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System in Indiana (Indiana
Department of Environmental Management, Point Shapefile), 2013]

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or
damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party.
The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>IDEM Office of Water Quality</cntorg>
          <cntper>Jeffrey A. Ewick</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Manager / OWQ GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>100 North Senate Avenue, P.O. Box 6015</address>
          <city>Indianapolis</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>46206-6015</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>317-233-0676</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>N/A</cnttdd>
        <cntfax>317-232-8406</cntfax>
        <cntemail>jewick@dem.state.in.us</cntemail>
        <hours>8:30 am - 5:00 pm EST, Monday - Friday</hours>
        <cntinst>For inquiries, please e-mail.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDEM, OLQ for the originally provided source shapefile A-NPDES-FACILITY:

"DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES

THE INDIANA DEPARTMENT OF ENVIRONMENTAL MANAGEMENT (IDEM), ITS EMPLOYEES, SUCCESSORS OR ASSIGNS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS
OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE COMPLETENESS, SUITABILITY, RELIABILITY, AVAILABILITY AND ACCURACY OF DATA, SOFTWARE, INFORMATION
OR SERVICES PROVIDED.

TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, ANY INFORMATION RETRIEVED FROM OR DELIVERED TO AN INDIVIDUAL OR ENTITY
THROUGH THE AUSPICES OF IDEM ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" AND INCLUDES ALL FAULTS WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY
OF ANY KIND.  THE RECIPIENT, OF THE DATA, SOFTWARE, INFORMATION OR SERVICES, ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT IT HAS RECEIVED
ADEQUATE NOTICE THAT USE OF THE DATA, SOFTWARE, INFORMATION OR SERVICES IS AT RECIPIENTS OWN RISK.

IDEM AND OR ITS RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS WITH REGARD TO THE AFOREMENTIONED MATERIAL,
INCLUDING WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, TITLE, NONINFRINGEMENT, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, LACK OF VIRUSES, ACCURACY
OR COMPLETENESS OF RESPONSES, RESULTS, LACK OF NEGLIGENCE OR LACK OF WORKMANLIKE EFFORT, QUIET ENJOYMENT, QUIET POSSESSION,
AND CORRESPONDENCE TO DESCRIPTION. FURTHER THE ABOVE LIST OF DISCLAIMED WARRANTIES IS NOT EXHAUSTIVE AS ANY AND ALL WARRANTIES
AND CONDITIONS ARE DISCLAIMED. THE ENTIRE RISK ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF OR PERFORMANCE OF THE DATA, SOFTWARE, INFORMATION
OR SERVICES IS BORNE BY THE RECIPIENT.

EXCLUSION OF INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL AND CERTAIN OTHER DAMAGES.

TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, IN NO EVENT SHALL IDEM OR ITS SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL,
INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, DAMAGES FOR: LOSS OF PROFITS,
LOSS OF CONFIDENTIAL OR OTHER INFORMATION, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, PERSONAL INJURY, LOSS OF PRIVACY, FAILURE TO MEET ANY
DUTY (INCLUDING GOOD FAITH AND REASONABLE CARE), NEGLIGENCE, AND ANY OTHER PECUNIARY OR OTHER LOSS WHATSOEVER, ARISING
OUT OF  OR IN ANY WAY RELATED TO THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE, THE DATA, SOFTWARE, INFORMATION OR SERVICES, EVEN IF THE
RECIPIENT IS ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.  RECIPIENT'S SOLE REMEDY IS TO DISCONTINUE THE USE OF THE DATA,
SOFTWARE, INFORMATION OR SERVICES."
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20021212</metd>
    <metrd>20131025</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGS. It should not to be altered or summarized. IGS
does not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>