<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>TrueWind Solutions, LLC (data creator)</origin>
        <origin>Michael Brower (data creator)</origin>
        <origin>National Renewable Energy Laboratory (data creator)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Commerce (data provider)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey (metadata creator)</origin>
        <origin>Denver Harper (metadata creator)</origin>
        <origin>Chris Dintaman (metadata creator)</origin>
        <pubdate>20070905</pubdate>
        <title>
WINDSPD50_IN: Mean Wind Speed at Height of 50 Meters above Ground, Derived from Mesoscale Atmospheric Simulation
System and WindMap (TrueWind Solutions, 200-Meter Grid)
</title>
        <edition>1</edition>
        <geoform>Raster digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
Brower, Michael, 2004, Wind energy resource maps of Indiana: unpublished report to the Indiana Department of Commerce
prepared by TrueWind Solutions, LLC, 11 p.

The above unpublished report is included in the downloadable file for this layer as a PDF file named "IndianaWindMappingReport.pdf."

This raster layer is one of a set of six showing mean wind speeds and mean wind power at various heights above the
ground. The six layers are named "WINDSPD30_IN," "WINDSPD50_IN," "WINDSPD70_IN," "WINDSPD100_IN," "WINDPWR50_IN," and
"WINDPWR100_IN."
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
The following is excerpted from an unpublished report by Michael Brower (2004):

"Using the MesoMap system, TrueWind has produced maps of mean wind speed in Indiana for heights of 30, 50, 70, and 100 m above
ground, as well as a map of wind power at 50 m. TrueWind has also produced data files of the predicted wind speed frequency
distribution and speed and energy by direction. The maps and data files are provided on a CD with the ArcReader software, which
will enable users to view, print, copy, and query the maps and wind rose data.

"The MesoMap system consists of an integrated set of atmospheric simulation models, databases, and computers and storage systems.
At the core of MesoMap is MASS (Mesoscale Atmospheric Simulation System), a numerical weather model, which simulates the physics
of the atmosphere. MASS is coupled to a simpler wind flow model, WindMap, which is used to refine the spatial resolution of MASS
and account for localized effects of terrain and surface roughness. MASS simulates weather conditions over a region for 366
historical days randomly selected from a 15-year period. When the runs are finished, the results are input into WindMap. In this
project, the MASS model was run on a grid spacing of 1.7 km and WindMap on a grid spacing of 200 m.

"The wind maps show that the best wind resource in Indiana is found in the northcentral part of the state. The mean wind speed at
50 m height between Indianapolis, Kokomo, and Lafayette, and to the northwest of Lafayette, is predicted to be in the range of
6.5 to 7 m/s, and the mean wind power is predicted to be about 250 to 350 W/m2, or NREL class 2 to 3. In the rest of northern
Indiana, the wind speed tends to be around 0.5 m/s lower, and the wind power is a solid class 2. In southern Indiana, a wind
speed of 4.5 to 6 m/s and a wind power class of 1 to 2 prevails. The main reason for this wind resource distribution pattern is
that the land is much more forested in the southern half of the state than in the northern half. Topography also plays a role, as
does the track of the jet stream."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
The following is excerpted from an unpublished report by Michael Brower (2004):

"The Indiana Department of Commerce is interested in assessing the wind resource of Indiana and finding suitable sites for wind
energy projects. Conventional field techniques of wind resource assessment can be time consuming, however, and often depend heavily
on local meteorological expertise as well as the availability of reliable and representative wind measurements. Conventional wind
flow models, on the other hand, have often proven inaccurate in complex wind regimes, and even in moderate terrain their accuracy
can decline substantially with distance from the nearest available reference mast.

"Mesoscale-microscale modeling techniques offer a solution to these challenges. By combining a sophisticated numerical weather
model capable of simulating large-scale wind patterns with a microscale wind flow model responsive to local terrain and surface
conditions, they enable the mapping of wind resources over large regions with much greater accuracy than has been possible in the
past. In addition, they do not require surface wind data to make reasonably accurate predictions. While on-site measurements are
still required to confirm the predicted wind resource at any particular location, mesoscale-microscale modeling can greatly
reduce the time and cost to identify and evaluate potential wind project sites.

"The objective of the current project was to use MesoMap to create high-resolution wind resource maps of Indiana and to provide
wind resource data in a format enabling the Indiana Department of Commerce to assess potential sites in a GIS. These objectives
have been met. In the following sections, we describe the MesoMap system and mapping process in detail; how MesoMap was applied
in this project; the validation process and results; the final wind maps and data files; and guidelines for the use of the maps."
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
The following is excerpted from an unpublished report by Michael Brower (2004):

"The MesoMap system has three main components: models, databases, and computer systems.

"At the core of the MesoMap system is MASS (Mesoscale Atmospheric Simulation System), a numerical weather model that has been
developed over the past 20 years by TrueWind partner MESO, Inc., both as a research tool and to provide commercial weather
forecasting services. MASS simulates the fundamental physics of the atmosphere including conservation of mass, momentum, and
energy, as well as the moisture phases, and it contains a turbulent kinetic energy module that accounts for the effects of
viscosity and thermal stability on wind shear. As a dynamical model, MASS simulates the evolution of atmospheric conditions in
time steps as short as a few seconds. This creates great computational demands, especially when running at high resolution.
Hence MASS is usually coupled to a simpler but much faster program, WindMap, a mass-conserving wind flow model. Depending on
the size and complexity of the region and requirements of the client, WindMap is used to improve the spatial resolution of the
MASS simulations to account for the local effects of terrain and surface roughness variations.

"The MASS model uses a variety of online, global, geophysical and meteorological databases. The main meteorological inputs are
reanalysis data, rawinsonde data, and land surface measurements. The reanalysis database – the most important – is a gridded
historical weather data set produced by the US National Centers for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) and National Center for
Atmospheric Research (NCAR). The data provide a snapshot of atmospheric conditions around the word at all levels of the atmosphere
in intervals of six hours. Along with the rawinsonde and surface data, the reanalysis data establish the initial conditions as
well as updated lateral boundary conditions for the MASS runs. The MASS model itself determines the evolution of atmospheric
conditions within the region based on the interactions among different elements in the atmosphere and between the atmosphere
and the surface. Because the reanalysis data are on a relatively coarse, 200 km grid, MASS is run in several nested grids of
successfuly finer mesh size, each taking as input the output of the previous nest, until the desired grid scale is reached. This
is to avoid generating noise at the boundaries that can result from large jumps in grid cell size. The outermost grid typically
extends several thousand kilometers.

"The main geophysical inputs are elevation, land cover, vegetation greenness (normalized differential vegetation index, or
NDVI), soil moisture, and sea-surface temperatures. The global elevation data normally used by MesoMap were produced by the
US Geological Survey in a gridded digital elevation model, or DEM, format from a variety of data sources.1 The US Geological
Survey, the University of Nebraska, and the European Commission’s Joint Research Centre (JRC) produced the global land cover
data in a cooperative project. The land cover classifications are derived from the interpretation of Advanced Very High
Resolution Radiometer (AVHRR) data – the same data used to calculate the NDVI. The model translates both land cover and
NDVI data into physical parameters such as surface roughness, albedo, and emissivity. The nominal spatial resolution of
all of these data sets is 1 km. Thus, the standard output of the MesoMap system is a 1 km gridded wind map. However, much
higher resolution maps can be produced where the necessary topographical and land cover data are available. In the United
States, the resolution is typically 100 to 400 m.

"The MesoMap system creates a wind resource map in several steps. First, the MASS model simulates weather conditions over
366 days selected from a 15-year period. The days are chosen through a stratified random sampling scheme so that each month
and season is represented equally in the sample; only the year is randomized. Each simulation generates wind and other weather
variables (including temperature, pressure, moisture, turbulent kinetic energy, and heat flux) in three dimensions throughout
the model domain, and the information is stored at hourly intervals. When the runs are finished, the results are compiled into
summary data files, which are then input into the WindMap program for the final mapping stage. The two main products are
usually (1) color-coded maps of mean wind speed and power density at various heights above ground and (2) data files containing
wind speed and direction frequency distribution parameters. The maps and data can then be compared with land and ocean surface
wind measurement, and if significant discrepancies are observed, adjustments to the wind maps can be made."
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20040315</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Data publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.687570</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.223033</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.086677</northbc>
        <southbc>37.434122</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Metadata Service Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>energy</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL)</themekey>
        <themekey>TrueWind Solutions</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Commerce</themekey>
        <themekey>MesoMap</themekey>
        <themekey>atmosphere</themekey>
        <themekey>atmospheric simulation</themekey>
        <themekey>alternative energy</themekey>
        <themekey>wind map</themekey>
        <themekey>wind energy</themekey>
        <themekey>wind speed</themekey>
        <themekey>wind resource</themekey>
        <themekey>wind power</themekey>
        <themekey>wind</themekey>
        <themekey>Geographic Information System (GIS)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dekalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.780, ESRI raster grid, 20.1 MB.</native>
    <useconst>Environment--Wind_Speed_50m</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The following is excerpted from an unpublished report by Michael Brower (2004):

"In collaboration with the National Renewable Energy Laboratory, TrueWind subsequently validated the wind maps using data
from 22 stations. The data were first extrapolated to a height of 50 m. The predicted wind speeds are on average about
0.3 m/s higher than the observed/extrapolated speeds. The root-mean-square discrepancy is 0.6 m/s, or about 10% of the
average of all the stations. After accounting for uncertainty in the data, we estimated the map error margin (one sigma)
to be 0.5 m/s, or 8.5%. The error margin in meters/second is comparable to that obtained in other MesoMap projects, but
in percentage terms it is somewhat larger than usual. This is mainly because of the moderate average speed (5.9 m/s at
50 m) of the Indiana stations. In addition, the validation sample includes data from five stations which have rather
low mean speeds compared to other stations in their vicinity. If these stations are excluded, the mean bias becomes
0.1 m/s, and the rms discrepancy becomes 0.4 m/s, or 6%, which is comparable to the error margin of the data.

"While the validation confirmed the overall accuracy of the maps, it also revealed some areas where MesoMap appears to have
either underestimated or overestimated the wind resource to a moderate degree. With the agreement of NREL, we adjusted the
predicted wind speed and power in parts of central and southwestern Indiana."

See the file "IndianaWindMappingReport.pdf" for additional information.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Not available</logic>
    <complete>Not available</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>See the file "IndianaWindMappingReport.pdf" for information regarding accuracy.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>See the file "IndianaWindMappingReport.pdf" for information regarding accuracy.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>TrueWind Solutions, LLC, and Indiana Department of Commerce</origin>
            <pubdate>20040315</pubdate>
            <title>Wind energy resource maps</title>
            <geoform>Raster digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Albany, New York</pubplace>
              <publish>AWS TrueWind, LLC</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>http://www.awstruewind.com/inner/windmaps/Indiana.htm</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20040315</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Data publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Six raster layers - "WINDSPD30_IN," "WINDSPD50_IN," "WINDSPD70_IN," "WINDSPD100_IN," "WINDPWR50_IN," and "WINDPWR100_IN"</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Six raster layers showing mean wind speeds and mean wind power at various heights above the ground.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Personnel of the Indiana Geological Survey received six raster layers from Paul Cummings of the Indiana Department of Commerce.
The six layers were renamed to match naming standards of the Indiana Geological Survey.
The layers were reprojected from GCS WGS 1984 to Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM), Zone 16, NAD83.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>in_spd30m, in_spd50m, in_spd70m, in_spd100m, in_pwr50m, in_pwr100m</srcused>
        <procdate>20070905</procdate>
        <srcprod>WINDSPD30_IN, WINDSPD50_IN, WINDSPD70_IN, WINDSPD100_IN, WINDPWR50_IN, WINDPWR100_IN</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>
cdintama@indiana.edu
Contact_Website: http://igs.indiana.edu/
</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit v 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser v 2.7.1) software
written by Peter N. Schweitzer (U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20070905</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>GIS Specialist/Geologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 - 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday - Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
      <rowcount>2566</rowcount>
      <colcount>1847</colcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.001024</absres>
            <ordres>0.001024</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>WINDSPD50_IN.VAT</enttypl>
        <enttypd>GRID Value Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mean wind speed at a height of 50 meters above ground</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TrueWind Solutions</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>3.455393076</rdommin>
            <rdommax>7.946171284</rdommax>
            <attrunit>Meters per second</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is required that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The following source
citation must be included: WINDSPD50_IN: Mean Wind Speed at Height of 50 Meters above Ground, Derived from Mesoscale
Atmospheric Simulation System and WindMap (TrueWind Solutions, 200-Meter Grid).

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be
free from defect in materials and workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove,
Bloomington, Indiana 47405 2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or
conditions, expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability
to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the
user. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product users indirect, incidental,
special, or consequential damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or
damaged data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey is not responsible
for claims by a third party. The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount
paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20070905</metd>
    <metrd>20070905</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Denver Harper</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 1369</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>
dharper@indiana.edu
Contact_Website: http://igs.indiana.edu/
</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC-CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received
from the IGS. It is not to be altered or summarized. IGS does not support secondary distribution. If this data
set was received from anyone other than the IGS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>