<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.pasda.psu.edu/pasda/uci_metadata/dtd/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</origin>
        <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
        <geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Pittsburgh, PA</pubplace>
          <publish>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <title>Allegheny County - Soils</title>
        <ftname Sync="TRUE">AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000</ftname>
        <othercit>Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Allegheny County, Pennsylvania

Identification_Information: 
Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: 20060914 
Title: 
Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database for Allegheny County, Pennsylvania 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Fort Worth, Texas 
Publisher: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Other_Citation_Details: pa003 
Online_Linkage: URL:&lt;http://SoilDataMart.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt; 
Description: 
Abstract: 
This data set is a digital soil survey and generally is the most detailed level of soil geographic data developed by the National Cooperative Soil Survey. The information was prepared by digitizing maps, by compiling information onto a planimetric correct base and digitizing, or by revising digitized maps using remotely sensed and other information. 
This data set consists of georeferenced digital map data and computerized attribute data. The map data are in a soil survey area extent format and include a detailed, field verified inventory of soils and miscellaneous areas that normally occur in a repeatable pattern on the landscape and that can be cartographically shown at the scale mapped. A special soil features layer (point and line features) is optional. This layer displays the location of features too small to delineate at the mapping scale, but they are large enough and contrasting enough to significantly influence use and management. The soil map units are linked to attributes in the National Soil Information System relational database, which gives the proportionate extent of the component soils and their properties. 

Purpose: 
SSURGO depicts information about the kinds and distribution of soils on the landscape. The soil map and data used in the SSURGO product were prepared by soil scientists as part of the National Cooperative Soil Survey. 
Supplemental_Information: 
Digital versions of hydrography, cultural features, and other associated layers that are not part of the SSURGO data set may be available from the primary organization listed in the Point of Contact. 
Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Range_of_Dates/Times: 
Beginning_Date: 20060914 
Ending_Date: 20060914 
Currentness_Reference: publication date 
Status: 
Progress: Complete 
Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency: As needed 
Spatial_Domain: 
Bounding_Coordinates: 
West_Bounding_Coordinate: -80.361 
East_Bounding_Coordinate: -79.689 
North_Bounding_Coordinate: 40.674 
South_Bounding_Coordinate: 40.194 
Keywords: 
Theme: 
Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus: None 
Theme_Keyword: soil survey 
Theme_Keyword: soils 
Theme_Keyword: Soil Survey Geographic 
Theme_Keyword: SSURGO 
Place: 
Place_Keyword_Thesaurus: USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) 
Place_Keyword: Pennsylvania 
Place_Keyword: Allegheny County 
Place_Keyword: Aliquippa Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Ambridge Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Baden Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Braddock Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Bridgeville Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Canonsburg Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Clinton Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Curtisville Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Donora Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Emsworth Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Freeport Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Glassport Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Glenshaw Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Mars Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: McKeesport Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Monongahela Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Murrysville Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: New Kensington East Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: New Kensington West Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Oakdale Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Pittsburgh East Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Pittsburgh West Quadrangle 
Place_Keyword: Valencia Quadrangle 
Access_Constraints: None 
Use_Constraints: 
The U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service, should be acknowledged as the data source in products derived from these data. 
This data set is not designed for use as a primary regulatory tool in permitting or citing decisions, but may be used as a reference source. This is public information and may be interpreted by organizations, agencies, units of government, or others based on needs; however, they are responsible for the appropriate application. Federal, State, or local regulatory bodies are not to reassign to the Natural Resources Conservation Service any authority for the decisions that they make. The Natural Resources Conservation Service will not perform any evaluations of these maps for purposes related solely to State or local regulatory programs. 

Photographic or digital enlargement of these maps to scales greater than at which they were originally mapped can cause misinterpretation of the data. If enlarged, maps do not show the small areas of contrasting soils that could have been shown at a larger scale. The depicted soil boundaries, interpretations, and analysis derived from them do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling, testing, and detailed study of specific sites for intensive uses. Thus, these data and their interpretations are intended for planning purposes only. Digital data files are periodically updated. Files are dated, and users are responsible for obtaining the latest version of the data. 

For educational/demonstration purposes only.  The Originator, Publisher and Distributor exclude any and all implied warranties and make no warranty or representation with respect to the data files or accompanying documentation, including quality, performance, merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. These data files and documentation are provided 'as is' and the User assumes the entire risk as to their quality and performance.

Point_of_Contact: 
Contact_Information: 
Contact_Organization_Primary: 
Contact_Organization: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Contact_Position: State Soil Scientist 
Contact_Address: 
Address_Type: mailing and physical address 
Address: USDA - Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Address: Pennsylvania State Office 
Address: One Credit Union Place, Suite 340 
City: Harrisburg 
State_or_Province: PA 
Postal_Code: 17110-2993 
Contact_Voice_Telephone: 717-237-2207 
Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone: (202) 720-2600 
Contact_Facsimile_Telephone: 717 237 2238 
Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address: ed.white@pa.usda.gov 

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Data_Quality_Information: 
Attribute_Accuracy: 
Attribute_Accuracy_Report: 
Attribute accuracy is tested by manual comparison of the source with hard copy plots and/or symbolized display of the map data on an interactive computer graphic system. Selected attributes that cannot be visually verified on plots or on screen are interactively queried and verified on screen. In addition, the attributes are tested against a master set of valid attributes. All attribute data conform to the attribute codes in the signed classification and correlation document and amendment(s). 
Logical_Consistency_Report: 
Certain node/geometry and topology GT- polygon/chain relationships are collected or generated to satisfy topological requirements (the GT-polygon corresponds to the soil delineation). Some of these requirements include: chains must begin and end at nodes, chains must connect to each other at nodes, chains do not extend through nodes, left and right GT-polygons are defined for each chain element and are consistent throughout, and the chains representing the limits of the file are free of gaps. The tests of logical consistency are performed using vendor software. All internal polygons are tested for closure with vendor software and are checked on hard copy plots. All data are checked for common soil lines (i.e., adjacent polygons with the same label). Edge locations generally do not deviate from centerline to centerline by more than 0.01 inch. 
The Soil Survey of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania is edge matched to the adjacent SSURGO (Soil SURvey GeOgraphic) certified Pennsylvania Soil Surveys of Beaver and Lawrence Counties, Greene and Washington Counties, Butler County, Armstrong County and Westmoreland County. 

The northeast corner of Allegheny County is joined to the southwest corner of Armstrong County. All of the feature edges for this soil survey match the feature edges in the Butler County Soil Survey. Most of the feature edges for this soil survey match the feature edges in the other adjacent soil surveys. Some of the labels for this soil survey match the labels in the adjacent soil surveys. 

The soil survey boundary for Allegheny County matches the soil survey boundaries of the adjacent certified soil surveys. 

Completeness_Report: 
A map unit is a collection of areas defined and named in terms of their soil components or miscellaneous areas or both. Each map unit differs in some respect from all others in a survey area and each map unit has a symbol that uniquely identifies the map unit on a soil map. Each individual area, point, or line so identified on the map is a delineation. 
Soil Scientists identify small areas of soils or miscellaneous areas that have properties and behavior significantly different than the named soils in the surrounding map unit. These minor components may be indicated as special features. If they have a minimal effect on use and management, or could not be precisely located, they may not be indicated on the map. 

A map unit has specified kinds of soils or miscellaneous areas (map unit components), each with a designated range in proportionate extent. Map units include one or more kinds of soil or miscellaneous area. Miscellaneous areas are areas that have little or no recognizable soil. 

Specific National Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures were used in the classification of soils, design and name of map units, and location of special soil features. These standards are outlined in Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, NRCS; Agricultural Handbook 436, Soil Taxonomy, 1995, USDA, NRCS; and all Amendments; Keys to Soil Taxonomy, (current issue) USDA, NRCS; National Soil Survey Handbook, title 430-VI,(current issue) USDA, NRCS. 

The actual composition and interpretive purity of the map unit delineations were based on data collected by scientists during the course of preparing the soil maps. Adherence to National Cooperative Soil Survey standards and procedures is based on peer review, quality control, and quality assurance. Quality control is outlined in the memorandum of understanding for the soil survey area and in documents that reside with the Natural Resources Conservation Service state soil scientist. Four kinds of map units are used in soil surveys: consociations, complexes, associations, and undifferentiated groups. 

Consociations - Consociations are named for the dominant soil. In a consociation, delineated areas use a single name from the dominant component in the map unit. Dissimilar components are minor in extent. The soil component in a consociation may be identified at any taxonomic level. Soil series is the lowest taxonomic level. A consociation that is named as a miscellaneous area is dominantly that kind of area and minor components do not significantly affect the use of the map unit. The total amount of dissimilar inclusions of other components in a map unit generally does not exceed about 15 percent if limiting and 25 percent if nonlimiting. A single component of a dissimilar limiting inclusion generally does not exceed 10 percent if very contrasting. 

Complexes and associations - Complexes and associations consist of two or more dissimilar components that occur in a regularly repeating pattern. The total amount of other dissimilar components is minor extent. The following arbitrary rule determines whether complex or association is used in the name. The major components of an association can be separated at the scale of mapping. In either case, because the major components are sufficiently different in morphology or behavior, the map unit cannot be called a consociation. In each delineation of a complex or an association, each major component is normally present though their proportions may vary appreciably from one delineation to another. The total amount of inclusions in a map unit that are dissimilar to any of the major components does not exceed 15 percent if limiting and 25 percent if nonlimiting. A single kind of dissimilar limiting inclusion usually does not exceed 10 percent. 

Undifferentiated groups - Undifferentiated groups consist of two or more components that are not consistently associated geographically and, therefore, do not always occur together in the same map delineation. These components are included in the same named map unit because their use and management are the same or very similar for common uses. Generally they are grouped together because some common feature, such as steepness, stoniness, or flooding, determines their use and management. If two or more additional map units would serve no useful purpose, they may be included in the same unit. Each delineation has at least one of the major components, and some may have all of them. The same principles regarding the proportion of minor components that apply to consociations also apply to undifferentiated groups. The same principles regarding proportion of inclusion apply to undifferentiated groups as to consociations. 

Minimum documentation consists of three complete soil profile descriptions that are collected for each soil added to the legend, one additional per 3,000 acres mapped; three 10 observation transects for each map unit, one additional 10 point transect per 3,000 acres. 

A defined standard or level of confidence in the interpretive purity of the map unit delineations is attained by adjusting the kind and intensity of field investigations. Field investigations and data collection are carried out in sufficient detail to name map units and to identify accurately and consistently areas of about 5 acres. 

Positional_Accuracy: 
Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy: 
Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy_Report: 
The accuracy of these digital data is based upon their compilation to base maps that meet National Map Accuracy Standards at a scale of 1 inch equals 1,000 feet. The difference in positional accuracy between the soil boundaries and special soil features locations in the field and their digitized map locations is unknown. The locational accuracy of soil delineations on the ground varies with the transition between map units. 
For example, on long gently sloping landscapes the transition occurs gradually over many feet. Where landscapes change abruptly from steep to level, the transition will be very narrow. Soil delineation boundaries and special soil features generally were digitized within 0.01 inch of their locations on the digitizing source. The digital map elements are edge matched between data sets. The data along each quadrangle edge are matched against the data for the adjacent quadrangle. Edge locations generally do not deviate from centerline to centerline by more than 0.01 inch. 

Lineage: 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: 1981 
Title: Soil Survey for Allegheny County, Pennsylvania 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: atlas 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Washington, D.C. 
Publisher: U.S. Government Printing Office 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 15840 
Type_of_Source_Media: paper 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 1981 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: SCS1 
Source_Contribution: 
basic reference material about soils and landscapes 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: unpublished material 
Title: publication annotation overlays 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: map 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 15840 
Type_of_Source_Media: stable-base material 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 1981 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date of the soil survey 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS1 
Source_Contribution: 
final publication negatives used to develop ratioed film positives 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: unpublished material 
Title: 
ratioed film positives of the publication annotation overlays 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: map 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: stable-base material 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 1981 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date of the soil survey 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS2 
Source_Contribution: reference material for line placement 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: U.S. Geological Survey 
Publication_Date: 1950-1998 
Title: multiple 7.5 minute topographic quadrangles 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: map 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Reston, Virginia 
Publisher: U.S. Geological Survey 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: paper 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Range_of_Dates/Times: 
Beginning_Date: 1950 
Ending_Date: 1998 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: USGS1 
Source_Contribution: landscape shape, aspect, and slope reference 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: U.S. Geological Survey 
Publication_Date: 1992-1994 
Title: multiple digital orthophotographic quadrangles (DOQs) 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: remotely sensed image 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Reston, Virginia 
Publisher: U.S. Geological Survey 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: stable-base material 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Range_of_Dates/Times: 
Beginning_Date: 1992 
Ending_Date: 1994 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: USGS2 
Source_Contribution: base maps for compilation 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: unpublished material 
Title: multiple annotated compilation overlays 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: map 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: stable-base material 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Range_of_Dates/Times: 
Beginning_Date: 1992 
Ending_Date: 1999 
Source_Currentness_Reference: dates of recompilation 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS3 
Source_Contribution: 
stable-base compilation sheets containing soil delineations and special feature locations 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: unpublished material 
Title: multiple characterization and statistical data 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: map 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: paper 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 2006 
Source_Currentness_Reference: download date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS4 
Source_Contribution: 
attribute information for soil map unit delineations, special feature locations, and data on soil properties 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: 2006 
Title: ARCGIS geodatabase for Allegheny County, Pennsylvania 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: vector digital data 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: University Park, Pennsylvania 
Publisher: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service, Pennsylvania Map Compilation and Digitizing Center 
Source_Scale_Denominator: 24000 
Type_of_Source_Media: online 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 2006 
Source_Currentness_Reference: date of publication 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS5 
Source_Contribution: source for soil survey edits 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: 2006 
Title: 
National Soil Information System (NASIS) database for Allegheny County, Pennsylvania 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: tabular digital data 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Fort Collins, Colorado 
Publisher: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service, Information Technology Center 
Type_of_Source_Media: online 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Single_Date/Time: 
Calendar_Date: 2006 
Source_Currentness_Reference: export certification date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS6 
Source_Contribution: 
tabular soil property data linked to spatial soil data 
Source_Information: 
Source_Citation: 
Citation_Information: 
Originator: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Publication_Date: 2006 
Title: National Soil Information System (NASIS) data base 
Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: tabular digital data 
Publication_Information: 
Publication_Place: Fort Collins, Colorado 
Publisher: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Type_of_Source_Media: database 
Source_Time_Period_of_Content: 
Time_Period_Information: 
Range_of_Dates/Times: 
Beginning_Date: 2006 
Ending_Date: 2006 
Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date 
Source_Citation_Abbreviation: NASIS 
Source_Contribution: attribute (tabular) information 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The Northeast Technical Service Center approved the Classification and Correlation of the Soils of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania in July, 1973. The Soil Survey of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania was published in 1981 at a scale of 1:15840. The published soil survey was considered to be an acceptable compilation source by the Pennsylvania Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) soil scientists. Ratioed film positives of the publication annotation overlays were produced at the scale of 1:24000. The soil boundaries were manually compiled on a stable-base film registered to a 7.5 minute quadrangle orthophotograph. Pennsylvania soil scientists used photographic interpretation of orthophotographs, topographic quadrangles and the ratioed film positives of the published soil survey as a reference for soil line placement. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: 
SCS1, NRCS1, NRCS2, NRCS3, USGS1 USGS2 
Process_Date: 1999 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The annotated compilation overlays were raster scanned by Midwest Graphics Inc. at 300 dpi on a drum scanner. Four control points corresponding to the four corners of the quadrangle were used for registration during data collection. The soil scientists and cartographic technicians at the Pennsylvania NRCS Map Compilation and Digitizing Center used the LT4X software for soil data development, which included raster editing, map neatline development, vector conversion, labeling, edge matching and vector editing. The cleaned vector files were imported into the ARC/INFO Version 8 software for final plotting, edit checks, and error analysis. The quadrangle coverages were then joined together into a seamless county coverage. Polygon attributes were checked against the correlation legend. The limit of the soil survey was adjusted to match the DOQ imagery. The adjacent soil surveys in digital format were joined, edited and clipped out to provide a common county boundary among the soil surveys. The data were created and maintained in North American Datum 1983. Statistics on map unit acreages were generated and checked with the correlation legend and tabular data. The tables containing the soil attributes and interpretations were downloaded from the State Survey Database or the National Soil Information System (NASIS) database where appropriate. The soil scientists and cartographic technicians at the Pennsylvania NRCS Map Compilation Center did a 100 percent quality review of the digitized product. The MLRA Region 13 Office Team Leader in Morgantown, West Virginia certified the digitizing on March 8, 2006. The ARCGIS geodatabase for the Allegheny County Soil Survey was posted on the Pennsylvania NRCS Map Compilation and Digitizing Center website. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS3, NRCS4, NRCS5, USGS2 
Process_Date: 2006 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The National Soil Information System (NASIS) database was developed by NRCS soil scientists according to national standards. The MIDU staff provided the Pennsylvania State Soil Scientist with the map unit symbols and acreages from the spatial data. Amendment 2 was drafted to add 10 soil mapping units and 3 miscellaneous land types. Amendment 3 was drafted to correct the slope phase of a soil mapping unit. The soil scientists used the map unit acreages from the digital soil survey as a guide to populate the NASIS database. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS6 
Process_Date: 2006 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The MIDU staff downloaded the ARCGIS geodatabase for the Allegheny County Soil Survey from the Pennsylvania NRCS Map Compilation and Digitizing Center website. The soils and special soil features (point and linear) in the geodatabase were converted to ARC/INFO coverages. The MIDU staff checked the soil survey coverages with a set of ARC Macro Language (AML) programs developed by NCGC. The soil survey coverages were processed using the January 2006 SSURGO Certification AML programs for seamless projects. These ARC/INFO programs identified areas within the coverages that needed revision. The data were edited. The Pennsylvania NRCS soil scientists supplied the SSURGO download from NASIS. The minor codes in the soils coverages were replaced with the map unit key codes to link the map units in the spatial data to the NASIS database. Upon successful completion of the SSURGO Evaluation, the area symbol was added to each feature in the soil survey coverages with the att_check.aml program. The county coverages and the metadata were electronically transferred to the NRCS Staging Server to be joined with the tabular data. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: NRCS5, NRCS6 
Process_Date: 2006 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or delegate, upon completion of data quality verification, determined that the tabular data should be released for official use. A selected set of map units and components in the soil survey legend was copied to a staging database, and rating values for selected interpretations were generated. The list of selected interpretations is stored in the database table named sainterp. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: NASIS 
Process_Date: 20060914 
Process_Step: 
Process_Description: 
The Natural Resources Conservation Service State Soil Scientist or delegate verified that the labels on the digitized soil map units link to map units in the tabular database, and certified the joined data sets for release to the Soil Data Warehouse. A system assigned version number and date stamp were added and the data were copied to the data warehouse. The tabular data for the map units and components were extracted from the data warehouse and reformatted into the soil data delivery data model, then stored in the Soil Data Mart. The spatial data were copied to the Soil Data Mart without change. 
Source_Used_Citation_Abbreviation: NASIS 
Process_Date: 20060914 

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Spatial_Data_Organization_Information: 
Direct_Spatial_Reference_Method: Vector 

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Spatial_Reference_Information: 
Horizontal_Coordinate_System_Definition: 
Geographic: 
Latitude_Resolution: 0.0000001 
Longitude_Resolution: 0.0000001 
Geographic_Coordinate_Units: decimal degrees 
Geodetic_Model: 
Horizontal_Datum_Name: North American Datum of 1983 
Ellipsoid_Name: Geodetic Reference System 80 
Semi-major_Axis: 6378137.0 
Denominator_of_Flattening_Ratio: 298.257 

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Entity_and_Attribute_Information: 
Detailed_Description: 
Entity_Type: 
Entity_Type_Label: Special Soil Features 
Entity_Type_Definition: 
Special Soil Features represent soil, miscellaneous area, or landform features that are too small to be digitized as soil delineations (area features). 
Entity_Type_Definition_Source: Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS. 
Attribute: 
Attribute_Label: Special Soil Features Codes 
Attribute_Definition: 
Special Soil Features labels represent specific Special Soil Features. These features are identified with a descriptive label. The label is assigned to the point or line assigned to represent the feature on maps. 
Attribute_Definition_Source: 
Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS; National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647 (current issue), USDA, NRCS. 
Attribute_Domain_Values: 
Codeset_Domain: 
Codeset_Name: 
Classification and Correlation of the Soils of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania 
Codeset_Source: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Overview_Description: 
Entity_and_Attribute_Overview: 
Map Unit Delineations are closed polygons that may be dominated by a single soil or miscellaneous area component plus allowable similar or dissimilar soils, or they can be geographic mixtures of groups of soils or soils and miscellaneous areas. 
The map unit symbol uniquely identifies each closed map unit delineation. Each symbol corresponds to a map unit name. The map unit key is used to link to information in the National Soil Information System tables. 

Map Unit Delineations are described by the National Soil Information System database. This attribute database gives the proportionate extent of the component soils and the properties for each soil. The database contains both estimated and measured data on the physical and chemical soil properties and soil interpretations for engineering, water management, recreation, agronomic, woodland, range, and wildlife uses of the soil. 

The National Soil Information System database contains static metadata. It documents the data structure and includes such information as what tables, columns, indexes, and relationships are defined as well as a variety of attributes of each of these database objects. Attributes include table and column descriptions and detailed domain information. 

The National Soil Information System database also contains a distribution metadata. It records the criteria used for selecting map units and components for inclusion in the set of distributed data. 

Special features are described in the feature table. It includes an area symbol, feature label, feature name, and feature description for each special and ad hoc feature in the survey area. 

Entity_and_Attribute_Detail_Citation: 
Soil Taxonomy: A basic system of soil classification for making and interpreting soil surveys. Agricultural Handbook 436, 1999, USDA, SCS. 
Keys to Soil Taxonomy (current issue), USDA, SCS. 

National Soil Survey Handbook, Title 430-VI, part 647 (current issue), USDA, NRCS. 

Agricultural Handbook 18, Soil Survey Manual, 1993, USDA, SCS. 


--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Distribution_Information: 
Distributor: 
Contact_Information: 
Contact_Organization_Primary: 
Contact_Organization: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service, National Cartography and Geospatial Center 
Contact_Address: 
Address_Type: mailing and physical address 
Address: 501 West Felix Street, Building 23, P.O. Box 6567 
City: Fort Worth 
State_or_Province: Texas 
Postal_Code: 76115 
Contact_Voice_Telephone: 800 672 5559 
Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone: 202 720 2600 
Contact_Facsimile_Telephone: 817 509 3469 
Resource_Description: Allegheny County, Pennsylvania SSURGO 
Distribution_Liability: 
Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the Agency regarding the utility of the data on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will warrant the delivery of this product in computer readable format, and will offer appropriate adjustment of credit when the product is determined unreadable by correctly adjusted computer input peripherals, or when the physical medium is delivered in damaged condition. Request for adjustment of credit must be made within 90 days from the date of this shipment from the ordering site. 
The U.S. Department of Agriculture, nor any of its agencies are liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of these data sets. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits discrimination in all its programs and activities on the basis of race, color, national origin, sex, religion, age, disability, political beliefs, sexual orientation, or marital or family status. (Not all prohibited bases apply to all programs.) 

Standard_Order_Process: 
Digital_Form: 
Digital_Transfer_Information: 
Format_Name: ARC/INFO coverage 
Format_Information_Content: spatial 
Transfer_Size: 29.8 
Digital_Transfer_Option: 
Offline_Option: 
Offline_Media: CD-ROM 
Recording_Format: ISO 9660 Level 2 
Digital_Form: 
Digital_Transfer_Information: 
Format_Name: ArcView shapefile 
Format_Information_Content: spatial 
Transfer_Size: 27.3 
Digital_Transfer_Option: 
Offline_Option: 
Offline_Media: CD-ROM 
Recording_Format: ISO 9660 Level 2 
Digital_Form: 
Digital_Transfer_Information: 
Format_Name: ASCII 
Format_Information_Content: keys and attributes 
Transfer_Size: 17.1 
Digital_Transfer_Option: 
Online_Option: 
Computer_Contact_Information: 
Network_Address: 
Network_Resource_Name: URL:&lt;http://SoilDataMart.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt; 
Access_Instructions: 
Select desired survey area at above Internet Web site. An email address is required for receipt of instructions on retrieval via anonymous FTP. Anticipate a delay between submission of request at Web site and receipt of email message. 
Fees: 
There is currently no direct charge for requesting data or for retrieval via FTP. 
Ordering_Instructions: 
Visit the above mentioned Internet Web Site, select state or territory, then select individual soil survey area of interest. Spatial line data and locations of special feature symbols are in ESRI ArcGIS (ArcView,ArcInfo) shapefile, coverage and interchange (i.e., export) formats. The National Soil Information System (NASIS) attribute soil data are available in variable length, pipe delimited, ASCII file format. 
Turnaround: Typically within four hours 

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Metadata_Reference_Information: 
Metadata_Date: 20060914 
Metadata_Contact: 
Contact_Information: 
Contact_Organization_Primary: 
Contact_Organization: 
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Contact_Position: State Soil Scientist 
Contact_Address: 
Address_Type: mailing and physical address 
Address: USDA - Natural Resources Conservation Service 
Address: Pennsylvania State Office 
Address: One Credit Union Place, Suite 340 
City: Harrisburg 
State_or_Province: PA 
Postal_Code: 17110-2993 
Contact_Voice_Telephone: 717-237-2207 
Contact_TDD/TTY_Telephone: (202) 720-2600 
Contact_Facsimile_Telephone: 717 237 2238 
Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address: ed.white@pa.usda.gov 
Metadata_Standard_Name: Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata 
Metadata_Standard_Version: FGDC-STD-001-1998</othercit>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>2002</begdate>
          <endtime>2002</endtime>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>creation date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc Sync="TRUE">-80.368656</westbc>
        <eastbc Sync="TRUE">-79.676224</eastbc>
        <northbc Sync="TRUE">40.682989</northbc>
        <southbc Sync="TRUE">40.184955</southbc>
      </bounding>
      <lboundng>
        <leftbc Sync="TRUE">1242196.875000</leftbc>
        <rightbc Sync="TRUE">1430465.927339</rightbc>
        <bottombc Sync="TRUE">320925.848882</bottombc>
        <topbc Sync="TRUE">497577.718750</topbc>
      </lboundng>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>GeoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekey>PA</placekey>
        <placekey>Allegheny County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pittsburgh</placekey>
        <placekey>Clairton</placekey>
        <placekey>Duquesne</placekey>
        <placekey>McKeesport</placekey>
        <placekey>Southwest PA</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Call for Details</accconst>
    <useconst>All parties acknowledge that the data is for informational purposes only. The existing digital data is shipped as is and there is no guarantee as to its completeness or accuracy. Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group is not responsible for any reliance upon said data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>621 County Office Building</address>
          <address>542 Forbes Ave.</address>
          <city>Pittsburgh</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>15219</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(412) 350-4774</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(412) 350-4754</cntfax>
        <cntemail>GIShelp@alleghenycounty.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.1.1332</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</origin>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform>
    <descript>
      <abstract>AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Data is based on other GIS data developed and maintained by Allegheny County GIS Staff.</logic>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Data is based on county base data horizontal positional accuracy</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Data is based on county base data vertical positional accuracy</vertaccr>
        <qvertpa>
        </qvertpa>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <othercit>Data was created in ArcInfo Coverages.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Windows NT Server</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2002</begdate>
              <endtime>2002</endtime>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccontr>http://soildatamart.nrcs.usda.gov/Download.aspx?Survey=PA003&amp;UseState=PA</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>During Y2K efforts of 1999-2000, data was transferred to Microsoft NT Server running ArcInfo 7 and was made available to county users across the network from a single location.</procdesc>
        <procdate>2000</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>1361 tiles were edgematched to create a single seamless County coverage</procdesc>
        <procdate>2000-2003</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Shapefiles were created from ArcInfo Coverages.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc Sync="TRUE">Metadata imported.</procdesc>
        <srcused Sync="TRUE">W:\1metadata\template.xml</srcused>
        <date Sync="TRUE">20060905</date>
        <time Sync="TRUE">15352200</time>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm Name="AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000">
        <sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">27044</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1756</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Label point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>30990</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
      <esriterm Name="AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000">
        <efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp>
        <efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom>
        <esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo>
        <efeacnt Sync="TRUE">27044</efeacnt>
        <spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex>
        <linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer>
      </esriterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <planci>
          <plance Sync="TRUE">coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</absres>
            <ordres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu Sync="TRUE">survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn Sync="TRUE">Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll Sync="TRUE">39.933333</stdparll>
            <stdparll Sync="TRUE">40.966667</stdparll>
            <longcm Sync="TRUE">-77.750000</longcm>
            <latprjo Sync="TRUE">39.333333</latprjo>
            <feast Sync="TRUE">1968500.000000</feast>
            <fnorth Sync="TRUE">0.000000</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
      <cordsysn>
        <geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn>
        <projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Pennsylvania_South_FIPS_3702_Feet</projcsn>
      </cordsysn>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed Name="AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000">
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl Sync="TRUE">AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000</enttypl>
        <enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt>
        <enttypc Sync="TRUE">27044</enttypc>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth>
        <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
        <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
        <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth>
        <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
        <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
        <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom Sync="TRUE">Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">AREA</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">AREA</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth>
        <atnumdec Sync="TRUE">5</atnumdec>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">PERIMETER</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth>
        <atnumdec Sync="TRUE">5</atnumdec>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SOILS_</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">SOILS_</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">11</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SOILS_ID</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">SOILS_ID</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">11</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">MINOR1</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">MINOR1</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">6</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SOIL_CODE</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">SOIL_CODE</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">ACRES</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth>
        <atnumdec Sync="TRUE">3</atnumdec>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">CLASS</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SUBCLASS</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">SUBCLASS</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">CAPABILITY</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">CAPABILITY</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">16</attwidth>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntpos>GIS Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>621 County Office Building</address>
          <address>542 Forbes Avenue</address>
          <city>Pittsburgh</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>15219-2952</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>412 350-4774</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>412 350-4754</cntfax>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Call for details.</resdesc>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <transize>66.284</transize>
          <dssize Sync="TRUE">26.050</dssize>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
      <ordering>Call for Details</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd Sync="TRUE">20080310</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntpos>System Supervisor, GIS</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>621 County Office Building</address>
          <address>524 Forbes Avenue</address>
          <city>Pittsburgh</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>15219-2952</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>412 350-4774</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>412 350-4754</cntfax>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Allegheny County Division of Computer Services Geographic Information Systems Group</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
    <langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta>
    <metextns>
      <onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <Esri>
    <ModDate>20080310</ModDate>
    <ModTime>12172900</ModTime>
    <MetaID>{C8730A12-25CB-498C-B232-20CF7C690C24}</MetaID>
    <CreaDate>20060905</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>15352200</CreaTime>
    <SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce>
    <SyncDate>20080310</SyncDate>
    <SyncTime>12172900</SyncTime>
  </Esri>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20080310</mdDateSt>
  <dataIdInfo>
    <envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.1.1332</envirDesc>
    <dataLang>
      <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en">
      </languageCode>
    </dataLang>
    <idCitation>
      <resTitle Sync="TRUE">AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000</resTitle>
      <presForm>
        <PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005">
        </PresFormCd>
      </presForm>
    </idCitation>
    <spatRpType>
      <SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001">
      </SpatRepTypCd>
    </spatRpType>
    <dataExt>
      <geoEle>
        <GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native">
          <westBL Sync="TRUE">1242196.875</westBL>
          <eastBL Sync="TRUE">1430465.927339</eastBL>
          <northBL Sync="TRUE">497577.71875</northBL>
          <southBL Sync="TRUE">320925.848882</southBL>
          <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
        </GeoBndBox>
      </geoEle>
    </dataExt>
    <geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees">
      <westBL Sync="TRUE">-80.368656</westBL>
      <eastBL Sync="TRUE">-79.676224</eastBL>
      <northBL Sync="TRUE">40.682989</northBL>
      <southBL Sync="TRUE">40.184955</southBL>
      <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
    </geoBox>
  </dataIdInfo>
  <mdLang>
    <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en">
    </languageCode>
  </mdLang>
  <mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName>
  <mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer>
  <mdChar>
    <CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004">
    </CharSetCd>
  </mdChar>
  <mdHrLv>
    <ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005">
    </ScopeCd>
  </mdHrLv>
  <mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName>
  <distInfo>
    <distributor>
      <distorTran>
        <onLineSrc>
          <orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\PC36\D$\AlleghenyCounty\AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000.shp</linkage>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
        </onLineSrc>
        <transSize Sync="TRUE">26.050</transSize>
      </distorTran>
      <distorFormat>
        <formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName>
      </distorFormat>
    </distributor>
  </distInfo>
  <refSysInfo>
    <RefSystem>
      <refSysID>
        <identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Pennsylvania_South_FIPS_3702_Feet</identCode>
      </refSysID>
    </RefSystem>
  </refSysInfo>
  <spatRepInfo>
    <VectSpatRep>
      <topLvl>
        <TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001">
        </TopoLevCd>
      </topLvl>
      <geometObjs Name="AlleghenyCounty_Soils2000">
        <geoObjTyp>
          <GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001">
          </GeoObjTypCd>
        </geoObjTyp>
        <geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">27044</geoObjCnt>
      </geometObjs>
    </VectSpatRep>
  </spatRepInfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>