<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>GIS Consortium</origin>
        <title>Chester County School district boundaries</title>
        <edition>1.0</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>West Chester, PA</pubplace>
          <publish>GIS Consortium</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <pubdate>201306</pubdate>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Quartely</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-76.136732</westbc>
        <eastbc>-75.354884</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.252489</northbc>
        <southbc>39.707848</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Educational Facilities</themekey>
        <themekey>School</themekey>
        <themekey>Chester County School Districts</themekey>
        <themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>Structure</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Chester County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Subject to Geographic Information Systems Access Policy. The GIS database is owned and copyrighted by the County of Chester. No access to, use of, or processing of the database or any product, service, or other item which is or may be a part thereof or derived therefrom shall be permitted without the express written consent of the County. The County will place this restriction on the face of the products generated by the GIS, or in contracts for services, software licenses or other appropriate agreement.</accconst>
    <useconst>Subject to Geographic Information Systems Access Policy. The User (s) of County of Chester, Pennsylvania information provided by the County, agrees that the GIS database, all products and services derived therefrom, and all rights thereto are owned and copyrighted by the County. The County grants the User the right to use the portion of the GIS database (and any product or service derived therefrom). The GIS database (and any product or service derived therefrom) is prohibited from being sold, duplicated, reproduced, disseminated or shared with any other person, entity or party without the prior express written consent from the County. When the County gives such written consent, any third party/vendor recipient of the GIS database shall be subject to the same terms and conditions as the User, and use of the GIS database shall be for the sole purpose of providing services necessary for the operations of the User.Furthemore, the User agrees to use its best efforts to require and enforce compliance by the additional recipient with the terms and conditions of this agreement, including return, purge or destruction by the additional recipient of its copy of the GIS database upon completion of its services. The User(s) indicate their acceptance of the aforementioned constraints by downloading or receiving the data contained on the GIS website.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Chester County GIS Department, GIS Consortium</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>313 W Market St, Suite 5302</address>
          <city>West Chester</city>
          <state>Pa.</state>
          <postal>19380-0991</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(610)344-4637</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(610)344-5211</cntfax>
        <hours>Mon-Fri 8-4:30</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.4.4000</native>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>201306</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </timeperd>
    <descript>
      <abstract>ChesterCounty_Schooldistrictboundaries201306</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>QA/QC was conducted by the Data Management Team</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Sampling same as land base (features built from land base = + -5 feet acuracy)</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>GIS Consortium</origin>
            <title>School District Boundaries</title>
            <edition>1.0</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>West Chester, PA</pubplace>
              <publish>GIS Consortium</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>www.chesco.org/gis.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>200</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>ChesCO-LRS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Political borders set by property files Process_Step</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>14</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>39.93333333333333</stdparll>
            <stdparll>40.96666666666667</stdparll>
            <longcm>-77.75</longcm>
            <latprjo>39.33333333333334</latprjo>
            <feast>1968500.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000026907964745248598</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000026907964745248598</ordres>
          </coordrep>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Chester County School district boundaries</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>URL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>School District Website</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of School District</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHARED_DIS</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ATTENDANCE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_LEN</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview />
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Chester County GIS Department, GIS Consortium</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>313 W Market St, Suite 5302</address>
          <city>West Chester</city>
          <state>Pa.</state>
          <postal>19380-0991</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(610)344-4637</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(610)344-5211</cntfax>
        <hours>Mon-Fri 8-4:30</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The Chester County Geographic Information System was prepared for use by the County for its internal purposes only. It was not designed for use by any other entity or the general public. Any use of the GIS data or any product or service derived therefrom shall be at the sole risk of the person or entity so using the GIS data or its derivative products and services. Chester County makes no representation or warranty as to the accuracy of the GIS database or the accuracy as to labeling, dimensions, contours, property boundaries, or placement or location of any map feature. CHESTER COUNTY MAKES NO WARRANTY OR MERCHANTABILITY OR WARRANTY FOR FITNESS OF USE FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THE GIS DATA OR ANY PRODUCT OR SERIVCE DERIVED THEREFROM. Any user or purchaser of the GIS data or any product or service derived therefrom, accepts the same AS IS, WITH ALL FAULTS, and assumes all responsibility for the use thereof, and further covenants and agrees to hold Chester Countyharmless from and against any damage, loss, or liability arising from the use of any GIS product or service. Independent verification of any data, product, or service from the GIS database should be obtained by any user or purchaser thereof. Chester County disclaims, and shall not be liable for, any and all damage, loss, or liability, whether direct, indirect, or consequential, which arises or may arise from the use of any GIS data, product, or service by any person or entity. See the GeographicInformation Systems Access Policy.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20130611</metd>
    <metrd>12/16/2005</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Chester County GIS Department, GIS Consortium</cntorg>
          <cntper>Mike Hott</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>313 W Market St, Suite 5302</address>
          <city>West Chester</city>
          <state>Pa</state>
          <postal>19380-0991</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(610)344-4549</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(610)344-5211</cntfax>
        <cntemail>afrazier@chesco.org</cntemail>
        <hours>Mon-Fri 8-4:30</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>