<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Land Use Land Cover</title>
        <edition>Based on 2012 aerial photos</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <origin>Lancaster County GIS Department</origin>
        <pubdate>201403</pubdate>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-76.727962</westbc>
        <eastbc>-75.864937</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.323400</northbc>
        <southbc>39.714860</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>land use</themekey>
        <themekey>land cover</themekey>
        <themekey>cover type</themekey>
        <themekey>PlanningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>For use at 1:2400 or smaller scale. For educational/demonstration purposes only. The Originator, Publisher and Distributor exclude any and all implied warranties and make no warranty or representation with respect to the data files or accompanying documentation, including quality, performance, merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. These data files and documentation are provided 'as is' and the User assumes the entire risk as to their quality and performance These data are not to be redistributed for commercial profit. Reproduction or redistribution of this digital data set without permission of the Originator/Publisher is expressly forbidden. The Originator and Publisher should be clearly cited in any product derived from this data. Any modifications to this data must be described in any digital or hardcopy product derived from this data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>County of Lancaster</cntorg>
          <cntper>IT/GIS</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>150 N. Queen St., Suite 322</address>
          <city>Lancaster</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>17603</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>717-391-7550</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>ithelpdesk@co.lancaster.pa.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.4.4000</native>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>201403</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </timeperd>
    <descript>
      <abstract>LancasterCountyLulc201403</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>48192</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>39.93333333333333</stdparll>
            <stdparll>40.96666666666667</stdparll>
            <longcm>-77.75</longcm>
            <latprjo>39.33333333333334</latprjo>
            <feast>1968500.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000026907964745248598</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000026907964745248598</ordres>
          </coordrep>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>LancasterCountyLULC</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Modified Anderson Level II Landuse Code 111 through 770. </attrdef>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>111</edomv>
            <edomvd>Residential less than 2 units per acre</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>112</edomv>
            <edomvd>Residential 2.1 - 7 units per acre </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>113</edomv>
            <edomvd>Residential more than 7 units per acre </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>114</edomv>
            <edomvd>farmsteads with outbuildings </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>120</edomv>
            <edomvd>Commercial and services</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>130</edomv>
            <edomvd>Industrial </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>140</edomv>
            <edomvd>Transportation and utilities </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>150</edomv>
            <edomvd>Industrial and commercial complexes </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>160</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mixed urban or build up land (urban centers)</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>170</edomv>
            <edomvd>other (not fitting other category or cannot be interpreted) </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>180</edomv>
            <edomvd>Institutional (schools, hospitals, churches) </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>190</edomv>
            <edomvd>Recreational (park, campground) </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>210</edomv>
            <edomvd>Cropland and pasture </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>211</edomv>
            <edomvd>Cropland </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>212</edomv>
            <edomvd>Pasture</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>220</edomv>
            <edomvd>Orchards/groves/vinyards/nurseries</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>230</edomv>
            <edomvd>Large confined feeding operations </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>240</edomv>
            <edomvd>Other agriculture</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>310</edomv>
            <edomvd>Herbaceous (open grassy areas with few trees or shrubs) </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>320</edomv>
            <edomvd>Shrub/brush </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>330</edomv>
            <edomvd>mixed cover </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>410</edomv>
            <edomvd>Deciduous forest </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>420</edomv>
            <edomvd>Coniferous forest</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>430</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mixed forest </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>500</edomv>
            <edomvd>Open water </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>610</edomv>
            <edomvd>Forested wetlands </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>620</edomv>
            <edomvd>Non-forested wetlands</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>730</edomv>
            <edomvd>Sandy non-beach </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>740</edomv>
            <edomvd>Rock outcrops </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>750</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mines, quarries, pits, junk yards, landfills </edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>760</edomv>
            <edomvd>Transitional (under construction)</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>770</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mixed barren and vegetated (basic disturbed class)</edomvd>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NWI_CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>National Wetlands Inventory Classification</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FLAG</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COMMENTS</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Editor</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Edit_Date</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_len</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>DESCRIPTION OF LAND USE/LAND COVER INTERPRETATION CODES
Land Use Codes:
ID, 100 Level (Residential)
ID, 200+ Levels (Other)
---------------National Wetlands Inventory Class (NWI_Class)
Estuarine
Palustrine
Riverine
Marine
Lacustrine
SourceLand Use Codes:
100 Level
111 Residential Less than 2 units per acre.
112 Residential 2.1 to 7 units per acre (villages, neighborhoods, highway strip houses).
113 Residential More than 7 units per acre (trailer parks, apartment buildings, condominiums, row homes).
114 Farmsteads Farm houses, usually associated with and including, barns and outbuildings. (NOT including large, commercial-sized hog/chicken operations - #230). Agricultural production may or may not be active.
120 Commercial and services Any apparent store, shop, mall, gas station or place of business where large-scale production is not occurring.
130 Industrial Large buildings that may have production in process.
140 Transportation and utilities Wide transportation corridors (including 4-lane divided highways), toll booth areas, highway departments, transmission stations, water towers/tanks, sewage treatment plants.
150 Industrial and commercial complexes Large areas where there are many adjacent industrial plants and/or other businesses. Only used when unable to determine the exact use as either 120 or 130.
160 Mixed urban or built-up land Densely developed land generally associated with urban centers. This category is often comprised of a mix of other developed land categories (i.e. 113, 120, 150, and 180) and is generally only used where development patterns are too complex to easily delineate separate developed land categories. For this project, this category will be rarely (if ever) used because the 300-scale photos appear to be sufficiently detailed to allow discrimination of separate categories.
170 Other Areas whose land use does not fit into any particular category or can not be interpreted from the aerial photography.
180 Institutional Schools, hospitals, or other institutional facilities. Churches and adjoining cemeteries. Stand-alone municipal buildings, including parking/storage areas for municipal equipment (i.e. snow plows). Also, stand-alone fire houses. Usually large buildings, surrounding access road with parking areas some landscaping, well-kept grounds.
190 Recreational Active Recreation Parks (i.e. ball fields, playgrounds, tennis courts). Also campgrounds, golf courses, hunt clubs.
Land Use Codes: 200+ Levels
210 Cropland and pasture Any land that is in agricultural use. Fields with crops or tractor tracks and grassy areas that may have cattle grazing or paths made by cattle.
211 Cropland
212 Pasture
220 Orchards/groves/vineyards/nurseries/other horticulture Trees/plants forming grid or regular patterns.
230 Large Confined Feeding Operations Usually associated with a farmstead (114) these are commercial-sized buildings housing hog or chicken operations.
240 Other agriculture
310 Herbaceous Open, grassy areas with few tress or shrubs. Generally refers to ungrazed or uncontrolled grass land, but also includes very large lawns and large cemeteries not adjacent to a church.
320 Shrub/brush Areas where shrubs, brush, and/or very small trees are present.
330 Mixed cover Areas that are not forested but have a mixture of vegetation.
410 Deciduous forest.
420 Coniferous forest.
430 Mixed forest.
500 Open water (Hydrology polygons from ADR).
610 Forested wetlands Wooded areas that appear to have very wet ground (location from NWI or TNC; linework by GDI).
620 Non-forested wetlands Swamps, and areas that have substantially wet ground (location from NWI or TNC; linework by GDI).
730 Sandy non-beach.
740 Rock outcrops
750 Mines/quarries/pits and junk yards/land fills.
760 Transitional (under construction).
770 Mixed barren and vegetated (basic disturbed class).
Ecological System:
Estuarine
E1RB1  Estuarine, Subtidal, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
E1RB2  Estuarine, Subtidal, Rock Bottom, Boulder
E1UB1  Estuarine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
E1UB2  Estuarine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
E1UB3  Estuarine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
E1UB4  Estuarine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
E1AB1  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
E1AB2  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
E1AB4  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
E1AB5  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Floating
E1AB6  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
E1AB7  Estuarine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
E1RF2  Estuarine, Subtidal, Reef, Mollusc
E1RF3  Estuarine, Subtidal, Reef, Worm
E1OW-  Estuarine, Subtidal, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
E2AB1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
E2AB2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
E2AB6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
E2AB7  Estuarine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
E2RF2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Reef, Mollusc
E2RF3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Reef, Worm
E2FL1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
E2FL2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Sand
E2FL3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Mud
E2FL4  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Organic
E2FL5  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
E2FL6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
E2SB1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
E2SB2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Streambed, Sand
E2SB3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Streambed, Mud
E2SB4  Estuarine, Intertidal, Streambed, Organic
E2RS1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
E2RS2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Boulder
E2RS6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Vegetated Non-pioneer
E2BB1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
E2BB2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Beach/Bar, Sand
E2EM1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Persistent
E2EM2  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Nonpersistent
E2EM3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
E2EM4  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
E2EM5  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Persistent
E2EM6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Emergent, Broad-leaved Persistent
E2SS1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Broad-leaved Deciduous
E2SS3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Broad-leaved Evergreen
E2SS4  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Needle-leaved Evergreen
E2SS5  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Dead
E2SS6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Deciduous
E2SS7  Estuarine, Intertidal, Scrub/Shrub, Evergreen
E2FO1  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Broad-leaved Deciduous
E2FO3  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Broad-leaved Evergreen
E2FO4  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Needle-leaved Evergreen
E2FO5  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Dead
E2FO6  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Deciduous
E2FO7  Estuarine, Intertidal, Forested, Evergreen
Ecological System:
Palustrine
PRB1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
PRB2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Rock Bottom, Boulder
PUB1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
PUB2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
PUB3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
PUB4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
PAB1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
PAB2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
PAB3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
PAB4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Floating-leaved
PAB5  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Floating
PAB6  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
PAB7  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
PFL1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
PFL2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Sand
PFL3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Mud
PFL4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Organic
PFL5  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
PFL6  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
PML1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Moss/Lichen, Moss
PML2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Moss/Lichen, Lichen
PEM1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Persistent
PEM2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Nonpersistent
PEM3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
PEM4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
PEM5  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Persistent
PEM6  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Emergent, Broad-leaved Persistent
PSS1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Broad-leaved Deciduous
PSS2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Needle-leaved Deciduous
PSS3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Broad-leaved Evergreen
PSS4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Needle-leaved Evergreen
PSS5  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Dead
PSS6  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Deciduous
PSS7  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Scrub/Shrub, Evergreen
PFO1  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Broad-leaved Deciduous
PFO2  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Needle-leaved Deciduous
PFO3  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Broad-leaved Evergreen
PFO4  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Needle-leaved Evergreen
PFO5  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Dead
PFO6  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Deciduous
PFO7  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Forested, Evergreen
POW-  Palustrine, No Ecological Subsystem, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System, Subsystem:
Riverine, Tidal
R1EM2  Riverine, Tidal, Emergent, Nonpersistent
R1EM3  Riverine, Tidal, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
R1EM4  Riverine, Tidal, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
R1RB1  Riverine, Tidal, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
R1RB2  Riverine, Tidal, Rock Bottom, Bolder
R1UB1  Riverine, Tidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
R1UB2  Riverine, Tidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
R1UB3  Riverine, Tidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
R1UB4  Riverine, Tidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
R1AB1  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
R1AB2  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
R1AB3  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
R1AB4  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
R1AB5  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Floating
R1AB6  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
R1AB7  Riverine, Tidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
R1FL1  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
R1FL2  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Sand
R1FL3  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Mud
R1FL4  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Organic
R1FL5  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
R1FL6  Riverine, Tidal, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
R1SB1  Riverine, Tidal, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
R1SB2  Riverine, Tidal, Streambed, Sand
R1SB3  Riverine, Tidal, Streambed, Mud
R1SB4  Riverine, Tidal, Streambed, Organic
R1RS1  Riverine, Tidal, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
R1RS2  Riverine, Tidal, Rocky Shore, Boulder
R1BB1  Riverine, Tidal, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
R1BB2  Riverine, Tidal, Beach/Bar, Sand
R1OW-  Riverine, Tidal, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System, Subsystem:
Riverine, Lower Perennial
R2EM2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Emergent, Nonpersistent
R2EM3  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
R2EM4  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
R2RB1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
R2RB2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bolder
R2UB1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
R2UB2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
R2UB3  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
R2UB4  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
R2AB1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
R2AB2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
R2AB3  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
R2AB4  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
R2AB5  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating
R2AB6  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
R2AB7  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
R2FL1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
R2FL2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Sand
R2FL3  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Mud
R2FL4  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Organic
R2FL5  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
R2FL6  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
R2SB1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
R2SB2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Streambed, Sand
R2SB3  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Streambed, Mud
R2SB4  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Streambed, Organic
R2RS1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
R2RS2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Rocky Shore, Boulder
R2BB1  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
R2BB2  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Beach/Bar, Sand
R2OW-  Riverine, Lower Perennial, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System, Subsystem:
Riverine, Upper Perennial
R3EM2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Emergent, Nonpersistent
R3EM3  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
R3EM4  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
R3RB1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
R3RB2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bolder
R3UB1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
R3UB2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
R3UB3  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
R3UB4  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
R3AB1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
R3AB2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
R3AB3  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
R3AB4  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
R3AB5  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating
R3AB6  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
R3AB7  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
R3FL1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
R3FL2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Sand
R3FL3  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Mud
R3FL4  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Organic
R3FL5  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
R3FL6  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
R3SB1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
R3SB2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Streambed, Sand
R3SB3  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Streambed, Mud
R3SB4  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Streambed, Organic
R3RS1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
R3RS2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Rocky Shore, Boulder
R3BB1  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
R3BB2  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Beach/Bar, Sand
R3OW-  Riverine, Upper Perennial, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System, Subsystem:
Riverine, Intermittent
R4EM2  Riverine, Intermittent, Emergent, Nonpersistent
R4EM3  Riverine, Intermittent, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
R4EM4  Riverine, Intermittent, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
R4RB1  Riverine, Intermittent, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
R4RB2  Riverine, Intermittent, Rock Bottom, Bolder
R4UB1  Riverine, Intermittent, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
R4UB2  Riverine, Intermittent, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
R4UB3  Riverine, Intermittent, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
R4UB4  Riverine, Intermittent, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
R4AB1  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
R4AB2  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
R4AB3  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
R4AB4  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
R4AB5  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Floating
R4AB6  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
R4AB7  Riverine, Intermittent, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
R4FL1  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
R4FL2  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Sand
R4FL3  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Mud
R4FL4  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Organic
R4FL5  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
R4FL6  Riverine, Intermittent, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
R4SB1  Riverine, Intermittent, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
R4SB2  Riverine, Intermittent, Streambed, Sand
R4SB3  Riverine, Intermittent, Streambed, Mud
R4SB4  Riverine, Intermittent, Streambed, Organic
R4RS1  Riverine, Intermittent, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
R4RS2  Riverine, Intermittent, Rocky Shore, Boulder
R4BB1  Riverine, Intermittent, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
R4BB2  Riverine, Intermittent, Beach/Bar, Sand
R4OW-  Riverine, Intermittent, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System, Subsystem:
Riverine, Unknown
R5EM2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Emergent, Nonpersistent
R5EM3  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
R5EM4  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
R5RB1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
R5RB2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Rock Bottom, Bolder
R5UB1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
R5UB2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
R5UB3  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
R5UB4  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
R5AB1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
R5AB2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
R5AB3  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
R5AB4  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating - Leaved
R5AB5  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Floating
R5AB6  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
R5AB7  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
R5FL1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
R5FL2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Sand
R5FL3  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Mud
R5FL4  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Organic
R5FL5  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
R5FL6  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
R5SB1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Streambed, Cobble/Gravel
R5SB2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Streambed, Sand
R5SB3  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Streambed, Mud
R5SB4  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Streambed, Organic
R5RS1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
R5RS2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Rocky Shore, Boulder
R5BB1  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
R5BB2  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Beach/Bar, Sand
R5OW-  Riverine, Unknown Perennial, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
Ecological System:
Marine
M1RB1  Marine, Subtidal, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
M1RB2  Marine, Subtidal, Rock Bottom, Boulder
M1UB1  Marine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
M1UB2  Marine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
M1UB3  Marine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
M1UB4  Marine, Subtidal, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
M1AB1  Marine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
M1AB2  Marine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
M1AB6  Marine, Subtidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
M1RF1  Marine, Subtidal, Reef, Coral
M1RF3  Marine, Subtidal, Reef, Worm
M1OW-  Marine, Subtidal, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
M2AB1  Marine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
M2AB2  Marine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
M2AB6  Marine, Intertidal, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
M2RF1  Marine, Intertidal, Reef, Coral
M2RF3  Marine, Intertidal, Reef, Worm
M2FL1  Marine, Intertidal, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
M2FL2  Marine, Intertidal, Flat, Sand
M2FL3  Marine, Intertidal, Flat, Mud
M2FL6  Marine, Intertidal, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
M2RS1  Marine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Bedrock
M2RS2  Marine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Boulder
M2RS6  Marine, Intertidal, Rocky Shore, Vegetated Non-pioneer
M2BB1  Marine, Intertidal, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
M2BB2  Marine, Intertidal, Beach/Bar, SandEcological System:
Lacustrine
L1RB1  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
L1RB2  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Rock Bottom, Boulder
L1UB1  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
L1UB2  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
L1UB3  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
L1UB4  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
L1AB1  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
L1AB2  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
L1AB3  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
L1AB4  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Floating-leaved
L1AB5  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Floating
L1AB6  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
L1AB7  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
L1OW-  Lacustrine, Limnetic, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
L2RB1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Rock Bottom, Bedrock
L2RB2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Rock Bottom, Boulder
L2UB1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Unconsolidated Bottom, Cobble/Gravel
L2UB2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Unconsolidated Bottom, Sand
L2UB3  Lacustrine, Littoral, Unconsolidated Bottom, Mud
L2UB4  Lacustrine, Littoral, Unconsolidated Bottom, Organic
L2AB1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Algal
L2AB2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Vascular
L2AB3  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Submergent Moss
L2AB4  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Floating -leaved
L2AB5  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Floating
L2AB6  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Submergent
L2AB7  Lacustrine, Littoral, Aquatic Bed, Unknown Surface
L2FL1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Cobble/Gravel
L2FL2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Sand
L2FL3  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Mud
L2FL4  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Organic
L2FL5  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Vegetated Pioneer
L2FL6  Lacustrine, Littoral, Flat, Vegetated Non-pioneer
L2RS1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Rocky Shale, Bedrock
L2RS2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Rocky Shale, Boulder
L2BB1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Beach/Bar, Cobble/Gravel
L2BB2  Lacustrine, Littoral, Beach/Bar, Sand
L2EM1  Lacustrine, Littoral, Emergent, Nonpersistent
L2EM3  Lacustrine, Littoral, Emergent, Narrow-leaved Nonpersistent
L2EM4  Lacustrine, Littoral, Emergent, Broad-leaved Nonpersistent
L2OW-  Lacustrine, Littoral, Open Water, Unknown Bottom
National Wetlands Inventory Class Source
Source  1 = ADR
2 = NWI
3 = GDI
4 = TNC 
</eaover>
      <eadetcit>Lancaster County GIS </eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SDE Feature Class</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt />
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20140318</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>County of Lancaster</cntorg>
          <cntper>IT/GIS</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>150 N. Queen St., Suite 322</address>
          <city>Lancaster</city>
          <state>PA</state>
          <postal>17603</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>717-391-7550</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>ithelpdesk@co.lancaster.pa.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>