<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USDA Forest Service, Northeastern Area State and Private Forestry</origin>
        <pubdate>2005</pubdate>
        <title>Mid-Atlantic Highlands</title>
        <edition>1</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1994-01-01</begdate>
          <enddate>2005-01-01</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Unknown</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>states</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>highlands</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>PA</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>NJ</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>NY</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>CT</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Appalachian Mountain Club (AMC) assumes no responsibility for errors, omissions, or any liability for damages resulting from use of any of the data. AMC makes no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, or reliability with respect to the data for any purpose. Any reliance placed on such information is strictly at the users own risk.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA Forest Service, Northeastern Area State and Private Forestry</cntorg>
          <cntper>Tom Luther</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>603-868-7710</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>603-868-1066</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tluther@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>USFS and Appalachian Mountain Club</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7600) ; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.4.4000</native>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Mid_Atlantic_Highlands</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Office of Information Resources Management (OIRM), Bureau of Geographic Information Systems (BGIS)</origin>
            <pubdate>2005-09-01</pubdate>
            <title>NJDEP Municipality Boundaries for the State of New Jersey</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace>
              <publish>NJDEP</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Municipal boundaries in New Jersey were gathered from USGS topoquads and other sources in 1987. Since that time, updates to the data have been limited to noting consolidations of boundaries. The scale of the original data varies, relying primarily on 1:24,000 topoquads. Changes were made when inconsistencies with other maps were found based on preponderance of data. In area where the line was labeled as approximate attempts were made to correctly locate the boundary. The 1986 photoquads were used to move the boundary lines to photo-identifiable features as needed. Changes less than 5 acres were not made. In July, 1997, the coverage was updated to reflect the consolidation of Pahaquarry Township with Hardwick Township. New jersey now has 566 municipalities. In March, 2000, the attributes were edited to properly label West Caldwell as a Township, as verified with the township clerk; it had been labeled as a borough. In January 2003 the Census 2000 population information was assessed to the former stmun coverage to create this stmun data layer. Additional attributes included population density by square mile. In May 2003 the FIPS codes and Township names were updated as identified. Essex Fells and North Caldwell were redesignated Boroughs in 1991 and Passaic Township is now Long Hill Township.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>NJDEP Municipality Boundaries for the State of New Jersey</srccitea>
        <srccontr>NJ municipalities</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Natural Resources Center, DEP, State of Connecticut</origin>
            <pubdate>1994-01-01</pubdate>
            <title>Connecticut Town Master Datalayer</title>
            <othercit>All of the state, county, town, borough, and village boundaries that appear on the published 7.5 minute quadrangle maps that cover the State of Connecticut. Derived From U.S. Geological Survey Digital Line Graph Files (DLG) for 1:24,000 scale maps.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Connecticut Town Master Datalayer</srccitea>
        <srccontr>CT municipalities</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Pennsylvania Department of Transportation, Bureau of Planning and Research, Cartographic Information Division</origin>
            <pubdate>2005-01-01</pubdate>
            <title>Boundaries of municipalities within Pennsylvania</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Harrisburg, PA</pubplace>
              <publish>Pennsylvania Department of Transportation</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Boundaries of municipalities within Pennsylvania as delineated for the PennDOT Type 10 general highway maps. Additional information comes from the Pennsylvania Bureau of Municipal Services. This layer contains all classifications of municipality including first and second class townships, boroughs, cities and the town.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Boundaries of municipalities within Pennsylvania</srccitea>
        <srccontr>PA municipalities</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>New York State Office of Cyber Security &amp; Critical Infrastructure Coordination (CSCIC)</origin>
            <pubdate>2005-01-01</pubdate>
            <title>New York State incorporated city and town boundaries</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Albany, NY</pubplace>
              <publish>New York State Office of Cyber Security and Critical Infrastructure Coordination (CSCIC)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>This data was created as part of the Accident Location Information System (ALIS) project. ALIS is a multi-agency project involving the NYS Office of Cyber Security &amp; Critical Infrastructure Coordination (CSCIC), the NYS Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV) and the NYS Department of Transportation (DOT). A major component of the ALIS Project was the creation of up-to-date statewide Geographic Information System (GIS) files.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>New York State incorporated city and town boundaries.</srccitea>
        <srccontr>NY municipalities</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Merged the four state municipalities. Edited the shared boundaries between states. Checked topology.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-75.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Mid_Atlantic_Highlands</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ID</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Acres</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20120529</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Northeastern Area State and Private Forestry</cntorg>
          <cntper>Rebecca Whitney</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Unknown</addrtype>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>603-868-7627</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>603-868-1066</cntfax>
        <cntemail>rwhitney@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:0 0 0 0;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Appalachian Mountain Club (AMC) assumes no responsibility for errors, omissions, or any liability for damages resulting from use of any of the data. AMC makes no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, or reliability with respect to the data for any purpose. Any reliance placed on such information is strictly at the users own risk.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</metuc>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>