<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.pasda.psu.edu/pasda/uci_metadata/dtd/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
        <title>USGS High Resolution Orthoimagery for Harrisburg, Pennsylvania - TILE INDEX </title>
        <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>High Resolution Orthoimagery</sername>
          <issue>0.1</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink> http://www.pasda.psu.edu</onlink>
        <onlink>http://gisdata.usgs.gov/tdds/downloadfile.php?TYPE=ortho&amp;ORIG=META&amp;FNAME=18TUK390505_201111_0x3000m_CL_1.zip</onlink>
        <onlink>http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>201111</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-76.891690637517</westbc>
        <eastbc>-76.8737032148747</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.2032453973689</northbc>
        <southbc>40.1894519103899</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>digital spatial data</themekey>
        <themekey>0.3 meter orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>rectified image</themekey>
        <themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>natural color orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>image map</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>010</themekey>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
        <themekey>008</themekey>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>013</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote
Sensing</themekt>
        <themekey>National Standards for Spatial Digital Accuracy (NSSDA)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard 10-4,): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>U.S.</placekey>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the identification of the States, the District of Columbia and the outlying areas of the United States, and associated areas (Federal Information Processing Standard 5-2): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
        <placekey>PA</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Counties and County Equivalents of the States of the United States and the District of Columbia (FIPS Pub 6-3)</placekt>
        <placekey>York County</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
        <placekey>Harrisburg</placekey>
        <placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Any downloading and use of these data signifies a user's agreement to comprehension and compliance of the USGS Standard Disclaimer.  Insure all portions of metadata are read and clearly understood before using these data in order to protect both user and USGS interests.</accconst>
    <useconst>There is no guarantee of warranty concerning the accuracy of the data.  Users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions.  Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full awareness of its limitations.  Acknowledgement of the originating agencies would be appreciated in products derived from these data.  Any user who modifies the data is obligated to describe the types of modifications they perform.  User specifically agrees not to misrepresent the data, nor to imply that changes made were approved or endorsed by the U.S. Geological Survey.  Please refer to http://www.usgs.gov/privacy.html for the USGS disclaimer.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
      <browsen>http://tdds.cr.usgs.gov/browse/ortho/18T/UK/18TUK390505_201111_0x3000m_CL_1.jpg</browsen>
      <browsed>Tiled High Resolution Orthoimagery (HRO)</browsed>
      <browset>JPEG</browset>
    </browse>
    <datacred>Digital Aerial Solutions, LLC (DAS)
8409 Laurel Fair Circle, Suite 100
Tampa, FL 33610 "and" U.S. Geological Survey</datacred>
    <secinfo>
      <secsys>None</secsys>
      <secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
      <sechandl>N/A</sechandl>
    </secinfo>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
    <descript>
      <abstract>NGA_USGS_Harrisburg2011_TileIndex</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Radiometry is verified by visual inspection of the digital orthophoto.  Slight systematic radiometric differences may exist between adjacent orthoimage files; these are due primarily to differences in source image capture dates and sun angles along flight lines.  These differences can be observed in an image's general lightness or darkness when it is compared to adjacent orthoimage file coverages. Tonal balancing may be performed over a group of images during the mosaicking process which may serve to lighten or darken adjacent images for better color tone matching.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>"All GeoTIFF tagged data and image file sizes are validated using commercial GIS software to ensure proper loading
before being archived.  This validation procedure ensures correct physical format and field values for tagged
elements.  Seamlines and tile edges are visually inspected. Seamlines mismatches are not corrected unless the
overall displacement exceeds one meter." 
Logical consistency is implicit in the raster image data structure. Source imagery is cloud free.</logic>
    <complete>"Orthoimages are visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no gaps or image misplacements exist within
and between adjacent images.  These images are derived by mosaicking multiple images to ensure complete
coverage.  Source imagery is cloud free.  Photography was flown during leaf-off in deciduous vegetation regions.
Coastal areas and international boundary regions may have areas without images (void areas) in parts of the
coverage.  These void areas have a radiometric value of either zero (black) or 128 (uniform gray)."</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>"The horizontal positional accuracy and the assurance of that accuracy depend, in part, on the accuracy of the data inputs to the rectification process.  The location of existing USGS photoidentifiable ground control and contractor aerotriangulation points were evaluated on the Geotiff image and compared with their ground values in order to determine an overall accuracy for each test block of orthoimages within the project.   After image coordinate measurement was completed for each block, an RMSE for the diagonal error was calculated for the orthoimages within the block. This value is an estimate of the horizontal accuracy of the tile expressed in meters." 
The relative accuracy is assembled by comparing rectified images generated from adjacent strips of imagery. The absolute accuracy is assessed by measuring the ground control points in the rectified image against the actual surveyed co-ordinate position. The testing is for overall accuracy.  This data has been produced to be fully compliant with the National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS) for mapping at this scale.</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
          <horizpav>0.50</horizpav>
          <horizpae>"Federal Geographic Data Committee, 1998, Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standard, Part 3, National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy, FGDC-STD-007.3-1998"</horizpae>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>There is no vertical accuracy component to orthophotography.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Digital Aerial Solutions, LLC</origin>
            <pubdate>2011</pubdate>
            <title>ADS40 digital imagery</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital imagery</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20111112</begdate>
              <enddate>20111113</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ADS40 digital imagery</srccitea>
        <srccontr>The digital imagery mission was composed of a total of 2 lifts.  Imagery (1-ft, 0.3 meter GSD) was obtained at an altitude of 9,450 feet above ground level on 12 and 13 Nov 2011.  The missions were flown with a Leica ADS40 (Sensor Head 52) digital camera with ABGPS and IMU. This imagery provides the data for the digital orthoimage. 
Imagery was acquired on the following dates -
Lift                    Date
0111122011           12 Nov 2011
0211132011           13 Nov 2011</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Digital Aerial Solutions, LLC</origin>
            <pubdate>2011</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>Geodetic Ground Control Survey</title>
            <geoform>model</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <mdattim>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20111112</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20111113</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20111115</caldate>
              </sngdate>
              <sngdate>
                <caldate>20111116</caldate>
              </sngdate>
            </mdattim>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Ground Condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GPS ground control</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Horizontal and vertical control was used to establish positions and elevations for reference and correlation purposes and as input to the aerotriangulation process.
Control consists of photoidentifiable surveyed ground control for ground reference.  A total of 16 photoidentifiable ground control points were collected.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20111231</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>Harrisburg, PA 3 Meter USGS DEM</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital file</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20100518</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Ground Condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DEM</srccitea>
        <srccontr>USGS format elevation data with a 3-meter grid post interval and covering a 7.5-minute x 7.5-minute quadrangle in extent.  Used to provide ground elevations for
orthorectification process.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Digital Aerial Solutions, LLC</origin>
            <pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>Airborne GPS/IMU Data</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital file</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20111112</begdate>
              <enddate>20111113</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Ground Condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ABGPS/IMU</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Airborne GPS (ABGPS) and IMU data are collected with an onboard dual frequency GPS survey unit and a corresponding IMU system in combination with the digital
imagery.  The GPS data provides the position of the imagery at the time of capture while the IMU system records instantaneous changes in position and attitude of
the sensor.  The GPS/IMU, base station, and ground control processing are an important step towards the development of accurate orthoimages.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>"Source Imagery - ADS40 (Sensor Head 52) Digital Camera Imagery
Control - Airborne GPS/IMU supplemented with photo identifiable field control
Aerotriangulation, Orthorectification - SOCET SET, ORIMA Elevation Model - USGS DEM Mosaic - OrthoVista
The following describes the digital production sequence.
1.  The raw ADS40 (Level-0) data and associated GPS and IMU data for each mission is downloaded from the hard drives and checked to confirm that no files have been corrupted and that all data can be successfully downloaded.
2.  The GPS and IMU data are post-processed along with the base station data to produce a precise position and attitude stream for each line of imagery.  Post processing uses the high frequency readouts of the IMU to verify the
GPS data and to provide instantaneous positioning of each line of imagery between GPS recordings. Likewise, the IMU attitude data is corrected for bias/drift and
transformed to real world coordinates by using the GPS data.  This process creates Level-1 rectified imagery which is an approximately geo-positioned image.
3.  The ADS40 production process uses aerial triangulation techniques to combine the short-term accuracy of the IMU with high global accuracy of GPS. In combination with the minimum required number of ground control points (GCPs), aerial triangulation delivers best fitting results on the ground.  The extra information added to the system by automatic tie point measurements (APM) leads to very reliable orientation results where photogrammetric measurements serve to control IMU/GPS measurements and vice versa.
4.  The results of the APM are run through a combined bundle adjustment process to further refine the measured
image coordinates and the position and attitude values from IMU and GPS computed by IMU/GPS post
processing.  The bundle adjustment process equally compensates for systematic errors such as the
misalignment between IMU and sensor axes, IMU/GPS drift, and the datum difference between IMU/GPS and
ground control coordinate system.  This results in a very accurate and precise determination of the parameters of
exterior orientation which are later used for Orthorectification.
5.  The orthorectification process uses the raw Level-0 data as the input imagery source to avoid repeated
re-sampling of the imagery to yield the best possible image quality and accuracy.  The raw Level-0 true color imagery
is orthorectified to the DEM using the adjusted position and orientation results from the aerial triangulation phase. The orthorectified strip of imagery is called the Level-2 data.
6.  The resulting images are then mosaicked and color balanced.
7.  The final 1500-meter by 1500-meter tiles are clipped out and the imagery is output in uncompressed GeoTIFF
format with no overlap.
8.  The completed natural color digital orthophotos are checked for image quality.  Minor artifacts are corrected
using Adobe Photoshop in an interactive editing session. Digital tiles are assigned final names based on the U.S.
National Grid."</procdesc>
        <procdate>201111</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Data received at Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS) were verified as:
Projection:   NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_18N
Resolution:  0.3000 m
Type:  Natural Color

and resampled to align to the U.S. National Grid (USNG). The naming convention is based on the U.S. National Grid (USNG), taking the coordinates of the SW corner of the orthoimage.   The naming convention is based on the U.S. National Grid (USNG), taking the coordinates of the SW corner of the orthoimage.  The metadata were imported and updated for display through The National Map at &lt;http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html&gt;    Chip-level metadata are provided in XML and HTML format. Data were compressed utilizing IAS software. The compression was JPEG2000 Lossy Compressed. The file format created was .jp2.</procdesc>
        <procdate>201203</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
              <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
              <city>Reston</city>
              <state>VA</state>
              <postal>20192</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
            <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
            <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
            <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>5000</rowcount>
      <colcount>5000</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75.0000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
              <feast>500,000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.3000</absres>
            <ordres>0.3000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum>
        <altres>1.00000</altres>
        <altunits>meters</altunits>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>Natural color orthoimagery is organized in three color bands or channels which represent the red, green, and blue portions of the spectrum.  Each image pixel is assigned a triplet of numeric values, one for each color band.  Numeric values range from 0 to 255. Areas where data is incomplete due to lack of full image coverage are represented with the numeric value of 0.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, 1999, Standards for Digital Orthoimagery: Reston, VA</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the USGS, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the USGS regarding the use of the data on any other system, nor does the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.  Data may have been compiled from various outside sources.  Spatial information may not meet National Map Accuracy Standards.  This information may be updated without notification. The USGS shall not be liable for any activity involving these data, installation, fitness of the data for a particular purpose, its use, or analyses results.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>JP2</formname>
          <formvern>ArcGIS 9.3</formvern>
          <formspec>Raster</formspec>
          <transize>0.001</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>The URL http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html provides a map interface that allows for viewing and data downloads within a customer defined area of interest. Zoom tools are available that can be used to investigate areas of interest on the map interface. The download tool allows the customer to capture layers from the map, utilizing The National Map process for downloading. The generated zip file can be unzipped and imported into various user software applications.</accinstr>
            <oncomp>Not available for dissemination</oncomp>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <turnarnd>Variable</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>ESRI ArcGIS Suite and/or Arc/Info or other compatible software, and supporting operating systems.</techpreq>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>2012</begdate>
          <enddate>unknown</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2012</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
    <metsi>
      <metscs>None</metscs>
      <metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
      <metshd>None</metshd>
    </metsi>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>pasda@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <Esri>
    <CreaDate>20131022</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>11025500</CreaTime>
    <ArcGISstyle>ISO 19139 Metadata Implementation Specification</ArcGISstyle>
    <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
    <DataProperties>
      <itemProps>
        <itemLocation>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\ALCES\D$\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_Harrisburg2011_TileIndex</linkage>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
        </itemLocation>
      </itemProps>
      <copyHistory>
        <copy source="D:\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_Harrisburg2011_TileIndex" dest="\\ALCES\D$\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_Harrisburg2011_TileIndex" date="20131022" time="11025500">
        </copy>
      </copyHistory>
    </DataProperties>
  </Esri>
</metadata>