<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>EarthData International, LLC</origin>
        <pubdate>20040927</pubdate>
        <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
        <title>Digital Orthophoto Production for Flood Assessment of the Juniata and Susquehanna Rivers in Pennsylvania</title>
        <edition>1st Edition</edition>
        <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Frederick, Maryland, U.S.A.</pubplace>
          <publish>EarthData International, LLC</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20040919</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-078.285524</westbc>
        <eastbc>-076.993583</eastbc>
        <northbc>+40.636944</northbc>
        <southbc>+40.207967</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>Digital Orthophotography</themekey>
        <themekey>Aerotriangulation</themekey>
        <themekey>DTM</themekey>
        <themekey>Imagery/Base Maps/Earth Cover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>United States of America (USA)</placekey>
        <placekey>State of Pennsylvania</placekey>
        <placekey>Juniata River</placekey>
        <placekey>Susquehanna River</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>EarthData International, LLC</cntorg>
          <cntper>Scott Lane</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>7320 Executive Way</address>
          <city>Frederick</city>
          <state>Maryland</state>
          <postal>21704</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>301-948-8550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>301-963-2064</cntfax>
        <cntemail>metadata@earthdata.com</cntemail>
        <hours>9:00-5:00 M-F</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <descript>
      <abstract>paivanflood2004</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>
EarthData adhered to a plus or minus 5 to 10 meter
horizontal accuracy by the following.
1. Utilized USGS DOQQs and DEM to develop photo
control.
2. Use of airborne GPS in conjunction with the acquisition
of photography.
3. Use of proprietary software and interactive editing
processes to confirm that the entire project area is
covered.
</logic>
    <complete>
Digital orthophotography  consists of 91 12000 X 12000
foot ortho tiles in tiff/tfw format.  MrSID mosaic files
were also produced and delivered with this dataset.  The
project area covers a portion of the Juniata River from the
Raystown Dam to the main stream of the Susquehanna
River.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The horizontal accuracy for the digital orthophotography
met accuracy levels of plus or minus 5 to 10 meters or
better.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>EarthData International, LLC</origin>
            <pubdate>20040922</pubdate>
            <title>Photo Control for the Pennsylvania Flood Assessment, Digital Orthophotography of the Juniata River, PA</title>
            <edition>1st</edition>
            <geoform>model</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Frederick, MD, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>EarthData International, LLC</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>4800</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20040922</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Photo Control</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
EarthData International, LLC established photo control
using USGS DOQQs and DEMs.  A total of 36 control
points were established across the project area.  Control
referenced the Pennsylvania State Plane Coordinate
System, South Zone, NAD83, NAVD88, US survey feet.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>EarthData Aviation</origin>
            <pubdate>20040919</pubdate>
            <pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
            <title>Aerial Photography of the Juniata River</title>
            <geoform>profile</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>28800</srcscale>
        <typesrc>filmstrip</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20040919</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Ground Condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Aerial photography</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
The aerial photographic mission was composed of a total
of 172 exposures in 11 flight lines following the Juniata
River from the Raystown Dam to the main body of the
Susquehanna River.  Photography was obtained at an
average altitude of 15613' above mean terrain. Aerial
photography was exposed in conjunction with airborne
GPS; the stationary GPS receiver was positioned over an
existing NGS control point.  Aerial photography was
exposed on natural color negative film using a Wild RC-30
camera, number 5242, 152.984mm (nominal 6 inch) focal
length lens cone number 13256.  Photography was
exposed on film type X-100, emulsion number
67663414.  All aerial photography was acquired during
September of 2004.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The ground control and airborne GPS data was integrated
into a rigid network through the completion of a fully
analytical bundle aerotriangulation adjustment.
1. The original aerial film was scanned at a resolution of
1,210 DPI.  The scans were produced using Z/I Imaging
PhotoScan flatbed metric scanners.  Each unit has a
positional accuracy of 1.5 microns and a radiometric
resolution of 1,024 gray levels for each of three color
layers.
2. The raster scans were given a preliminary visual check
on the scanner workstation to ensure that the raster file
size is correct and to verify that the tone and contrast were
acceptable. A uniform directory structure for the project
was established on the network. The project was then
created on the network using the ZI Stereo Softcopy Kit
(SSK) workstation.  All operators and workstations
accessed the project through the network, avoiding
confusion or errors due to inconsistencies in digital data.
The project was defined using the relevant camera
information that was obtained from the USGS camera
calibration report for the aerial camera and the date of
photography. The technician verified that the datum and
units of measurement for the supplied control were
consistent with the project requirements. These units were
designated as Pennsylvania State Plane Coordinate
System, South Zone, NAD83, NAVD88, US Survey Feet.
3. The photogrammetric technician performed an automatic
interior orientation for the frames in the project. The
softcopy systems that were used by the technicians have
the ability to set up predefined fiducial templates for the
aerial camera(s) used for the project. Using the template
that was predefined in the project parameter setup, the
software identified and measured the eight fiducial
positions for all the frames. Upon completion, the results
were reviewed against the tolerance threshold.  Any
problems that occurred during the automatic interior
orientation will cause the software to reject the frame and
identify it as a potential problem. The operator then had
the option to measure the fiducials manually.
4. The operator launched the point selection software,
ZI Image Station Automated Triangulation (ISAT). The
software routine automatically correlates appropriate tie
and pass point locations based on the standard Von
Grueber locations. The correlation tool that is part of the
routine identified each point of contrast and then located
the same point on the adjacent frames using
autocorrelation techniques.  The operator then manually
located and measured the locations of the ground control
using ZI Image Station Digital Mensuration (ISDM)
interactive module.  The results of the ISAT run were then
reviewed. The project area was interactively accessed for
insufficient ties and poorly selected tie/pass points.  The
operator visited these locations and accepted or
refined the interpolated locations assisted by proprietary
software.  The interpolation tool can be turned on and off
by the operator depending on the type of land cover in the
triangulation block. Factors that influence the settings
include the amount of contrast and the sharpness of
features present on the photography.  The operator set the
search pattern in order to ensure that six points were
selected in each stereo model. In order to ensure maximum
strength of the final bundle adjustment, pass and tie points
were transferred across adjacent flight strips. A preliminary
adjustment was run to identify pass points that had high
residuals. This process was accomplished for each flight
line or partial flight line to ensure that the network has
sufficient levels of accuracy as the points were selected.
The points were visited and the cause for any inaccuracy
was identified and rectified.  This process also identified
any gaps where the point selection routine failed to
establish a point.  The operator interactively set any
missing points.
5. The control and pass point measurement data was
processed in ISAT, which was used for the final
adjustment.  The ISAT program created a results file with
the RMSE results for all points within the block and their
relation to one another. The photogrammetrist performing
the adjustments used their experience to determine what
course of action to take for any point falling outside
specifications.
6. The bundle adjustment was run through the ISAT ZI
Imaging Bundle Block Adjustment software several times.
7. The accuracy of the final solution was verified by
running the final adjustment, placing no constraints on any
quality control points.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Aerotriangulation</srcused>
        <procdate>20040923</procdate>
        <srcprod>Analytical Aerotriangulation</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>EarthData International, LLC</cntorg>
              <cntper>Scott Lane</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>7320 Executive Way</address>
              <city>Frederick</city>
              <state>Maryland</state>
              <postal>21704</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>301-948-8550</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>301-963-2064</cntfax>
            <cntemail>metadata@earthdata.com</cntemail>
            <hours>9 AM - 5 PM Mon. - Fri.</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
EarthData International, LLC utilized USGS downloaded
DEMs as its surface model for a small portion of the
orthophotography under this priority of the job.  However,
the majority of Juniata River priority area utilized previously
created DTM from a South Western Pennsylvania job
previously performed by EarthData International, LLC.  The
DTM file is composed of random data points (X,Y and Z)
and three dimensional breaklines.  The relationship of
points to breaklines and the density and position of points
will vary depending on the complexity and severity of the
terrain.  Breaklines are collected along the edges of roads,
stream banks and centerlines, ridges, and other features
where the slope of the terrain changes and where
necessary.  The previously existing DEM from the SW
Pennsylvania job also had bridge decks.  Where bridge
decks were present, EarthData clipped the DEM data
around the bridge decks.  This is a proven method which
eliminates some of the smearing around bridges in the
orthophotography.  The following step-by-step procedure
was utilized for DTM development.
1. DTM data was captured in the MicroStation
environment, which allowed the photogrammetrist to see
graphically where each single X, Y, and Z point and any
breaklines fall in relation to each other.  This unique
approach allowed for interactive editing of the point data
by the photogrammetrist as the DTM data was collected.
The data was then passed to the editing department for
fomatting.
2. The cartographic editor performed an accuracy
evaluation for each DTM file.  This step was accomplished
by a visual inspection of the dataset in profile view to
identify spikes or pits in the mass point information.  The
technician also verified that sufficient coverage exists for
each file to ensure full coverage for each completed
orthophoto.
3. Acceptable DTM data was used for digital orthophoto
production.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>DTM Mapping</srcused>
        <procdate>20040922</procdate>
        <srcprod>DTM</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>EarthData International, LLC</cntorg>
              <cntper>Scott Lane</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>7320 Executive Way</address>
              <city>Frederick</city>
              <state>Maryland</state>
              <postal>21704</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>301-948-8550</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>301-963-2064</cntfax>
            <cntemail>metadata@earthdata.com</cntemail>
            <hours>9 AM - 5 PM Mon. - Fri.</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The digital orthophotography was produced in 24-bit
natural color at a ratio of 1 in 4,800 with a 2 foot pixel
resolution.  A step-by-step breakdown of the digital
orthophoto production process follows.
1. A representative number of raster image files were
visually checked for image quality on the workstation.
2. The digital image files were oriented on the digital
orthophoto production workstation. The following
information was then loaded onto the workstation.
- The camera calibration parameters and flight line direction
- Ground control and pass point locations
- The exterior orientation parameters from the
aerotriangulation process
- ASCII file containing the corner coordinates of the
orthophotos
- The digital elevation model in a MGE format
- Project-specific requirements such as final tile size
and resolution.
-Orientation parameters developed from the
aerotriangulation solution.
A coordinate transformation based on the camera
calibration fiducial coordinates was then undertaken.  This
transformation allowed the conversion of every measured
element of the plates to a sample/line location. Each pixel
in an image was then referenced by sample and line (its
horizontal and vertical position) and matched to project
control.
3. DTM data was imported and written to the correct
subdirectory on disk.  The final digital orthophotos were
referenced to Pennsylvania State Plane, South Zone,
NAD83, NAVD88, in US Survey Feet.
4. The DTM file was re-inspected for missing or erroneous
data points.
5. A complete differential rectification was carried out
using a cubic convolution algorithm that removed image
displacement due to topographic relief, tip and tilt of the
aircraft at the moment of exposure, and radial distortion
within the camera.  Each final orthophoto was produced at
a natural scale of 1 in 4800 with a 2 foot pixel
resolution.  The digital orthophotos were partially imagery
filled with a black background outside a 1 mile buffer on
each side of the river banks.
6. Each digital orthophoto image was visually checked
for accuracy on the workstation screen.  Selected control
points (control panels or photoidentifiable points) that are
visible on the original film were visited on the screen, and
the X and Y coordinates of the location of the panel or
photoidentifiable point were measured.  This information
was cross-referenced with the X and Y information
provided by the original ground survey.  The digital
orthophotos were then edge-matched using proprietary
software that runs in Z/I Imaging OrthoPro software
package.  Adjoining images were displayed in alternating
colors of red and cyan.  In areas of exact overlap, the
image appears in gray-scale rendition.  Offsets were
colored red or cyan, depending on the angle of
displacement.  The operator panned down each overlap
line at a map scale to inspect the overlap area.
7. Once the orthos were inspected and approved for
accuracy, the files were copied to the network and
downloaded by the ortho finishing department. This
production unit was charged with radiometrically correcting
the orthophotos prior to completing the mosaicking and
clipping of the final tiles.  The image processing technician
performed a histogram analysis of several images that
contained different land forms (urban, agricultural, forested,
etc.) and established a histogram that best preserves detail
in highlight and shadow areas.  EarthData Intrernational
has developed a proprietary piece of software called
"Image Dodging."  This radiometric correction algorithm
was utilized in batch and interactive modes.  Used in this
fashion, this routine eliminated density changes due to sun
angle and changes in flight direction.  A block of images
were processed through image dodging, in batch mode
and displayed using Z/I Imaging OrthoPro software.  At this
point the images have been balanced internally, but there
are global differences in color and brightness that were
adjusted interactively.  The technician assigned correction
values for each orthophoto then displayed the corrected
files to assess the effectiveness of the adjustment. This
process was repeated until the match was considered near
seamless.  The files then were returned to digital
orthophoto production to mosaic the images.
8. The processed images were mosaicked using the Z/I
Imaging software.  The mosaic lines were set up
interactively by the technician and were placed in areas
that avoided buildings, bridges, elevated roadways, or
other features that would highlight the mosaic lines.  File
names were assigned.
9. The finishing department performed final visual checks
for orthophoto image quality.  The images were inspected
using Adobe Photoshop, which enabled the technician to
remove some imperfections.  However, the scope of this
emergency response limited the amount of intensive visual
checks in photoshop.
10. The final orthophoto images were written out into
TIFF format with the corresponding georeference files for
ESRI platforms.  Three MrSID files were also created for
the project.  The MrSID files were mosaiced from groups of
individual TIFFs.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Digital Orthophotography</srcused>
        <procdate>20040925</procdate>
        <srcprod>Digital Orthophotography</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>EarthData International, LLC</cntorg>
              <cntper>Scott Lane</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>7320 Executive Way</address>
              <city>Frederick</city>
              <state>Maryland</state>
              <postal>21704</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>301-948-8550</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>301-963-2064</cntfax>
            <cntemail>metadata@earthdata.com</cntemail>
            <hours>9 AM - 5 PM Mon. - Fri.</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <cloud>0</cloud>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Point</direct>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>Pennsylvania S. (3702)</spcszone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999995</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-077.750000</longcm>
              <latprjo>+39.333333</latprjo>
              <feast>600000.00</feast>
              <fnorth>0.0000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>2</absres>
            <ordres>2</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Survey Feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>1/298.2572221010</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Jim Knudson</cntper>
          <cntorg>State of Pennsylvania, Office for Information Technology</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Director of Geospatial Technologies</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>
State of Pennsylvania
Office for Information Technology
Governor's Office of Administration
210 Finance Building
</address>
          <city>Harrisburg</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>17120</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>717-346-1538</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>717-787-4523</cntfax>
        <cntemail>jknudson@state.pa.us</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F 9am to 5pm</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>None</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20041004</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>EarthData International, LLC</cntorg>
          <cntper>Scott Lane</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>7320 Executive Way</address>
          <city>Frederick</city>
          <state>Maryland</state>
          <postal>21704</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>301-948-8550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>301-963-2064</cntfax>
        <cntemail>metadata@earthdata.com</cntemail>
        <hours>9:00 AM - 5:00 PM (ET) M-F</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
  <Esri>
    <ModDate>20080612</ModDate>
    <ModTime>10550900</ModTime>
  </Esri>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20080612</mdDateSt>
</metadata>