<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.pasda.psu.edu/pasda/uci_metadata/dtd/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Aero-Metric, Inc.</origin>
        <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
        <title>USGS High Resolution Orthoimagery for Scranton - Wilkes Barre, Pennsylvania - TILE INDEX</title>
        <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>High Resolution Orthoimagery</sername>
          <issue>0.1</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>The data obtained through The National Map is considered to be the "best available" data from USGS. Information in quotation marks, initial processing steps, accuracy reports, and source information is taken directly from the original metadata.</othercit>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu</onlink>
        <onlink>http://gisdata.usgs.gov/tdds/downloadfile.php?TYPE=ortho&amp;ORIG=META&amp;FNAME=18TVL395720_201203_0x3000m_CL_1.zip</onlink>
        <onlink>http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>201203</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-75.7227707588481</westbc>
        <eastbc>-75.7047066623471</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.310806106399</northbc>
        <southbc>41.2971844194145</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>digital spatial data</themekey>
        <themekey>0.3 meter orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>rectified image</themekey>
        <themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>natural color orthophoto</themekey>
        <themekey>orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>image map</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>010</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote
Sensing</themekt>
        <themekey>National Standards for Spatial Digital Accuracy (NSSDA)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard 10-4,): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>U.S.</placekey>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the identification of the States, the District of Columbia and the outlying areas of the United States, and associated areas (Federal Information Processing Standard 5-2): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</placekt>
        <placekey>PA</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Counties and County Equivalents of the States of the United States and the District of Columbia (FIPS Pub 6-3)</placekt>
        <placekey>Luzerne County</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
        <placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Any downloading and use of these data signifies a user's agreement to comprehension and compliance of the USGS Standard Disclaimer.  Insure all portions of metadata are read and clearly understood before using these data in order to protect both user and USGS interests.</accconst>
    <useconst>"None. However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions.  Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full awareness of it's limitations. Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated for products derived from these data." There is no guarantee of warranty concerning the accuracy of the data.  Users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions.  Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full awareness of its limitations.  Acknowledgement of the originating agencies would be appreciated in products derived from these data.  Any user who modifies the data is obligated to describe the types of modifications they perform.  User specifically agrees not to misrepresent the data, nor to imply that changes made were approved or endorsed by the U.S. Geological Survey.  Please refer to http://www.usgs.gov/privacy.html for the USGS disclaimer.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
      <browsen>http://tdds.cr.usgs.gov/browse/ortho/18T/VL/18TVL395720_201203_0x3000m_CL_1.jpg</browsen>
      <browsed>Tiled High Resolution Orthoimagery (HRO)</browsed>
      <browset>JPEG</browset>
    </browse>
    <datacred>U.S. Geological Survey and Aero-Metric, Inc.</datacred>
    <secinfo>
      <secsys>None</secsys>
      <secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
      <sechandl>N/A</sechandl>
    </secinfo>
    <native>"Intergraph OrthoPro ver 6.01, IRAS C ver 10.0, Photoshop ver CS5,  Windows XP and Windows 7, INPHO OrthoVista 4.6, Global Mapper 13, Bentley MicroStation 7 and 8" 

Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
    <descript>
      <abstract>NGA_USGS_ScrantonWilkesBarre2012_TileIndex</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Radiometry is verified by visual inspection of the digital orthophoto.  Slight systematic radiometric differences may exist between adjacent orthoimage files; these are due primarily to differences in source image capture dates and sun angles along flight lines.  These differences can be observed in an image's general lightness or darkness when it is compared to adjacent orthoimage file coverages. Tonal balancing may be performed over a group of images during the mosaicking process which may serve to lighten or darken adjacent images for better color tone matching.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>"GeoTIFFs conform to the specifications set forth by the USGS for production of orthophotos in the Task Order Number G12PD00343." 

Logical consistency is implicit in the raster image data structure. Source imagery is cloud free.</logic>
    <complete>"Orthoimages are visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no gaps or image misplacements exist within and between adjacent images. These images are derived by mosaicking multiple images to ensure complete coverage. Source imagery is cloud free."</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>"The 0.30 meter ortho image horizontal accuracy does not exceed 1.52-meters NSSDA 95% confidence (0.88-meters Root Mean Squared (RMSE) Error XY (0.62 meter RMSE X or Y)." 

The relative accuracy is assembled by comparing rectified images generated from adjacent strips of imagery. The absolute accuracy is assessed by measuring the ground control points in the rectified image against the actual surveyed co-ordinate position. The testing is for overall accuracy.  This data has been produced to be fully compliant with the National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS) for mapping at this scale.</horizpar>
        <qhorizpa>
          <horizpav>0.86</horizpav>
          <horizpae>The horizontal accuracy of the orthorectified images is mainly determined by the quality of the DEM. The elevation data was provided by the PAMAP website. Airborne GPS/IMU data was used. All photo identifiable checkpoints were measured and compared to the surveyed checkpoints to determine the RMSE. All rectified chip overlap was checked for mismatch. All final tiles were checked visually for edge matching.</horizpae>
        </qhorizpa>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical accuracy of the airborne GPS control was tested through the aerotriangulation and vertical positions were adjusted to best fit the GPS ground control in the final aerotriangulation.</vertaccr>
        <qvertpa>
          <vertaccv>0.008</vertaccv>
          <vertacce>The vertical accuracy of the airborne GPS control does not exceed the 0.3 meter requirement.</vertacce>
        </qvertpa>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>AeroMetric, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
            <title>088003</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20120404</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Image</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source imagery for orthophoto production.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>AeroMetric, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
            <title>088004</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20120404</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Image</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source imagery for orthophoto production.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>PAMAP</origin>
            <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
            <title>PAMAP Dataset</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2012</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DEM</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Used to provide ground elevations for orthorectification process.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>AeroMetric, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>2012</pubdate>
            <title>Scranton / Wilkes-Barre Area Aerotriangulation</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>201208</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>AT</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Used to provide photo exterior orientations for orthorectification process.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>"The digital images were aero-triangulated to support digital ortho image production for the Scranton / Wilkes-Barre, PA project area.  Ground check point data was provided by AeroMetric, Inc.  The project was referenced to the North American Datum of 1983 (NAD83), UTM Zone 18 horizontally and to the North American Vertical Datum of 1988 (NAVD88) vertically.  Units were in meters.

The images, ABGPS/IMU data, and ground check point data were used as inputs to the Zeiss/Intergraph ImageStation Automatic Triangulation (ISAT) softcopy program.  ISAT correlated image points and aerotriangulated the block of images to create exposure station exterior orientations.  All ground points were manually measured on the imagery.  These points were included in the aerotriangulation adjustments for absolute ground location verification.

The scale of the aerial photos was 1"=2116'.  The photography was exposed between 3/21/12 and 4/7/12.

Rectification was done using the aerotriangulation data, raw images, and PAMAP DEM data.  These rectified images were used to generate seamlines which were then reviewed and edited. The rectified images were mosaicked, balanced, and cut into final image sheets.  The final sheets were viewed and artifacts were removed as well as other edits performed."</procdesc>
        <procdate>201208</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Data received at Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS) were verified as:
Projection:   NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_18N
Resolution:  0.3000 m
Type:  Natural Color
and resampled to align to the U.S. National Grid (USNG). The naming convention is based on the U.S. National Grid (USNG), taking the coordinates of the SW corner of the orthoimage.   The naming convention is based on the U.S. National Grid (USNG), taking the coordinates of the SW corner of the orthoimage.  The metadata were imported and updated for display through The National Map Server at &lt;http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html&gt;    Chip-level metadata are provided in XML and HTML format. Data were compressed utilizing IAS software. The compression was JPEG2000 Lossy Compressed. The file format created was .jp2.</procdesc>
        <procdate>201210</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
              <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
              <city>Reston</city>
              <state>VA</state>
              <postal>20192</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
            <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
            <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
            <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>5000</rowcount>
      <colcount>5000</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>18</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-75.0000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
              <feast>500,000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.3000</absres>
            <ordres>0.3000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum>
        <altres>1.00000</altres>
        <altunits>meters</altunits>
        <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>Natural color orthoimagery is organized in three color bands or channels which represent the red, green, and blue portions of the spectrum.  Each image pixel is assigned a triplet of numeric values, one for each color band.  Numeric values range from 0 to 255. Areas where data is incomplete due to lack of full image coverage are represented with the numeric value of 0.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, 1999, Standards for Digital Orthoimagery: Reston, VA</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the USGS, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the USGS regarding the use of the data on any other system, nor does the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.  Data may have been compiled from various outside sources.  Spatial information may not meet National Map Accuracy Standards.  This information may be updated without notification. The USGS shall not be liable for any activity involving these data, installation, fitness of the data for a particular purpose, its use, or analyses results.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>JP2</formname>
          <formvern>ArcGIS 9.3</formvern>
          <formspec>Raster</formspec>
          <transize>0.001</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>The URL http://nationalmap.gov/viewer.html provides a map interface that allows for viewing and data downloads within a customer defined area of interest. Zoom tools are available that can be used to investigate areas of interest on the map interface. The download tool allows the customer to capture layers from the map, utilizing The National Map process for downloading. The generated zip file can be unzipped and imported into various user software applications.</accinstr>
            <oncomp>Not available for dissemination</oncomp>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <turnarnd>Variable</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>ESRI ArcGIS Suite and/or Arc/Info or other compatible software, and supporting operating systems.</techpreq>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>2012</begdate>
          <enddate>unknown</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2012</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Services Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>USGS National Geospatial Program Office</address>
          <address>12201 Sunrise Valley Drive</address>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <state>VA</state>
          <postal>20192</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntvoice>Unknown</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>Unknown</cntfax>
        <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
        <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/ to contact us.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
    <metsi>
      <metscs>None</metscs>
      <metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
      <metshd>None</metshd>
    </metsi>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA)</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cnttdd>pasda@psu.edu</cnttdd>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>    The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <Esri>
    <CreaDate>20131022</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>11031500</CreaTime>
    <ArcGISstyle>ISO 19139 Metadata Implementation Specification</ArcGISstyle>
    <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
    <DataProperties>
      <itemProps>
        <itemLocation>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\ALCES\D$\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_ScrantonWilkesBarre2012_TileIndex</linkage>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
        </itemLocation>
      </itemProps>
      <copyHistory>
        <copy source="D:\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_ScrantonWilkesBarre2012_TileIndex" dest="\\ALCES\D$\DATA\NGA\NGA_USGS_ScrantonWilkesBarre2012_TileIndex" date="20131022" time="11031500">
        </copy>
      </copyHistory>
    </DataProperties>
  </Esri>
</metadata>