<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Penn State Altoona - Roads_unpaved</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>http://www.datacommons.psu.edu/</onlink>
        <pubdate>2016</pubdate>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-78.416792</westbc>
        <eastbc>-78.404900</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.545000</northbc>
        <southbc>40.534551</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords />
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The user shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend the Commonwealth, the University, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation.
				
				The University excludes any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose.
				
				The University makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance.
				
				The University will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.
				
The USER is granted permission to translate and add value to the FILES for the use of the FILES on its computer hardware; provided, however, that the USER annually notify the University of any customizing or value-adding work done.</useconst>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.0.2414</native>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>John Richendrfer</cntper>
          <cntorg>Penn State - Office of Physical Plant</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntemail>jdr20@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <descript>
      <abstract>PSU_OPP_Altoona_Roads_unpaved2016</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>16</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>39.93333333333333</stdparll>
            <stdparll>40.96666666666667</stdparll>
            <longcm>-77.75</longcm>
            <latprjo>39.33333333333334</latprjo>
            <feast>1968500.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000026907964745248598</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000026907964745248598</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Foot_US</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D NAD 1983 2011</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>PSU_OPP_Altoona_Roads_unpaved2016</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LAYER</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_Leng</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2016</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Penn State Data Commons</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water Building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>datacommons@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Penn State Data Commons</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water Building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>datacommons@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metd>2016</metd>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>