<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Homeland Security</origin>
        <origin>TechniGraphics, Inc.</origin>
        <pubdate>20090629</pubdate>
        <title>
FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN: Fire Stations in Indiana as Developed for the Homeland Security Infrastructure Program
(Indiana Department of Homeland Security, Point Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Homeland Security</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
This data set was provided to personnel of the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) by Indiana Department of Homeland
Security (IDHS) personnel. The data set provided was in an ESRI shapefile format, and was named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp"
on June 29, 2009. "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp" was originally prepared in March 2009 for IDHS by TechniGraphics, Inc. (TGS),
Wooster, Ohio, 44691. TGS included the following statement to IDHS upon delivery of "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"This dataset includes any location where fire fighters are stationed or based out of, or where equipment that such personnel
use in carrying out their jobs is stored for ready use. Fire Departments not having a permanent location are included, in
which case their location has been depicted at the city/town hall or at the center of their service area if a city/town hall
does not exist. This dataset includes those locations primarily engaged in forest or grasslands fire fighting, including fire
lookout towers if the towers are in current use for fire protection purposes. This dataset includes both private and governmental
entities. Fire fighting training academies are also included.

"TGS has made a concerted effort to include all fire stations in Indiana."
</othercit>
        <onlink>Downloadable data</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN is a point shapefile that contains locations of fire station, as developed for the Homeland Security
Infrastructure Program (HSIP). The data were provided by personnel of Indiana Department of Homeland Security (IDHS) on June 29, 2009.
This data set was provided by IDHS in ESRI shapefile format and was named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp."

The following is a description of the Homeland Security Infrastructure Program (HSIP) provided by personnel of the Indiana Geographic
Information Council (IGIC):

"Homeland Security Infrastructure Program (HSIP)

After September 11, 2001, federal decision makers needed a single place to go for geospatial data. The National Geospatial-Intelligence
Agency (NGA) stood up a tiger team to determine the type of information needed for the nation’s critical infrastructure and developed an
acquisition strategy to provide that data to the federal community. The Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data (HIFLD) Working
Group provided guidance in the development of the Homeland Security Infrastructure Program (HSIP). There are currently two different
version of HSIP data: HSIP Gold and HSIP Freedom.

"HSIP Gold:  Designed to combine all geospatial data, and Geospatial Intelligence products into a single, integrated database. HSIP Gold
is a collection of base map layers and homeland security related geospatial data. There are many sources, including licensed commodity
datasets and Federal &amp; State agency data. The HSIP Gold data was created for Federal government homeland security and homeland defense purposes.
These data are only available to state and local governments for viewing purposes across a thin client network. This is referred to as
“disclosure” in the Federal licensing agreements with the private sector contributors. However, Federal licenses also require that in the
event of declared emergencies, that the data may be released to state and local governments to support their operations. Non-government
organizations can not access the HSIP Gold data.

"HSIP Freedom: NGA’s goal is to provide complete datasets with no limits on distribution to state and local responders. The challenge is
the private-sector license restrictions. NGA came up with different approach – HSIP Freedom where state and local government provide data
to DHS or NGA, which could be improved and returned to state and locals so they can get benefit from that data. Then the states would be
able to look at same data as federal government and distribute it as they see fit.

"The current emphasis of the HSIP Freedom program is on sharing and improving data to create uniform State &amp; Federal information on: Fire
Stations, EMS Stations &amp; Ambulance Services, Police Stations, Prisons &amp; Jails, Hospitals &amp; Urgent Care Clinics. TechniGraphicS, Inc. (TGS)
was the contractor to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) for development of this HSIP Freedom data. Most improvements to
date have been done by TGS telephoning local officials to verify the name, address, phone number, and geospatial location of their facilities.
Geospatial location is determined by asking the local official to describe their location relative to landmarks visible in orthoimagery.
TGS incorporates the improved State data into the "License Free” HSIP Freedom product and makes it available to the states. They also incorporate
the improved State data into HSIP Gold and deliver it to NGA. States are encouraged to share these improved data with the U.S. Geological Survey
for use in The National Map and for the new generation of graphic products being produced at USGS for emergency responders."

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"Fire Stations in Indiana

"Any location where fire fighters are stationed or based out of, or where equipment that such personnel use in carrying out their jobs
is stored for ready use. Fire Departments not having a permanent location are included, in which case their location has been depicted
at the city/town hall or at the center of their service area if a city/town hall does not exist. This dataset includes those locations
primarily engaged in forest or grasslands fire fighting, including fire lookout towers if the towers are in current use for fire
protection purposes. This dataset includes both private and governmental entities. Fire fighting training academies are also included.

"This dataset is comprised completely of license free data.

"The Fire Station dataset and the EMS dataset were merged into one working file.  TGS processed as one file and then separated
for delivery purposes.

"Records with "-DOD" appended to the end of the [NAME] value are located on a military base, as defined by the Defense
Installation Spatial Data Infrastructure (DISDI) military installations and military range boundaries.

"Text fields in this dataset have been set to all upper case to facilitate consistent database engine search results.

"All diacritics (e.g., the German umlaut or the Spanish tilde) have been replaced with their closest equivalent English character
to facilitate use with database systems that may not support diacritics.

"The currentness of this dataset is indicated by the [CONTDATE] field. Based upon this field, the oldest record dates from 01/04/2005
and the newest record dates from 08/19/2008."
</abstract>
      <purpose>
FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN was developed to provide accurate locations of fire stations in Indiana.

The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"Homeland Security

"Use Cases: Use cases describe how the data may be used and help to define and clarify requirements.

"1. An assessment of whether or not the total fire fighting capability in a given area is adequate.

"2. A list of resources to draw upon by surrounding areas when local resources have temporarily been overwhelmed by
a disaster - route analysis can determine those entities that are able to respond the quickest.

"3. A resource for Emergency Management planning purposes.

"4. A resource for catastrophe response to aid in the retrieval of equipment by outside responders in order to deal with the disaster.

"5. A resource for situational awareness planning and response for Federal Government events."
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20090629</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Based on the publication date for the source shapefile "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp."</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-87.978812</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.811358</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.751261</northbc>
        <southbc>37.860458</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological Survey (IGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Homeland Security (IDHS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Geographic Information Council (IGIC)</themekey>
        <themekey>Homeland Security Infrastructure Program (HSIP)</themekey>
        <themekey>TechniGraphics, Inc. (TGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Airplane ambulance</themekey>
        <themekey>Ambulance</themekey>
        <themekey>Ambulance service</themekey>
        <themekey>Emergency medical service</themekey>
        <themekey>Emergency medical personnel</themekey>
        <themekey>Fire department</themekey>
        <themekey>Fire station</themekey>
        <themekey>Helicopter ambulance</themekey>
        <themekey>Search and rescue operation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>IGS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>DeKalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Roger Koelpin</cntper>
          <cntorg>Indiana Department of Homeland Security</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>GIS/CI Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>302 West Washington Street, Rm E208</address>
          <city>Indianapolis</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>46204</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>317-232-0181</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>317-233-5006</cntfax>
        <cntemail>rkoelpin@dhs.in.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>
ESRI ArcGIS version 9.3.1.3000 shapefile format, approximately 2.4 Mb
Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.0 (Build 26001) Service Pack 1, ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3000
</native>
    <useconst>Infrastructure--Critical_Facilities_IDHS_Fire_Stations</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"For entities that were contacted, the name, address, city, state, and five (5) digit zip codes were verified to be correct as of
the date indicated by the [CONTDATE] field. The existence of the entity was also verified, as well as whether or not it met
the criteria for inclusion in this dataset. Four (4) digit zip code extensions were derived from USPS (United States Postal Service)
data and were not verified.

"ID Check: The [ID] field is not blank and each of its values is unique.

"Coordinate Check: Coordinates are not null or zero and the x and y fields match the shape.

"Basic Address Check: Physical addresses were verified to be non blank and to not be a "PO Box", "General Delivery", "Highway Contract",
or "Rural Route" address.

"Highway Address without Type Check: Physical addresses containing the word "Highway" or "Route" were verified to also contain a type
designator such as "State", "US", or "County", if one actually exists for the highway or route. These type designators are often missing
from addresses, leading to confusion if more than one "Highway" of the given number exists in an area.

"Basic Name Check: Entity name is not blank, is not the same as entity city, and has a minimum of 2 characters. Name does not contain
punctuation characters that can interfere with database operations, such as " (quote) and * (asterisk).

"City Check: Entity's [CITY] field is not blank, and entity is located within 25 miles of its tabular city as found in the NAVTEQ
Named Places reference file.

"State Check: The entity is located within its tabular state.

"County FIPS to State Compare Check: The county represented by the tabular FIPS Code is actually in the state specified in the [STATE] field.

"County Name to State Compare Check: The county represented by the tabular county name is actually in the state specified in the [STATE] field.

"Basic Phone Check: All phone numbers (including the area code) are ten (10) numeric digits. Alphabetic characters have been converted to
the corresponding numeric digit.

"NPA_NXX Check: Area codes (sometimes called "Number Planning Areas", or NPA's) and central office codes (sometimes known as exchanges, or NXX's)
were validated against data from the North American Number Planning Administration (NANPA). In some cases, NPA-NXX combinations did not show up
in the NANPA data but were verified to work.

"Area Code Distance Check: The entity's area code (NPA) is valid, and the entity is not more than 25 miles from its area code boundary, as
defined by data from the North American Number Planning Administration (NANPA), unless TGS has previously verified that the phone number
rings to a headquarters location or otherwise does not ring to the entity's location.

"Zip Code Check: The zip code is five (5) or nine (9) numeric digits, is listed in the postal database, is in the same state as indicated
by the entity's [STATE] value, and is not a PO Box only zip code.

"Zip City Check: The entity's zip code and its city were verified to match according to the USPS Address Information System (AIS).

"Zip Code Distance Check: The entity is located within 25 miles of its zip code boundary, as defined by the U.S. Census Bureau's 1999 Zip Code file.

"NAICS Code Check: The NAICS field is not blank, the NAICS Code is one of the accepted codes for this layer, the NAICS Description is an acceptable
Index Entry for the NAICS Code, and certain key words in the entity name do not conflict with the NAICS Code.

"Collocation Check: Entities with different addresses must not share the exact same geospatial location.

"Geographic Spell Check: Words that appear in the entity name were checked against a standard English word list (and Spanish word list for
entities in Puerto Rico). Words not appearing in these standard word lists were then checked against names appearing in the Geographic Names
Information System (GNIS) of geographic features that are located within 25 miles of the entity. Proper names were manually reviewed for correct
spelling."
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"See "Attribute_Accuracy_Report". Many of the checks described in that section check for both attribute accuracy and logical
consistency."
</logic>
    <complete>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"Administrative Locations - Locations that serve only an administrative function (e.g., a business office) are intended to be
excluded from this dataset. Locations that serve both an administrative function as well as an operational function are included in the dataset."
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
The following is excerpted from the metadata provided by IDHS for the source shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp":

"The geographic location of entities was verified to be correct relative to the street data and version indicated by the
[ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION] fields. The horizontal accuracy is indicated by the [GEOPREC] field. A value of "BLOCKFACE" indicates
the entity was geocoded on the correct street segment (block) and correct side of the street. A value of "ONENTITY" indicates that
the location is on the entity's facility, as determined by USGS DOQQ imagery, and that it is on the correct street segment (block)
and correct side of the street. Entities that are part of a larger institution (e.g., University Campus or Military Base) with
"BLOCKFACE" precision may be located at the main entrance to the larger institution.

"Records with "-DOD" appended to the end of the [NAME] value are located on a military base, as defined by the Defense
Installation Spatial Data Infrastructure (DISDI) military installations and military range boundaries.

"Fire Departments not having a permanent location are depicted at the city/town hall or at the center of the town or service
area if a city/town hall does not exist."
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Not applicable (2-D data only).</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Homeland Security</origin>
            <pubdate>20090629</pubdate>
            <title>2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp</title>
            <edition>1</edition>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>IDHS</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
This data set was provided to IGS personnel from IDHS personnel on June 29, 2009 to provide the
accurate locations of fire stations for the citizens of Indiana.
</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>ESRI shapefile</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20090629</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Fire station locations in Indiana, with basic attribute information such as name, address, city, state, zip code, and telephone number.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
IGS personnel received an ESRI shapefile named "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp" from IDHS personnel (Roger Koelpin) on June 29, 2009.
"2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp" was loaded into ESRI ArcMap 9.3.1 and the data were examined for completeness. "2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp"
was reprojected using ESRI ArcToolBox from WGS_1984 to Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM) Zone 16, NAD 83. The shapefile was then renamed
to FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN.SHP to conform to IGS naming conventions.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>2008_09_20_IN_Firestations.shp</srcused>
        <procdate>20090629</procdate>
        <srcprod>FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata
Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated
by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution"
and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20090710</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1233</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN.DBF</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique identifier for feature</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SECCLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Security classification of feature</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>UNCLASSIFIED</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is unclassified</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TELEPHONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Ten (10) digit telephone number for entity formatted as nnn-nnn-nnnn</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ADDRESS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Physical street address for entity. "PO Box", "General Delivery", "Rural Route", and "Highway Contract"
addresses are not considered physical addresses and should not appear in this field. Some areas do not have regular city
style addressing, so entities in those areas may not have a street number. In such cases, the name of the road on which
they are located is listed in this field. Some rural areas may not have named roads. In these rare cases, this field will be blank.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ADDRESS2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Location within physical address, e.g., floor, suite, building</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CITY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The name of the city associated with the entity's physical address. For physical addresses that the U.S. Postal Service (USPS)
delivers to, this should be a "city" acceptable to the USPS as defined in their Address Information System (AIS). Sometimes the
USPS does not deliver mail to a physical address but recognizes the location (i.e., they list the location as "undeliverable").
The cities associated with these locations are acceptable. In some cases, the USPS does not recognize individual physical
addresses in a city, rather, they list the city as having "General Delivery". In these cases, the city and associated zip code
are acceptable (the entity's [ADDRESS] field will contain a street address, not "general delivery"). The entity may not actually
be located within the city limits of the "city" specified in its [CITY] field. Instead, it may actually be located within the city
limits of another city. In some cases, the "city" that appears in this field may not even be a city in an administrative sense, but
it is still an acceptable "city" to the USPS. An example of this is "Notre Dame, IN". There is no city in Indiana called "Notre Dame",
but this is considered an acceptable city by the USPS for any delivery going to the University of Notre Dame which is actually located
in the city of South Bend. "Notre Dame", like most USPS cities, is an easily recognized place, and it gives the user of the data a good
general idea of where the entity is located (if the entity is located in a small municipality, the USPS "city" may be more recognizable
than the name of the municipality), and it would be part of the address one would use to send a shipment to the entity's location.
Using the USPS acceptable "city" also allows someone to do a logical consistency check between the zip code and the city by using the USPS AIS.

Sometimes an entity may report a city that is not accepted by the USPS, and although TGS has tried to replace those cities with an
acceptable alternative, some of them may remain in this dataset.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Two character abbreviation for state associated with the entity's physical address. In almost all cases, this is the same as the state
where the entity has been depicted geospatially. However, there are cases, particularly where an entity is part of a larger facility
that cuts across state lines, where the entity's location may be depicted in a state other than the one indicated in this field. Also,
the state in which an entity appears to be located may change depending on the scale of the state boundary theme being used.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Official USPS Abbreviations - State Abbreviations</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Postal Service http://www.usps.com/ncsc/lookups/usps_abbreviations.html</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ZIP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Five (5) digit USPS zip code for entity's physical location</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USPS Address Information System - Domain is further restricted by only allowing physical (non PO Box) zip codes</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ZIPP4</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Four (4) digit USPS zip code extension. These values are automatically assigned using the entity's physical address
and USPS address information system (AIS) data.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>USPS Address Information System (AIS) - ZIP9</codesetn>
            <codesets>United States Postal Service</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>County name where entity is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</codesetn>
            <codesets>US Department of the Interior - US Geologic Survey</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Five (5) digit FIPS (Federal Information Processing Standards) Code for the County where entity is located.
The first two (2) digits represent the state and the last three (3) digits identify the county within the state.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards Publications - Counties and Equivalent Entities of the U.S., Its Possessions, and Associated Areas</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;http://www.itl.nist.gov/fipspubs/co-codes/states.txt&gt;</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DIRECTIONS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Directions to entity location, or description of the entity's location</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMERGTITLE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Title of person or name of office for emergency point of contact</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMERGTEL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Telephone number of emergency point of contact formatted as nnn-nnn-nnnn.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMERGEXT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Telephone extension for emergency point of contact</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CONTDATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date entity was contacted by TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Date</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CONTHOW</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Method by which entity was contacted</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PHONE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was contacted by phone</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FAX</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was contacted by fax</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>MAIL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was contacted by mail</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>EMAIL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was contacted by email</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>WEB</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity information was gathered and/or verified by official entity website as a last resort</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ALT REF</edomv>
            <edomvd>Geospatial reference information obtained from local authorities, e.g., downloadable parcel maps, 911 streets, and shape files</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity has not been contacted by TGS</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GEODATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date entity was geocoded by TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Date</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GEOHOW</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Method by which entity was geocoded</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AUTO</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was automatically geocoded</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>MANUAL</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was manually geocoded</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ADJUSTED</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Entity was shifted by TechniGraphics, Inc. to an updated set of NAVTEQ streets. This
only applies if the entity was manually geocoded by TechniGraphics, Inc. to a previous version of NAVTEQ streets.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PROVIDED</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity was geocoded using coordinates provided by the original source</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAICSCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
NAICS (North American Industry Classification System) Code for entity. NAICS Codes (and NAICS Descriptions) have been
assigned based upon the entity's primary function, regardless of if that is the function that qualified it to be included in this dataset.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>North American Industry Classification System (NAICS 2007)</codesetn>
            <codesets>US Census Bureau - &lt;http://www.census.gov/epcd/www/naics.html&gt;</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAICSDESCR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
NAICS (North American Industry Classification System) Description for entity. The "Index Entries" that appear on the NAICS webpage
(http://www.census.gov/epcd/www/naics.html&gt;) are being used to populate this field, as opposed to the "NAICS Title". While there is a
one to one correspondence between NAICS Codes and "NAICS Titles", there is a one to many relationship between NAICS Codes and the
"Index Entries". By using the "Index Entries", we have placed the entities that make up this layer into more specific categories;
however, the user of this data should be aware that this was not the intended purpose of these "Index Entries". The "Index Entries" were
intended as a way to search the NAICS database and as a way of enumerating ways in which establishments falling under the given NAICS Code
may be named. Thus, there are often two or more "Index Entries" that are synonyms, for example: "Prisons" and "Penitentiaries". In cases
like this, we have standardized on one "Index Entry".

NAICS Descriptions (and NAICS Codes) have been assigned based upon the entity's primary function, regardless of if that is the function
that qualified it to be included in this dataset.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AIR AMBULANCE SERVICES</edomv>
            <edomvd>
AIR AMBULANCE SERVICES - [NAICS Code 621910]: Entities that are primarily engaged in providing
transportation of patients by air that have medical care capabilities are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AMBULANCE AND FIRE SERVICE COMBINED</edomv>
            <edomvd>
AMBULANCE AND FIRE SERVICE COMBINED - [NAICS Code 922160]: Entities providing ambulance services
with fire protection service are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AMBULANCE SERVICES, AIR OR GROUND</edomv>
            <edomvd>
AMBULANCE SERVICES, AIR OR GROUND - [NAICS Code 621910]: Entities that are primarily engaged in
providing transportation of patients by ground or air that have medical care capabilities are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIRE AND RESCUE SERVICE</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIRE AND RESCUE SERVICE - [NAICS Code 922160]: Entities that are involved in fire fighting and
rescue service are classified under this description, unless they are privately owned or primarily involved in forest fire fighting.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIRE DEPARTMENTS (E.G., GOVERNMENT, VOLUNTEER (EXCEPT PRIVATE))</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIRE DEPARTMENTS (E.G., GOVERNMENT, VOLUNTEER (EXCEPT PRIVATE)) - [NAICS Code 922160]: Entities that
are involved in fire fighting are classified under this description, unless they are privately owned, are primarily involved in forest
fire fighting, or also operate a rescue service.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIREFIGHTING, FOREST</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIREFIGHTING, FOREST - [NAICS Code 115310]: Entities that are primarily involved in forest fire fighting
are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIRE FIGHTER TRAINING SCHOOLS</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIRE FIGHTER TRAINING SCHOOLS - [NAICS Code 611519]: Entities that are primarily involved in training
fire fighters are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIRE FIGHTING SERVICES AS A COMMERCIAL ACTIVITY</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIRE FIGHTING SERVICES AS A COMMERCIAL ACTIVITY - [NAICS Code 561990]: Entities providing fire protection
for a commercial facility are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>FIRE MARSHALS' OFFICES</edomv>
            <edomvd>
FIRE MARSHALS' OFFICES - [NAICS Code 922160]: Entities that are fire marshals' offices are classified
under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS, COMBINED</edomv>
            <edomvd>
POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS, COMBINED - [NAICS Code 922120]: Entities providing combined police and fire
protection service are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>PRIVATE VOLUNTEER FIRE FIGHTING</edomv>
            <edomvd>
PRIVATE VOLUNTEER FIRE FIGHTING - [NAICS Code 561990]: Entities providing fire fighting services that are
privately owned and whose fire fighters are volunteers are classified under this description.
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GEOLINKID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Link ID for the street segment to which the entity was geocoded. Refer to the [ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION] fields for the street
vendor and version that was used to geocode the entity.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>X</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude in WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-180</rdommin>
            <rdommax>180</rdommax>
            <attrunit>WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Y</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude in WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-90</rdommin>
            <rdommax>90</rdommax>
            <attrunit>WGS 84 Decimal Degrees</attrunit>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ST_VENDOR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates name of vendor providing original street data used for geocoding</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NAVTEQ</edomv>
            <edomvd>NAVTEQ streets were used for geocoding</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomv>
            <edomvd>TechniGraphics, Inc. drew in a new street segment that does not exist in the file supplied by NAVTEQ</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TIGER</edomv>
            <edomvd>TIGER/Line streets were used for geocoding</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ST_VERSION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates the year and quarter of streets used for geocoding</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2008Q1</edomv>
            <edomvd>1st Quarter 2008 NAVTEQ street data was used for geocoding</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>2006FE</edomv>
            <edomvd>2006fe version of TIGER/Line streets were used for geocoding in areas where NAVTEQ does not have coverage</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GEOPREC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Geocoding precision</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>BLOCKFACE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is geocoded to correct block and correct side of street per street data indicated by [ST_VENDOR] and [ST_VERSION]</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>ONENTITY</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is geocoded on entity rooftop per aerial imagery (in most cases USGS DOQQs)</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PHONELOC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates whether the phone number in the [TELEPHONE] field rings to the actual location of the entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>YES</edomv>
            <edomvd>Phone number rings to the actual entity location</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>NO</edomv>
            <edomvd>Phone number does not ring to the actual entity location, it may ring to an administrative office or central location</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unknown - It is not known if the entity's phone number rings to the entity's location</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>QC_QA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Organization that performed Quality Control/Quality Assurance on the record</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>TGS</edomv>
            <edomvd>
TechniGraphics, Inc. has performed Quality Control/Quality Assurance on all TGS added records and all
records contacted since 01/01/2005
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
            <edomvd>
The record is not TGS added or has not had Quality Control/Quality Assurance performed by TGS, or
Quality Control/Quality Assurance was performed prior to 01/01/2005
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
State Hospital Data ID. For states that contributed data, this field is populated with the unique ID used by the state to track fire
stations.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FDID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
A unique five-character identifier assigned by the state to identify a particular fire department within the state. The
first two characters designate the county and the last three designate the department within the county. This identifier is only unique within
each state, not nationwide.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FRST_MBRS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of fire fighter members associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came
from individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMS_MBRS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of EMS members associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTALPERS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of members associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc..
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NUMTRKS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of fire trucks associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc..
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NUMABUL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of ambulances associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOTAL_VEHI</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Total number of vehicles associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc..
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TGSTechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NBR_STA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The total number of stations associated with the DEPARTMENT. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The type of ownership for the entity. The values that this field is populated with came from individual states
and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc..
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEVEL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Indicates the level of medical services provided. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc..
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Type of employees. The values that this field is populated with came from individual states and have not
been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SPECIALTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Indicates any type of specialty unit available at the facility. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMSLICENSE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
License number for EMS agency provided by the state. The values that this field is populated with came from
individual states and have not been validated or checked by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMERPHONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Emergency Contact Number as provided by individual states. Some values also include telephone extensions and/or
alternate telephone numbers.  All alphabetic characters have been translated to the corresponding numeric digit. The values in
this field have not been verified by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Indicates if the entity also has EMS capabilities</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Y</edomv>
            <edomvd>Indicates the entity has EMS capabilities</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>N</edomv>
            <edomvd>Indicates the entity does not have EMS capabilities</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>&lt;BLANK&gt;</edomv>
            <edomvd>Unable to determine if entity has EMS capabilities</edomvd>
            <edomvds>TechniGraphics, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERM_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The unique permanent identifier of The National Structures Dataset. The values in this field have not been
verified by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
The unique permanent identifier of the Geographic Names Information System that is up to eight (8) digits in
length and unique within the nation. The values in this field have not been verified by TechniGraphics, Inc.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>TechniGraphics, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT:

It is requested that the Indiana Department of Homeland Security (IDHS) be cited in any products generated from
this data set. The following source citation should be included: [FIRE_STATIONS_HSIP_IDHS_IN: Fire Stations in
Indiana as Developed for the Homeland Security Infrastructure Program (Indiana Department of Homeland Security,
Point Shapefile)]

WARRANTY:

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405
2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY:

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20090629</metd>
    <metrd>20090710</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-856-5654</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>