<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGWS) (Data processor)</origin>
        <origin>Indiana State Department of Health (ISDH) (Data originator)</origin>
        <pubdate>20180226</pubdate>
        <title>NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP: Registered Naloxone Dispensing Entities in Indiana (Indiana State Department of Health, Point Shapefile)</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
NOTE: NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP is an Esri point shapefile that was produced from data that were harvested on February 26, 2018 from the
"Overdose Prevention Therapy-Indiana Registry" website of the Indiana State Department of Health (ISDH). These data should not be considered
completely current, as entities could potentially be added or removed from the registry since the last date of publication. Further, entities
that temporarily run out of naloxone stock are temporarily removed from the live optIN Registry website, and are reinstated when the ISDH is
notified that the entity has been resupplied with dosages. For the most current information about naloxone entities, and other related online
resources, please visit the ISDH optIN Registry website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ).

The following is excerpted from the file named "Indiana-Statewide-Naloxone-Standing-Order-Toolkit.pdf" which is
hosted online by the ISDH ( https://optin.in.gov/files/Indiana-Statewide-Naloxone-Standing-Order-Toolkit.pdf ):

"Naloxone Entity Defined - "Naloxone Entities" may include pharmacies, pharmacists or other
non-pharmacy organizations, non-profit entities or individuals that are in a position to
assist an individual who, there is reason to believe, is at risk of experiencing an
opioid-related overdose. Naloxone Entities must, at all times, comply with the following
criteria and all other conditions enumerated in Indiana Code 16-42-27 et seq.:

"1. Obtain naloxone from a prescriber (physician, physician assistant or advanced
practice nurse with authority to prescribe) either by virtue of the attached standing
order or other standing order or prescription issued by a prescriber;

"2. Annually register as a "Naloxone Entity" at https://optin.in.gov/ in a manner prescribed
by the Indiana State Department of Health (ISDH);

"3. Provide education and training on drug overdose response and treatment, including the
administration of an overdose intervention drug and the legal requirement to call 9-1-1
immediately before or after administering the drug; and

"4. Provide drug addiction treatment information and referrals to drug treatment programs,
including programs in the local area and programs that offer medication assisted treatment
that includes a federal Food and Drug Administration approved long acting, non-addictive
medication for the treatment of opioid or alcohol dependence."

The ISDH optIN website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ) also states the following:

"The state is committed to saving lives by making naloxone, a drug that reverses the symptoms of opioid overdose,
available to first responders, family, friends and others who are likely to be the first on the scene if someone
overdoses. Naloxone, also known by the brand name "Narcan," is a non-narcotic medication that is an antidote for
opioid overdoses. If administered in a timely manner, naloxone can reverse the life-threatening respiratory failure
that is usually the cause of overdose deaths. Naloxone has been proven effective in reversing overdoses caused by
heroin and prescription medications such as "OxyContin," "Percocet," "Methadone," and "Vicodin."

"The ISDH has created the Overdose Prevention Therapy-Indiana, or optIN, registry where entities can register as
naloxone dispensers. The registry, which can be accessed at www.optin.in.gov, allows nonprofits, pharmacies, local
health departments, addiction treatment facilities, correctional facilities and other entities to register as providers
of naloxone. Entities must provide training in the use of naloxone, instruct those who administer it to call 911 and
provide a list of options for substance abuse treatment. Registered entities must annually report, among other things,
the number of naloxone doses distributed to the state."

Visit the following webpage for further information from the ISDH concerning opioid misuse, prevention, and fatal
overdoses - ( https://www.in.gov/isdh/27358.htm ).
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://maps.indiana.edu/layerGallery.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP is an Esri point shapefile showing the locations of 705 registered Naloxone Entities in Indiana.
These registered entities can dispense naloxone to people without a prescription (no prescription is needed). A person seeking naloxone
can ask the entity to use the state health commissioner's "Statewide Standing Order." The Statewide Standing Order, authorized by I.C 16-42-27,
is renewed each year. Naloxone Entities must at all times remain compliant with Indiana law to act under the Statewide Standing Order, and
abide by the attestations made on the optIN Registry website. All entities are also required to provide training for usage of naloxone, as
well as to provide other available addictions resources within Indiana. Attribute information includes entity name, address, contact phone,
contact email, and website URLs.

NOTE: NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP should not be considered completely current, as entities could potentially be added or removed from
the registry since the last date of publication (20180226). Further, entities that temporarily run out of naloxone stock are temporarily
removed from the live optIN Registry website, and are reinstated when the ISDH is notified that the entity has been resupplied with
dosages. For the most current information about Naloxone Entities in Indiana, and other related online resources, please visit the
ISDH optIN Registry website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ).
</abstract>
      <purpose>
NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP was created to provide a GIS layer that shows the registered Naloxone Entities in Indiana. These registered
entities have the ability to provide a person access to dosages of the non-narcotic medication naloxone, as well as to provide training or
assistance in usage of naloxone. For the most current information about Naloxone Entities in Indiana, and other related online resources,
please visit the ISDH optIN Registry website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ).
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20180226</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-87.945276</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.762980</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.756497</northbc>
        <southbc>37.915590</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Metadata Service Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>health</themekey>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>IGWS Metadata Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Indiana Geological and Water Survey (IGWS)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana State Department of Health (ISDH)</themekey>
        <themekey>Overdose Prevention Therapy-Indiana Registry (optIN)</themekey>
        <themekey>naloxone</themekey>
        <themekey>non-narcotic medication</themekey>
        <themekey>Narcan</themekey>
        <themekey>opioid antidote</themekey>
        <themekey>OxyContin</themekey>
        <themekey>Percocet</themekey>
        <themekey>Methadone</themekey>
        <themekey>Vicodin</themekey>
        <themekey>heroin</themekey>
        <themekey>nonprofits</themekey>
        <themekey>pharmacies</themekey>
        <themekey>local health departments</themekey>
        <themekey>addiction treatment facilities</themekey>
        <themekey>correctional facilities</themekey>
        <themekey>school</themekey>
        <themekey>medical service</themekey>
        <themekey>substance abuse</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Allen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>DeKalb County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Johnson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lake County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vanderburgh County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana State Department of Health</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Waldron</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Director of Health Data, Informatics, and Geographics (HDIG)</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>2 N Meridian Street</address>
          <city>Indianapolis</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>46204</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>317 233 5570</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>cwaldron@isdh.in.gov</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Esri ArcGIS point shapefile format (v 10.5), approximately 500 Kb</native>
    <useconst>Infrastructure--Facilities_Naloxone_Providers_ISDH</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>All attributes values were harvested from the ISDH optIn Registry website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ) and are assumed to be accurate.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>Esri point shapefile format.</logic>
    <complete>This dataset contains all naloxone dispensing entities in Indiana (as of 20180226) that have registered on the ISDH optIn Registry website ( https://optin.in.gov/ ).</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The data were provided by ISDH and assumed to be accurate.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the production of this shapefile.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana State Department of Health</origin>
            <pubdate>20180226</pubdate>
            <title>"Overdose Prevention Therapy-Indiana Registry" (optIN)</title>
            <geoform>Website</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana State Department of Health</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://optin.in.gov/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20180226</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>optIN_Naloxone_Dispensers_26Feb2018.txt (GeoJSON format)</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Provides locations of registered naloxone dispensing entities in Indiana as of February 26, 2018.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
IGWS personnel harvested the locations of registered naloxone entites in Indiana from the ISDH "Overdose Prevention Therapy-Indiana Registry" (optIN)
website, and saved the output as a text file named "optIN_Naloxone_Dispensers_26Feb2018.txt" in GeoJSON format. The GeoJSON file was then converted
to an Esri point shapefile using an online conversion tool ( https://mygeodata.cloud/converter/geojson-to-shp ). The resulting shapefile was reprojected
to UTM (Zone 16 North) coordinates (NAD83), and saved as "NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP" to conform to naming conventions of the IGWS. The following
empty or superfluous attribute fields were then deleted from the attribute table; CNTY, ORG, ADR, GEO, PHYS, HOURS, STATE, and WEBNAME. Also, one entity
was removed because the actual location is in Michigan, while five entity locations were manually re-adjusted to more accurate locations (Walgreens #12812,
Walgreens #5141, Walgreens #5718, Walgreens #7618, and Walgreens #9359) by visual inspection using aerial imagery and online web search results for store
address locations.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>optIN_Naloxone_Dispensers_26Feb2018.txt (GeoJSON format)</srcused>
        <procdate>20180226</procdate>
        <srcprod>NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
After internal review of the data, IGWS personnel added the attribute field named "TypeCorr" to the attribute table so that potential errors in the facility
designation attribute field named "EntityType" could be fixed. A total of sixteen (16) records were estimated to have an entity designation that were in error.
A better estimate for these 16 entities were based on interpretation of the information provided in the "Name" attribute field. (For example, the entity named
"Bloomington Police Department" was originally labeled as "other (99)" but has now been attributed to represent "Corrections/Fire (30)".
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20180319</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v. 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v. 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer
(U.S. Geological Survey). The errors generated by MP were all addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution"
and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20180413</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405 2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Point</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>705</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.DBF</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile attributes table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREET</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street address for the entity location</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CITY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>City name where the entity is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ZIP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>ZIP Code for the address where the entity is located</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PHONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Telephone number for contact for the entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EMAIL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Electronic-mail address for contact for the entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WEB</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Website URL address for the entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ENTITYTYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Coded value for the type of entity</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana State Department of Health</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "501(c) Non-Profit" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>20</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Addictions Treatment" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>30</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Corrections" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>40</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Health Department" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>50</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Pharmacy" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>60</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "School" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>99</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as "Other" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPECORR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>coded value for the type of entity (IGWS corrected 16 entties designations, based on the facility names)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>10</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "501(c) Non-Profit" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>20</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Addictions Treatment" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>30</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Corrections" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>40</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Health Department" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>50</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "Pharmacy" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>60</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as a "School" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>99</edomv>
            <edomvd>Entity is designated as "Other" facility</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana State Department of Health</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 855 7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological and Water Survey be cited in any products generated from this data. The
following source citation should be included: [NALOXONE_PROVIDERS_ISDH_IN.SHP: Registered Naloxone Dispensing Entities
in Indiana (Indiana State Department of Health, Point Shapefile), 20180226].

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey warrants that the media on which this product is stored will be free
from defect in materials and workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a defect is found, return
the media to Publication Sales, Indiana Geological and Water Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove Avenue, Bloomington, Indiana
47405 2208, and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS", without any other warranties or conditions,
expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or suitability to a particular purpose
or use. The risk or liability resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana University,
Indiana Geological and Water Survey shares no liability with product users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential
damages whatsoever, including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged data or other commercial
or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana Geological and Water Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party.
The maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180227</metd>
    <metrd>20180413</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological and Water Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Dintaman</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geologist/GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove Avenue</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405 2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812 856 5654</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812 855 2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cdintama@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC-CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the data set identified and received from the IGWS. It is not to be altered or summarized. IGWS does
not support secondary distribution. If this data set was received from anyone other than the IGWS, this metadata file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>