<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>Nathan K. Eaton (GIS compiler)</origin>
        <pubdate>20020419</pubdate>
        <title>
COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN: Abandoned Mine Lands, Miscellaneous Site Features in Indiana
(Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Polygon Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Bloomington, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
AML_POLY, the predecessor of COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN, was derived
from preexisting AutoCAD files digitized by personnel of the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the
Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation.

This shapefile contains information that is related to two additional shapefiles produced by the
Indiana Geological Survey:

1) COAL_AML_HIGHWALLS_IN: Abandoned Mine Lands, Dangerous Highwalls in Indiana
(Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, PolyLine Shapefile).

2) COAL_AML_MISC_IN: Abandoned Mine Lands, Entrances, Equipment, Facilities, and Dangerous
Gasses in Indiana, (Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Point Shapefile).
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
AML_POLY, the predecessor of COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN, is a 1:24,000-scale polygon-based ESRI ArcView shapefile
that shows the locations and extents of Abandoned Mine Lands (AML) sites and site features in the coal
region of Indiana. AML_POLY includes all Indiana sites listed on the federal AML site
inventory by personnel of the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, Division of Reclamation. COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN includes attributes that allow the polygons to
be differentiated based on site type, site number, and site feature type.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN is a compilation of all polygon features associated with Abandoned Mine Lands
(AML) sites in Indiana. AML_POLY was compiled by the Indiana Geological Survey
(IGS) as part of a contract deliverable for the Abandoned Mine Lands program of the Indiana Department
of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation. AML_POLY was generated from data digitized from
1:24,000-scale topographic maps. All AML data included in AML_POLY are organized in a geographic
information system (GIS) using ESRI ArcInfo and ESRI ArcView software of the Environmental Systems Research
Institute (ESRI) on the Windows NT and Windows 2000 platforms. AML_POLY includes attributes which
allow the polygons to be differentiated based on site type (AML, Bond Forfeiture, or Lost Surety),
site number, or site feature type (pits, slurry, gob, spoil, haul roads, subsidence, water, dangerous
piles and embankments, waste sites, and site boundaries).
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
Two ESRI ArcView legend files (*.avl) are provided with this shapefile to aid in symbolizing the polygons.
The default legend file, COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN.avl, differentiates polygons based on site feature type.
Site features include pits, slurry, gob, spoil, haul roads, subsidence, water, dangerous piles and
embankments, waste sites, and site boundaries. The alternative legend file,
COAL_AML_FEATURES_SITES_IN.avl, differentiates the polygons based on site type. Site type is assigned
by AML program personnel and refers to the funding source used to reclaim a particular site. Site
types include AML (normal federal AML program funding for reclamation of pre-1977 mining), Bond
Forfeiture (funding from bond money forfeited by a coal company that failed to reclaim a site), or
Lost Surety (post-1977 bond forfeiture reclaimed with federal AML funding because of surety company
bankruptcy).
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1977</begdate>
          <enddate>2000</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-87.5911</westbc>
        <eastbc>-86.6679</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.6056</northbc>
        <southbc>37.9073</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcView version 3.2 shapefile format, Windows 2000, approximately 2.3 Mb</native>
    <themekey>
Theme Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus
Place Place_Keyword_Thesaurus
</themekey>
    <useconst>OLD_Coal_Data--Coal_AML_Features_IN</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
The AML sites and site features included in COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN are associated with Abandoned
Mine Lands (AML) sites listed on the federal AML site inventory maintained by the Abandoned Mine Lands
program of the Indiana Division of Reclamation. All areas from COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN have been identified
and field-verified by AML program personnel.

Two tests for attribute consistency were performed by IGS personnel using the QueryBuilder Tool in ESRI
Arcview.

(1) Completeness of values was verified.

- No values were left blank, unless appropriate. (In some instances an AML site is assigned a
federal number and no state (AML) number, or vice versa.

(2) Validity of values was verified.

- All features were attributed with values in the appropriate range and format.
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>ESRI ArcInfo polygon topology is present.</logic>
    <complete>
AML_POLY was derived from preexisting AutoCAD files digitized by personnel of the Abandoned Mine Lands
program of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation. Completeness of
AML_POLY is dependant on the completeness of the source data files. Spot-checks of areas during the
attributing process indicate that 95% of the sites shown on the original federal AML site inventory
maps are represented in AML_POLY.
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
No records exist regarding the horizontal positional accuracy of this shapefile. AML_POLY was
derived from preexisting AutoCAD files digitized by personnel of the Abandoned Mine Lands program
of the Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation. Horizontal positional
accuracy of AML_POLY is dependant on the positional accuracy of the source data files. The source
AutoCAD files were originally digitized from data shown on 1:24,000-scale topographic maps. The
topographic map set, which constitutes the AML program's compilation of federally inventoried AML
sites, was designed to provide a diagrammatic tool for visualizing the types of features associated
with AML sites. Site features such as pits, slurry, gob, spoil, haul roads, subsidence, and waste
sites areas were, in most cases, simply sketched in their approximate location within the more
precisely located AML site boundaries. This means that the horizontal positional accuracy of
AML_POLY site feature polygons is probably most significantly affected by the lack
of horizontal positional accuracy associated with the source topographic maps. Because of the potential
for horizontal positional error associated with AML site feature polygons obtained from AML_POLY, it
is recommended that this dataset be used only as an index of actual AML site feature locations. If
the detailed location of a specific type of AML site feature is needed, more detailed information
is available from the Indiana Division of Reclamation, Abandoned Mine Lands Program.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
The vertical positional accuracy was not a factor in the
creation of COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN. No quantitative tests were performed.
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>
Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation Abandoned
Mine Lands Program
</origin>
            <pubdate>2000</pubdate>
            <title>Federal Abandoned Mine Lands Site Inventory Maps</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Jasonville, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>
Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation Abandoned
Mine Lands Program
</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1977</begdate>
              <enddate>2000</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Federal Inventory Maps</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Source from which CAD files were created.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
AML_POLY was created at the IGS using digital CAD data provided by the Indiana Department of
Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation Abandoned Mine Lands Program. Although the origins
of the CAD data are somewhat uncertain, the general procedures are known. AML site boundaries
and site features (gob, slurry, pits, spoil areas, etc.) were digitized using AutoCAD from
1:24,000-scale topographic maps. The CAD files were then geo-referenced to UTM Zone 16, NAD27
using tics from 1:24,000-scale topographic maps.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>Unknown</srcused>
        <procdate>1996</procdate>
        <srcprod>AML_POLY</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Jim Metzger</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Reclamation</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Technical Manager</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype>
              <address>P.O. Box 147</address>
              <city>Jasonville</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47438</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(800)772-6463</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>jmetzger@kern.osmre.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
County-based AutoCAD (.dwg) files were converted to ESRI ArcView shapefiles using the 'convert to
shapefile' function in ESRI ArcView (v 3.2). The ESRI ArcView shapefile polygons were then attributed
with several items including site number, site type, feature type, and source. The CAD
files included annotation layers which listed information for most of the sites. The source
Federal Abandoned Mine Lands Site Inventory Maps were consulted to obtain attributes for
polygons not annotated in the CAD files. After all the county shapefiles had been attributed,
the ESRI ArcView Geoprocessing wizard was used to merge the county shapefiles to a single shapefile
named AML_POLY.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>digital CAD files (.dwg)</srcused>
        <procdate>20000320</procdate>
        <srcprod>AML_POLY</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Nathan Eaton</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geotechnical Systems Analyst</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>(812)855-0417</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>(812)855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>neaton@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The original shapefile, AML_POLY, was first converted to a coverage named "AML_POLY" using the
'SHAPEARC' command in ESRI ArcInfo.  AML_POLY was then reprojected from NAD27 to NAD83 in ESRI ArcInfo using
the 'PROJECT' command, to create a coverage named "AML_POLY_83." AML_POLY_83 was clipped to a
coverage named "INCLP83," which contains the area within the county boundaries in the state of
Indiana, which was compiled at a scale of 1:24,000.  The Geoprocessing
Wizard in ESRI ArcView was used to perform the clipping operation to create the shapefile named
"COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN."
</procdesc>
        <srcused>AML_POLY</srcused>
        <procdate>20020419</procdate>
        <srcprod>COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN.shp</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>awalls@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata file was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and
MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1) software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (United
States Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to
"Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20030227</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
              <city>Bloomington</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47405-2208</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
            <cntemail>awalls@indiana.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
            <cntinst>
Monday through Friday, except holidays
</cntinst>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>2338</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>
            </absres>
            <ordres>
            </ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN.dbf</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile attribute table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Feature_ty</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of AML site feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>DPE</edomv>
            <edomvd>Dangerous piles and embankments</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Gob</edomv>
            <edomvd>Coarse-grained coal refuse material</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Haul Road</edomv>
            <edomvd>Coal haulage road</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>IR Waste</edomv>
            <edomvd>Industrial/residential waste</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Other</edomv>
            <edomvd>N/A</edomvd>
            <edomvds>N/A</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Pit</edomv>
            <edomvd>N/A</edomvd>
            <edomvds>N/A</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Site Boundary</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Extent of site eligible for reclamation;
may include larger area than actually disturbed or reclaimed
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Slurry</edomv>
            <edomvd>Fine-grained coal refuse material</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Spoil Area</edomv>
            <edomvd>Overburden material</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Subsidence</edomv>
            <edomvd>Documented mine subsidence area</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Water</edomv>
            <edomvd>Hazardous water bodies</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Feature_na</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of AML site or specific site feature</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Site_type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of AML site</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>AML</edomv>
            <edomvd>AML Site reclaimed with Federal AML funds</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Lost Surety</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Post-1977 bond forfeiture reclaimed with Federal AML
funds because of a surety bankrupcy
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Bond Forfeiture</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Mine reclaimed with bond money forfeited by a mine
operator that failed to reclaim a site
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Division of Reclamation</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Aml_id</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State AML site ID number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Fed_id</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Federal AML site ID number</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Division of Reclamation</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Source</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Code for citation of source spatial data</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>100000</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Generated from CAD files digitized by Mark Wolfe,
Indiana Dept. of Natural Resources, Division of
Reclamation, Jasonville, Indiana
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>100001</edomv>
            <edomvd>
Digitized from paper Federal Abandoned Mine Lands
Site Inventory Maps by Nathan Eaton, Indiana
Geological Survey
</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Indiana Geological Survey</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Comment</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Miscellaneous notes; may include secondary/tertiary site numbers</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Indiana Geological Survey</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Character Field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Publication Sales</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Clerk</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812/855-7636</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812/855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>IGSinfo@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
CREDIT

It is requested that the Indiana Geological Survey be cited in any
products generated from this data.  The following source citation should be
included: [COAL_AML_FEATURES_IN: Abandoned Mine Lands, Miscellaneous Site Features in Indiana
(Indiana Geological Survey, 1:24,000, Polygon Shapefile)]

WARRANTY

Indiana University, Indiana Geological Survey warrants that the media on
which this product is stored will be free from defect in materials and
workmanship for ninety (90) days from the date of acquisition. If such a
defect is found, return the media to Publication Sales, Indiana
Geological Survey, 611 North Walnut Grove, Bloomington, Indiana 47405-2208,
and it will be replaced free of charge.

LIMITATION OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

Except for the expressed warranty above, the product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user. Indiana
University, Indiana Geological Survey shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Indiana University, Indiana
Geological Survey is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020418</metd>
    <metrd>20040407</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Indiana Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chris Walls</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geographer, GIS Specialist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>611 North Walnut Grove</address>
          <city>Bloomington</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47405-2208</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>812-855-1346</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-855-2862</cntfax>
        <cntemail>awalls@indiana.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>0800 to 1700 Eastern Standard Time</hours>
        <cntinst>Monday through Friday, except holidays</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the IGS.  It should not to be altered
or summarized.  IGS does not support secondary distribution.  If this
data set was received from anyone besides the IGS, this metadata file and
the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>