<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</origin>
        <pubdate>20090617</pubdate>
        <title>NAIP County Mosaics - New York 2009</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah</pubplace>
          <publish>USDA FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://www.pasda.psu.edu/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2009</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Photography Source Image Dates.</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-78.342627</westbc>
        <eastbc>-77.651037</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.578104</northbc>
        <southbc>41.918374</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories </themekt>
        <themekey>farming</themekey>
        <themekey>Digital Ortho rectified Image</themekey>
        <themekey>Mosaic</themekey>
        <themekey>Quarter Quadrangle Centered</themekey>
        <themekey>Ortho Rectification</themekey>
        <themekey>Compression</themekey>
        <themekey>MrSID</themekey>
        <themekey>JPEG 2000</themekey>
        <themekey>NAIP</themekey>
        <themekey>Compliance</themekey>
        <themekey>Aerial Compliance</themekey>
        <themekey>Imagery/Base Maps/Earth Cover </themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
        <placekey>ALLEGANY</placekey>
        <placekey>ALLEGANY NY</placekey>
        <placekey>36003</placekey>
        <placekey>NY</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>
None, The USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office asks to
be credited in derived products.
If defects are found in the NAIP imagery during the warranty
period such as horizontal offsets, replacement imagery may be
provided. Imagery containing defects that require the
acquisition of new imagery, such as excessive cloud cover,
specular reflectance, etc., will not be replaced within a
NAIP project year.
</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>2222 West 2300 South</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>Utah</state>
          <postal>84119-2020</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-844-2922</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>801-956-3653</cntfax>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
      <browsen>None</browsen>
      <browsed>None</browsed>
      <browset>None</browset>
    </browse>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.0.1324</native>
    <descript>
      <abstract>NAIP_NY_CountyMosaics2009</abstract>
    </descript>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>
NAIP 3.75 minute tile file names are based
on the USGS quadrangle naming convention.
</logic>
    <complete>None</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>FSA Digital Orthophoto Specifications.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>N/A  2d only</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</origin>
            <pubdate>20090617</pubdate>
            <title>ALLEGANY, NY</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>CD/DVD</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2009</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Majority Aerial Photography Date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>MrSID / JPEG2000 compressed image.</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Mosaicked County Image</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
The imagery was collected using ADS40, ADS40-SH51, and ADS40-SH52 digital sensors.
Collection was performed using a combination of twin-engine aircraft flying
at an average flying height of 21000 ft above mean terrain with 25% sidelap,
giving the collected data nominal ground sampling distance of 0.7 meters.
Based-upon the CCD Array configuration present in the ADS40 digital sensor,
imagery for each flight line is 12,000-pixels in width.  Red, Green, Blue,
Near-Infrared and Panchromatic image bands were collected.

Collected data was downloaded to portable hard drives and shipped to the processing
facility daily.  Raw flight data was extracted from external data drives using GPro
software. Airborne GPS / IMU data was post-processed using IPAS, PosPac and/or TerraPos
software and reviewed to ensure sufficient accuracy for project requirements.

Using Pictovera software, planar rectified images were generated from the collected data
for use in image quality review.  The planar rectified images were generated at five meter
resolution using a two standard deviation histogram stretch.  Factors considered during
this review included but were not limited to the presence of smoke and/or cloud cover,
contrails, light conditions, sun glint and any sensor or hardware-related issues that
potentially could result in faulty data.  When necessary, image strips identified as not
meeting image quality specifications were re-flown to obtain suitable imagery.

Aerotriangulation blocks were defined primarily by order of acquisition and consisted of
four to seventeen strips.  Image tie points providing the observations for the least
squares bundle adjustment were selected from the images using an autocorrelation algorithm.
Photogrammetric control points consisted of photo identifiable control points, collected
using GPS field survey techniques.  The control points were loaded in to a softcopy workstation
and measured in the acquired image strips.  A least squares bundle adjustment of image pass
points, control points and the ABGPS was performed to develop an aerotriangulation solution
for each block using Pictovera software.  Upon final bundle adjustment, the triangulated strips
were ortho-rectified to the USGS NED DEM for the project area.  A combination of 10-Meter
and 30-Meter NED data purchased from USGS in 2005 was used for rectification.  The images
were re-sampled from the raw resolution of 0.7 meters to the required resolution of 1.0 meters.

Positional accuracy was reviewed in the rectified imagery by visually verifying the horizontal
positioning of the known photo-identifiable survey locations using ArcGIS software.

The red, green, and blue bands were combined to generate a final ortho-rectified image strip.
The ADS40 sensor collects twelve bit image data which requires radiometric adjustment for output
in standard eight bit image channels.  The ortho-rectified image strips were produced with the
full 12 bit data range, allowing radiometric adjustment to 8 bit range to be performed on a strip
by strip basis during the final mosaicking steps.

The imagery was mosaicked using manual seamline generation in Orthovista Seam Editor (OVSE).
The 12 bit data range was adjusted for display in standard eight bit image channels by defining
a piecewise histogram stretch using OrthoVista software.  A constant stretch was defined for
each image collection period, and then strip by strip adjustments were made as needed to account
for changes in sun angle and azimuth during the collection period.  Strip adjustments were also
made to match the strips histograms as closely as possible to APFO specified histogram metrics and
color balance requirements.  Automated balancing algorithms were applied to account for bi-directional
reflectance as a final step before the conversion to 8 bit data range.

APFO specified DOQQs were extracted from the final mosaic in GeoTIFF format. 3-Band DOQQs were
produced and 3-Band RGB CCMs were created.  DOQQs corresponding to an individual CCM were
reviewed for overall color balance within the CCM.  Local corrections were made where necessary
to ensure uniformity within the CCM.  In the case of DOQQs occurring in more than one CCM,
a separate version of the image was generated and balanced for each CCM it occurred in.
The color balanced DOQQs were then compressed to MrSID Generation 3 format at 15:1 compression ratio
to create a composite CCM.
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20090617</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>ALLEGANY, NY</indspref>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>71429</rowcount>
      <colcount>54611</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>17</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-81.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>1.000000</absres>
            <ordres>1.000000</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>24 bit pixels, 3 band color (RGB) represent brightness values 0-255.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>None</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Supervisor Customer Service Section</cntper>
          <cntorg>USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>2222 West 2300 South</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>Utah</state>
          <postal>84119-2020</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-844-2922</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>801-956-3653</cntfax>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Mosaicked County Image for ALLEGANY, NY</resdesc>
    <distliab>
In no event shall the creators, custodians, or distributors
of this information be liable for any damages arising out
of its use (or the inability to use it).
</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Compressed County Mosaic</formname>
          <formcont>Natural Color</formcont>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>None</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>CD-ROM</offmedia>
            <recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>DVD-R</offmedia>
            <recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>USB/Firewire/SATA External Hard Drive</offmedia>
            <recfmt>NTFS</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>
Contact the USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office
for more information.
</fees>
    </stdorder>
    <availabl>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2009</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </availabl>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20090618</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</cntorg>
          <cntper>REQUIRED: The person responsible for the metadata information.</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>2222 West 2300 South</address>
          <city>Salt Lake City</city>
          <state>Utah</state>
          <postal>84119-2020</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>801-844-2922</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <Esri>
    <ModDate>20110307</ModDate>
    <ModTime>16404000</ModTime>
  </Esri>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110307</mdDateSt>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Penn State Data Commons</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>115 Land and Water Building</address>
          <city>University Park</city>
          <state>Pennsylvania</state>
          <postal>16802</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(814) 865 - 8792</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>datacommons@psu.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>