<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</origin>
        <pubdate>20040909</pubdate>
        <title>
FLOODPLAINS_CROSSSECTION_DFIRM_IDNR_IN: DFIRM Floodplain Cross section
Lines for 86 of 92 Counties in Indiana (Indiana Department of Natural
Resources, 1:12,000, Line Shapefile)
</title>
        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
          <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>
Cross sections (XS) are one layer in the interim digital flood rate insurance maps
(DFIRM) created by the Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR) and available for
download from the following URL:

http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/surface_water/hydro_hydraulic/flood_maps/index.html
</othercit>
        <onlink>http://igs.indiana.edu/arcims/statewide/download.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
This line layer represents cross sections (XS) created from FEMA Flood Rate
Insurance Maps (FIRM). These lines represent the locations of channel surveys
performed for input into the hydraulic model used to calculate flood elevations.
These locations are also shown on the Flood Profiles in the Flood Insurance Study
(FIS) report and can cross reference the Flood Profiles to the planimetric
depiction of the flood hazard. Of 92 counties in Indiana, 86 are included in this
DFIRM data set and 61 counties have XS information.  The following 6 counties are
omitted – Allen, DeKalb, Johnson, Lake, Marion, Vanderburgh.  These counties will
be completed as work on the IDNR project progresses. This floodplain data may be used
with an associated floodplain polygon shapefile and base flood elevation line shapefile.

IDNR documentation states -

“This database is an interim version of the Digital Flood Insurance Rate
Map (DFIRM) Database.  It does not fully meet all DFIRM specifications as
found in “Guidelines and Specifications for Flood Hazard Mapping Partners,
Appendix L: Guidance for Preparing Draft Digital Data and DFIRM Database”.
A fully compliant product is expected in 2005.

The DFIRM Database is derived from Flood Insurance Studies (FISs),
previously published Flood Insurance Rate Maps (FIRMs), flood hazard
analyses performed in support of the FISs and FIRMs, and new mapping data,
where available. The FISs and FIRMs are published by the Federal Emergency
Management Agency (FEMA). The specifications for the horizontal control of
DFIRM data files are consistent with those required for mapping at a scale
of 1:12,000.

The DFIRM Database presents the flood risk information depicted on the
FIRM in a digital format suitable for use in electronic mapping
applications. The DFIRM database is a subset of the Digital FIS database
that serves to archive the information collected during the FIS.”
</abstract>
      <purpose>
IDNR documentation states –

“The purpose of this interim product is to provide much of the same
information as the paper FIRM while moving toward compliance with the
specifications found in “Guidelines and Specifications for Flood Hazard
Mapping Partners, Appendix L: Guidance for Preparing Draft Digital Data
and DFIRM Database.

The FIRM is the basis for floodplain management, mitigation, and
insurance activities for the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP).
Insurance applications include enforcement of the mandatory purchase
requirement of the Flood Disaster Protection Act, which "... requires the
purchase of flood insurance by property owners who are being assisted by
Federal programs or by Federally supervised, regulated or insured agencies
or institutions in the acquisition or improvement of land facilities
located or to be located in identified areas having special flood
hazards," Section 2(b) (4) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973.
In addition to the identification of Special Flood Hazard Areas (SFHAs),
the risk zones shown on the FIRMs are the basis for the establishment of
premium rates for flood coverage offered through the NFIP.”
</purpose>
      <supplinf>
This dataset, as well as many others, was compiled
for mapping and download as part of the Web site titled "A GIS Atlas for Indiana,"
funded by the Indiana Department of Transportation (INDOT). Many publicly
available datasets were created, edited, and compiled inclusion on the Web site
where users can download data or map online using ESRI ArcIMS. Many public data
sources, not created in conjunction with the statewide project, were obtained
by Web site download, contacting originators, and creating spatial files from
tabular data. A range of layer editing was used, specific to each layer, from full
creation, to data cleaning, to only reformatting metadata. The level of editing done
by BLA or the Indiana Geological Survey (IGS) is fully disclosed in the process
steps of this metadata; credit for the information is retained by the originator.
</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>FIRM Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.1607</westbc>
        <eastbc>-84.6882</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.7753</northbc>
        <southbc>37.7554</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Geography Network Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>FEMA Flood Hazard Zone</themekey>
        <themekey>Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)</themekey>
        <themekey>Indiana Department of Natural Resources (IDNR)</themekey>
        <themekey>special flood hazard area (SFHA)</themekey>
        <themekey>riverine flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>base flood elevation (BFE)</themekey>
        <themekey>Flood Insurance Rate Map (FIRM)</themekey>
        <themekey>Digital flood insurance rate map database (DFIRM)</themekey>
        <themekey>floodway</themekey>
        <themekey>floodplain</themekey>
        <themekey>stream</themekey>
        <themekey>surface water</themekey>
        <themekey>cross section (XS)</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Indiana</placekey>
        <placekey>Adams County</placekey>
        <placekey>Bartholomew County</placekey>
        <placekey>Benton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Blackford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Boone County</placekey>
        <placekey>Brown County</placekey>
        <placekey>Carroll County</placekey>
        <placekey>Cass County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clark County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Clinton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Crawford County</placekey>
        <placekey>Daviess County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dearborn County</placekey>
        <placekey>Decatur County</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware County</placekey>
        <placekey>Dubois County</placekey>
        <placekey>Elkhart County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fayette County</placekey>
        <placekey>Floyd County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fountain County</placekey>
        <placekey>Franklin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Fulton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Gibson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Grant County</placekey>
        <placekey>Greene County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hamilton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hancock County</placekey>
        <placekey>Harrison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Hendricks County</placekey>
        <placekey>Henry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Howard County</placekey>
        <placekey>Huntington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jackson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jasper County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jay County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jefferson County</placekey>
        <placekey>Jennings County</placekey>
        <placekey>Knox County</placekey>
        <placekey>Kosciusko County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lagrange County</placekey>
        <placekey>LaPorte County</placekey>
        <placekey>Lawrence County</placekey>
        <placekey>Madison County</placekey>
        <placekey>Marshall County</placekey>
        <placekey>Martin County</placekey>
        <placekey>Miami County</placekey>
        <placekey>Monroe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Montgomery County</placekey>
        <placekey>Morgan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Newton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Noble County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ohio County</placekey>
        <placekey>Orange County</placekey>
        <placekey>Owen County</placekey>
        <placekey>Parke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Perry County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pike County</placekey>
        <placekey>Porter County</placekey>
        <placekey>Posey County</placekey>
        <placekey>Pulaski County</placekey>
        <placekey>Putnam County</placekey>
        <placekey>Randolph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Ripley County</placekey>
        <placekey>Rush County</placekey>
        <placekey>Scott County</placekey>
        <placekey>Shelby County</placekey>
        <placekey>Spencer County</placekey>
        <placekey>Starke County</placekey>
        <placekey>Steuben County</placekey>
        <placekey>St Joseph County</placekey>
        <placekey>Sullivan County</placekey>
        <placekey>Switzerland County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tippecanoe County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tipton County</placekey>
        <placekey>Union County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vermillion County</placekey>
        <placekey>Vigo County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wabash County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warren County</placekey>
        <placekey>Warrick County</placekey>
        <placekey>Washington County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wayne County</placekey>
        <placekey>Wells County</placekey>
        <placekey>White County</placekey>
        <placekey>Whitley County</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
          <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>ESRI ArcView version 3.2 shapefile format, approximately 2.46 Mb</native>
    <useconst>extra_data--Floodplains_Crosssection_DFIRM_IDNR_IN</useconst>
    <datacred>UNIQUEFILENAME</datacred>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>
Some fields in this shapefile are blank, but they have been left as the original data organized
them in case the data remaining to be included has information that would be included in these fields.
When all counties are published, if the fields remain blank, they may be deleted at that time.

IDNR documentation states –

“The DFIRM Database consists of countywide vector files and associated
attributes produced in conjunction with the hard copy FEMAFIRM. The
published effective FIRM and DFIRM maps are issued as the official
designation of the SFHAs. As such they are adopted by local communities
and form the basis for administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they
are authoritative. Provisions exist in the regulations for public review,
appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown to better
match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this
type, variation from the estimated flood heights and floodplain boundaries
is possible. Details of FEMA's requirements for the FISs and flood mapping
process that produces these data are available in the Guidelines and
Specifications for Flood Hazard Mapping Partners. Attribute accuracy was
tested by manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a
symbolized display on an interactive computer graphic system. Independent
quality control testing of FEMA’s DFIRM database was also performed.

Flood elevation data presented in the FIS report must be used in conjunction
with the FIRM for purposes of construction and/or floodplain management.”
</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>
IDNR documentation states –

“When FEMA revises an FIS, adjacent studies are checked to ensure agreement
between flood elevations at the boundaries. Likewise flood elevations at
the confluence of streams studied independently are checked to ensure
agreement at the confluence. The FIRM and the FIS are developed together
and care is taken to ensure that the elevations and other features shown on
the flood profiles in the FIS agree with the information shown on the FIRM.
However, the elevations as shown on the FIRM are rounded whole-foot
elevations. They must be shown so that a profile recreated from the
elevations on the FIRM will match the FIS profiles within one half of one
foot.

FEMA’s Guidelines and Specifications for Flood Hazard Mapping Partners,
Appendix L: Guidance for Preparing Draft Digital Data and DFIRM Database
gives the following information reqarding XS logical consistency (L-350).

XS lines generally extend from outside the floodplain, across the entire
floodplain, and out the other side.  Each cross section is a single line
feature.  Location and shape depicts the position of the cross section
used.”
</logic>
    <complete>
Only 61 of the 86 avialable county DFIRMs have a cross section layer, but all 86 counties
are listed in the place keywords to alert users that the cross section is not a part of
these DFIRMs, rather than the DFIRMs being unfinished as is the case in the 6 omitted counties.
Some fields in this shapefile are blank, but they have been left as the original data organized
them in case the data remaining to be included has information that would be included in these fields.
When all counties are published, if the fields remain blank, they may be deleted at that time.

IDNR documentation states –

“Data contained in the DFIRM Database files reflect the content of the
source materials. Features may have been eliminated or generalized on the
source graphic, due to scale and legibility constraints. With new mapping,
FEMA plans to maintain full detail in the spatial data it produces.
However, older information is often transferred from existing maps where
some generalization has taken place. Flood risk data are developed for
communities participating in the NFIP for use in insurance rating and for
floodplain management. Flood hazard areas are determined using statistical
analyses of records of river flow, storm tides, and rainfall; information
obtained through consultation with the communities; floodplain topographic
surveys; and hydrological and hydraulic analysis. Both detailed and
approximate analyses are employed. Generally, detailed analyses are used
to generate flood risk data only for developed or developing areas of
communities. For areas where little or no development is expected to
occur, FEMA uses approximate analyses to generate flood risk data.
Typically, only drainage areas that are greater than one square mile are
studied.”
</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>
IDNR documentation states –

“The DFIRM Database consists of countywide vector files and associated
attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM. As with
any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated
flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's
requirements for the FISs and flood mapping process that produces these
data are available in the Guidelines and Specifications for Flood Hazard
Mapping Partners. Horizontal accuracy was tested by manual comparison of
source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display on an
interactive computer graphic system. Independent quality control testing
of FEMA’s DFIRM database was also performed.

The specifications for the horizontal control of DFIRM data files are consistent with those
required for mapping at a scale of 1:12,000.”
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>
IDNR documentation states -

“The DFIRM Database consists of countywide vector files and associated
attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM. As with
any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated
flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's
requirements for the FISs and flood mapping process that produces these
data are available in the Guidelines and Specifications for Flood Hazard
Mapping Partners.

Independent quality control testing of FEMA’s DFIRM database was also performed.”
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Federal Emergency Management Agency</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>Flood Insurance Rate Maps, Indiana Counties, USA</title>
            <geoform>Map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
              <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>Paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>FIRM</srccitea>
        <srccontr>
Spatial and attribute information, floodplain widths, BFEs,
Cross Sections, floodplain location.
</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</origin>
            <pubdate>20040528</pubdate>
            <title>[COUNTY]_S_XS</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indianapolis, Indiana</pubplace>
              <publish>Indiana Department of Natural Resources</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>
IDNR documentation states –

“This database is an interim version of the Digital Flood Insurance
Rate Map (DFIRM) Database.  It does not fully meet all DFIRM
specifications as found in “Guidelines and Specifications for Flood
Hazard Mapping Partners, Appendix L: Guidance for Preparing Draft
Digital Data and DFIRM Database”. A fully compliant product is
expected in 2005.”
</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/surface_water/hydro_hydraulic/flood_maps/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>12,000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>FIRM Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DFIRM XS</srccitea>
        <srccontr>XS lines for 61 of 86 counties with DFIRMs</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
No process information regarding the original shapefile creation from FIRM maps was
provided in the source documentation. Information may be obtained from FEMA guidelines
on creating DFIRMs avaialable online. Data creator must be contacted for inquiry.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>FIRM</srcused>
        <procdate>20040901</procdate>
        <srcprod>DFIRM XS</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>David B. Knipe, PE, CFM</cntper>
              <cntorg>Indiana Department of Natural Resources, Division of Water</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Engineering Section Manager (Central)</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>402 W Washington St., Rm. W264</address>
              <city>Indianapolis</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>46204</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>877-928-3755</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>317-233-4579</cntfax>
            <cntemail>dknipe@dnr.in.gov</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
All available DFIRM zip files were downloaded from the IDNR Web site URL:

http://www.in.gov/dnr/water/surface_water/hydro_hydraulic/flood_maps/index.html

Zip files were extracted and each county’s, “S_XS” shapefile was added
to an ESRI ArcView 3.2 project. The "Geoprocessing" extension was used to merge the 86 county
files together to form a single, in work, statewide file. The “in work” status
reflects the interim nature of these files and the absence of 6 counties
which have not yet been published.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>DFIRM XS</srcused>
        <procdate>20041014</procdate>
        <srcprod>FLOODPLAINS_CROSSSECTION_DFIRM_IDNR_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47715</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-479-6200</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website: www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
            <hours>0800-1700 CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
Data was updated by merging newly completed DFIRM files for Adams, Grant,
and Hamilton counties downloaded from the DFIRM website. Metadata was updated
as necessary.
</procdesc>
        <srcused>DFIRM XS</srcused>
        <procdate>20050202</procdate>
        <srcprod>FLOODPLAINS_CROSSSECTION_DFIRM_IDNR_IN.SHP</srcprod>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47715</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>812-479-6200</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website: www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
            <hours>0800-1700 CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>
This metadata was pre-parsed and parsed using CNS (Chew and Spit, v 2.6.1) and MP (Metadata Parser, v 2.7.1)
software written by Peter N. Schweitzer (U.S. Geological Survey).  The errors generated by MP were all
addressed and corrected, except that no values were assigned to "Abscissa_Resolution" and "Ordinate_Resolution."
</procdesc>
        <procdate>20050412</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntperp>
              <cntper>Neal Schroeder</cntper>
              <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
            </cntperp>
            <cntpos>Geographer, Environmental Planner</cntpos>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
              <city>Evansville</city>
              <state>Indiana</state>
              <postal>47715-4006</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>812-479-6262</cntfax>
            <cntemail>nschroeder@blainc.com</cntemail>
            <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Indiana</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Complete Chain</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>8597</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>16</utmzone>
            <transmer>
              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>
              <longcm>-87.000000</longcm>
              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>
              <feast>500000.000000</feast>
              <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
            </transmer>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>Row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.001024</absres>
            <ordres>0.001024</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.26</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>FLOODPLAINS_CROSSSECTION_DFIRM_IDNR_IN.DBF</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Shapefile attributes table</enttypd>
        <enttypds>None</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>XS_LN_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>primary key field</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IDNR</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>XS_LTR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Letter or number assigned to the cross section on the hardcopy FIRM and in the FIS report.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>START_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Link to the station start lookup table. The station start describes the origin for the
measurements in the stream_stn field.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STREAM_STN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Measurement along the stream to the cross-section location.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>XS_LN_TYP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>cross section line type</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Lettered</edomv>
            <edomvd>Cross section is shown on the hardcopy FIRM</edomvd>
            <edomvds>FEMA</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Not Lettered</edomv>
            <edomvd>Cross section is not shown on the hardcopy FIRM, but is part of the backup data for the study.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>FEMA</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WTR_NM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Surface water feature name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>WSEL_REG</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>
Regulatory Water-Surface Elevation for the 1% Annual
Chance Flood Event. It is the precise water surface elevation of the
base flood calculated at the cross section. This elevation exactly
matches the elevation of the base flood in the Flood Profiles and the
Floodway Data Table. This number is determined during the engineering
analysis.
</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>numeric field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEN_UNIT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Measurement unit for water surface elevation (feet)</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>character field, “feet”</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>V_DATUM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Reference surface from which the flood elevations are measured</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>character field, “ngvd29”</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SOURCE_CIT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Citation of the map source of the feature. Most are FIRM maps but some are IDNR supplemental sources.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FEMA FIRM</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>character field</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Division</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website: www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>
No claims to accuracy are made on this data. It is intended
to be used only for general planning purposes. Detailed
planning or analysis will require more accurate data.

LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

The product is provided "AS IS",
without any other warranties or conditions, expressed or implied,
including, but not limited to, warranties for product quality, or
suitability to a particular purpose or use. The risk or liability
resulting from the use of this product is assumed by the user.
Bernardin, Lochmueller and Associates shares no liability with product
users indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages whatsoever,
including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or profit, lost or damaged
data or other commercial or economic loss. Bernardin-Lochmueller and Assoc.
is not responsible for claims by a third party. The
maximum aggregate liability to the original purchaser shall not exceed
the amount paid by you for the product.
</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20041015</metd>
    <metrd>20050412</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cinda Bonds</cntper>
          <cntorg>Bernardin-Lochmueller and Associates</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Environmental Biologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>6200 Vogel Road</address>
          <city>Evansville</city>
          <state>Indiana</state>
          <postal>47715-4006</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-423-7411</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>
812-479-6262
Contact_Website: www.blainc.com
</cntfax>
        <hours>8am-5pm CST</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC CSDGM</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>
This metadata file is intended to accompany the
data set identified and received from the BLA/IGS. It should not to be
altered or summarized. BLA/IGS does not support secondary distribution. If
this data set was received from anyone besides the BLA/IGS, this metadata
file and the data set it describes may lack integrity.
</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>